[{"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion KielS-2319 / S-2230 A - St 110S-2230 - 19 - St 22 2S-2230 -S-2319S-2230 for the assessment period 1976 the principles remain applicable according to the order of the OFD Saarbr\u00fccken S-2230 - 13 - St 222 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "13 4 1978; Bibliography of the relevant administrative instructions in terms of content: SaarlandOFD Saarbr\u00fccken S-2230 - 19 - St 22 2 vom 24011979EStG: 10EStG: 13EStG: 13aGDL: 12 Assessment of farmers and foresters who are not required to keep accounts for income tax for the 1974 calendar year; here: assessment according to \u00a7 13a EStG1 general 11 deviations from the GDL12 temporal scope 13 personal scope (\u00a7 13a paragraph 1 sentence 1 EStG) 14 application for exercising the right to choose different profit determination (\u00a7 13a paragraph 1 sentence 2 EStG) 2 determination of profit according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 2 - 6 EStG 3 Basic amount (Section 13a Paragraph 3 EStG) 4 Value of the work performance (Section 13a Paragraph 4 EStG) 5 Value of the work performance for the business performance (Section 13a Paragraph 4 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1 b EStG) 6 Rent interest received (\u00a7 13a Paragraph 2 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Paragraph 5 Clause 3 EStG) 7 Surcharges (Section 13 Paragraph 6 EStG) 8 Value in use of the apartment (Section 13a Paragraph 2 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "5 EStG) 9 Deductions from the basic amount (Section 13a (2) sentence 2 EStG) 91 Rent paid out (Section 13a (5) sentence 1 and"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "2 EStG) 92 Debt interest93 Permanent burdens10 Questions of doubt Addition of the OFD Saarbr\u00fccken: 10 Special depreciations 101 Increased deductions according to \u00a7 7b EStG 102 Increased deductions according to \u00a7 7d EStG II Appraisal farmers III Book-keeping farmers and foresters 1 General 2 Usage value of one's own apartment 3 Flat amounts for personal consumption and Boarding IV Final remarks 1 Application for extension of the statutory exclusion period of \u00a7 55 Paragraph 5 EStG 2 Special depreciation acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7\u00a7 76 - 78 EStDV 3 Partial retirement benefits 1 General The provision of \u00a7 13a EStG replaces the GDL of 15 September 1965; according to its system, it is essentially comparable to the GDL"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The determination of the profit takes place according to average rates on the basis of the unit values \u200b\u200bof the enterprises of the agriculture and forestry determined according to the value relationships of 1 1 1964"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "With the average rates the profit i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "of Section 4 (1) EStG (see the BFH rulings on VOL from 5 11 1964 BStBl II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "602; from 3 6 1965 BStBl III p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "576)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The principles established by the Federal Fiscal Court on the nature of the VOL and the GDL also apply to the provisions of Section 13a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "11 Deviations from the GDL \u00a7 13a EStG, however, may differ"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "in the following points from the previously applied average taxation according to \u00a7 12 GDL: the option to switch to bookkeeping has been expanded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "In addition to the transition to determining profits by comparing business assets, it is now also possible to transition to income surplus calculation (Section 13 (1) no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The value in use of the owner's apartment is to be recorded at one-eightteenth of the apartment value specifically shown in the unit value (Section 13a, Paragraph 2, No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "5 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The profit according to \u00a7 13a EStG has to be determined anew for each financial year and used as a basis for taxation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The provisions of \u00a7 7 GDL (validity of the determination of profits), \u00a7 9 (validity of the tax assessment), \u00a7 10 (tax waiver in exceptional cases) and the transitional provisions of \u00a7\u00a7 11 and 12 GDL have not been adopted as dispensable in \u00a7 13a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "A surcharge for abnormal animal husbandry is no longer permitted (Section 13 Paragraph 3 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1 letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "a EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The twelfth part of the starting value is to be used as the basic amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The initial value results from the unit value of the company (Section 13a (3) EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The provision of Section 13a EStG is to be applied for the first time for financial years beginning after December 31, 1973 (Section 52 (15) EStG 1974)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "This is usually the 1974/75 financial year EStG, the profit is to be determined in accordance with \u00a7 13a Paragraph 2 - 6 EStG if the basic amount (\u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 EStG) is more than zero DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "If there is exclusively or almost exclusively forestry, horticulture or other agricultural and forestry activity, a profit determination according to \u00a7 13a EStG does not come into consideration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "In the case of the transition to the accounting obligation according to \u00a7 161 Paragraph 1 No. 1 AO, this generally only begins after the tax office has indicated the point in time of the beginning by means of a special notification (BFH judgment of 9 5 1957 BStBl III 291; Paragraph 127 Paragraph 1 sentences 2 and"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "3 EStR; FinMin-Erl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "vom 21 5 1974 - S-1160 a - L VI 32 a, communicated by Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "from 9 7 1974 - S-1160 a A - St 251)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "This also applies if the farmers and foresters are looked after by members of the tax advisory professions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "14 Application for exercising the right to choose to otherwise determine the profit (Section 13a, Paragraph 1, Clause 2 EStG) The application period of 6 months after the end of the respective financial year is a preclusive period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The application must be made in writing; it cannot be revoked (Section 13 (1) sentence 3 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The right to choose can be exercised by changing over to the determination of profits by comparing business assets (no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1) or to determine profit by comparing operating income with operating expenses (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "With the latter type of profit determination, the provisions of Section 4 (3) EStG are to be applied (u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Depreciation or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "AfS acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "7 EStG, taking into account the acquisition or production costs for non-depreciable assets only at the time of the sale or removal of these assets and inclusion of these assets in special, ongoing"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "directories to be kept, Section 4 Paragraph 3 Sentences 3 - 5 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "If a farmer and forester changes from the determination of profits according to Section 4 (1) EStG, Section 12 GDL or Section 13a EStG to determining profits by comparing operating income and operating expenses, the provisions of Section 19 EStR (profit correction) must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "This also applies if he changes from the income surplus calculation to another type of profit determination"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "2 Determination of the profit according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 2 - 6 EStG The profit is the sum of the basic amount (Paragraph 3), the value of the work performed by the business owner and his relatives working in the company (Paragraph 4), the rent received (Paragraph 5 Sentence 3) , the surcharges according to Paragraph 6, the value in use of the owner's apartment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "3 Basic amount (\u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 EStG) The twelfth part of the initial value is to be used as the basic amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "31 The initial value includes the values \u200b\u200bshown in the relevant unit value of the farm: the comparative value for agricultural use including the associated discounts and surcharges according to Section 41 BewG, but excluding special crops, the hectare values \u200b\u200bof the lowest land, the comparative values \u200b\u200bfor special uses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 13a para 3 no 1 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "c EStG, if the sum of the values \u200b\u200bof these special uses contained in the unit value does not exceed DM 4000"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "32 The allocation of the areas to the individual uses using the standard value method is also decisive if the actual use deviates from this"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Such deviations can only be made after the EW has been updated, taking into account Section 13a (3) no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1 last paragraph of the Income Tax Act (EStG) can be taken into account by a correction in accordance with Section 218 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Changes that occurred after the last EW determination that do not reach the value limits of Section 22 BewG and therefore do not lead to an update of values \u200b\u200b(e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Acquisition of land, abnormal animal husbandry, increase in the value of the apartment as a result of structural changes, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": ") cannot be included in the determination of the profit with a special surcharge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "33 If the areas or assets included in the initial value are leased, the values \u200b\u200battributable to the leased areas or assets are to be excluded when determining the initial value (Section 13a Paragraph 3 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "4 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "34 Are areas or assets i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1 letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "a and c EStG, the initial value must be increased by the values \u200b\u200battributable to these leased areas or assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The conditions at the beginning of the financial year are decisive here"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to so-called leasehold businesses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "If there is no special comparative value for the leased areas, a \"substitute comparative value\" is to be determined (\u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "2 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "35 Are comparative values \u200b\u200bfor leased areas for asparagus cultivation, vegetable, flower and ornamental plant cultivation and tree nurseries (Section 61 BewG) as well as for other agricultural and forestry use (Section 62 Paragraph 1 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "6 BewG), care must be taken to ensure that the comparative values \u200b\u200bfor agricultural uses attributable to the leased (intensively used) areas and attributed to the owner of the areas are to be used (cf. \u00a7 48a BewG, unit value of certain intensively used areas)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "36 If areas used for agriculture and forestry are valued as real estate (Section 69 BewG), these areas are to be assessed at the value that would result from the provisions on the valuation of agricultural and forestry assets (Section 13a Paragraph 3 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "5 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "4 Value of work performance (Section 13a, Paragraph 4 of the Income Tax Act) The unit valuation assumes that the agricultural and forestry business is managed exclusively with paid workers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Therefore, the value of the work performed by the business owner and his unpaid relatives (Section 10 StAnpG) must be added to the basic amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "41 With the exception of occasional, minor work, any co-operation of the retirees in the company must be taken into account to a reasonable extent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "42 The maximum number of full-time employees (VAK) appropriate for the type and size of the company may be set as the value of the work performed by relatives"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "For agricultural use, the number of VAKs to be taken into account must not exceed 007 VAKs per hectare (Section 13 Paragraph 4 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "5 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The physical cooperation of the business owner is to be included here"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "43 If the initial value is a value share for special uses (uses, parts of use and other assets in the"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1 letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "c EStG), because the sum of the comparative or individual income values \u200b\u200bfor these special uses does not exceed DM 4,000 in total, no reduction by the VAK shares for special uses is required when determining the value of the work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "In this case, when determining the maximum VAK to be applied, the area of \u200b\u200bspecial uses is to be included in the relevant area of \u200b\u200bthe maximum permissible number of VAK (\u00a7 13a Paragraph 4 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "5 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "This means that there is no need to calculate the VAK actually required for these special uses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "44 If the business owner or relatives are not fully employed in the business (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "due to reduced earning capacity, persistent illness, activity outside of the agricultural and forestry business), only a part of the relevant value of the work performance corresponding to the actual work is to be applied"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The same applies if the physical work is attributable to uses of the agricultural and forestry operations that are not included in the determination of the initial value in accordance with Section 13a (3) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "These include the items listed in Paragraph 3 no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1 letter c, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "with a decisive value totaling more than 4000 DM as well as forestry use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Because of the difficulties of such determinations, it has already been ordered under the scope of the GDL that in the case of missing or obviously inaccurate information about the respective share of employment in Annex L to the income tax declaration, it must be assumed that the workforce is 50 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "on normal agricultural use and on special branches (incl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Special crops) if the actual conditions do not speak against such a distribution ratio (see FinMin-Erl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "dated 28 12 1966 - S-2142 - 63 II 31 communicated by Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "dated 13 1 1967 - S-2230 A - St 110/11 2 and general assessment decision of 3 1 1973 - S-2319 A pp"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "- St 110/112 Tz"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "534)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "This instruction continues to apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "45 For other uses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1 letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "b and c (lowland, special crops, viticultural, horticultural and other agricultural and forestry uses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 62 BewG, ancillary operations, mining land), for which the VAK requirement can be higher or lower, the appropriate number of VAK is to be determined on the basis of experience (see Felsmann comment, Table 4 and note"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "C 27)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "5 Value of the work performed for the operational performance (\u00a7 13a Paragraph 4 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1 b EStG) As the value of the work for the management of the company, the basic amount is 25 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "of the initial value determined in accordance with Section 13a (3) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The amount of 25 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The full amount of the initial value must also be applied if the company is managed by a person whose physical work performance is not to be taken into account at its full value or to be left entirely out of consideration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The value must also be applied in full if the business owner does not manage the business himself or the management is in other hands (e"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Wife, son, son-in-law)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "If the company is managed by several people, the value only needs to be taken into account once"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "6 Lease interest received (Section 13a Paragraph 2 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Paragraph 5, sentence 3 of the EStG) Rent collected is to be added to the basic amount if it is part of the income from agriculture and forestry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The prerequisite for this is that the leased areas belong to the agricultural and forestry business assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Even individually leased areas that are permitted to be assigned to business assets remain business assets until they are transferred to private assets through a clear (explicit or conclusive) withdrawal process (Section 14, Paragraph 13 of the Income Tax Act)."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "If, according to the lease agreement, the lessee has taken on the payment of property tax, contributions to the Chamber of Agriculture and similar charges, these amounts are to be recognized as rent received from the lessor"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "7 Surcharges (\u00a7 13 Paragraph 6 EStG) When determining profits according to \u00a7 13a EStG, the income from special uses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1 letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "c EStG, if these are not already included in the basic amount (i.e. the sum of the comparative values, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "is more than 4000 DM); forestry use; other operating processes that were not taken into account when determining the initial value in accordance with Paragraph 3, if this increases the amount determined in accordance with Section 13a Paragraph 2 - 5 EStG by at least DM 800"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "71 The income to be recognized as a surcharge is generally to be determined by comparing the operating income and operating expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Insofar as there are no records of these operational incidents, the profit surcharge according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 217 AO to appreciate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "72 When determining the surcharges, it is not necessary to start from the areas included in the unit value, but from the areas actually cultivated for special uses at the beginning of the marketing year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "This does not change the areas of agricultural use recorded in the initial value (Paragraph 3)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "73 The surcharges according to Paragraph 6 are to be regarded as a unit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Losses incurred in individual special uses and operations can be offset against profits from other special uses and operations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "A total loss calculated with this balancing cannot lead to a discount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "In the case of capital-intensive branches of business, it should be noted that the operating expenses incurred (in particular debt interest) are also allocated to this branch of business"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "74 The special crops include hops, asparagus and other special crops (Section 52 BewG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The horticultural use includes u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "the useful parts of vegetable, flower and ornamental plant cultivation, fruit cultivation and tree nurseries"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Bushberry fruits and strawberries are also used for horticultural purposes (see also Section 111 BewRL)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Other agricultural and forestry uses include in particular inland fishing, migrant sheep farming, pond farming, mushroom cultivation, fish farming for inland fishing and pond farming, Christmas tree culture, beekeeping, and seed cultivation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "(see also \u00a7 62 BewG, Section 112 BewRL)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "If headed cabbage (white, red and savoy cabbage), picking peas and picking beans are grown as the main crop according to the agricultural cultivation method as part of the agricultural crop rotation, the areas under cultivation belong to agricultural use (Section 108 BewRL)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "This also includes minor areas in accordance with Section 113 BewR L"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "75 Income from forestry use (Paragraph 6 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "2) When determining the initial value or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "of the basic amount, forestry use is excluded in full"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Therefore, the profits from timber exploitation, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "to be recorded by a surcharge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to profits that accrue to the standing wood (tillering) when selling forest properties"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "76 Income from other business operations (Paragraph 6, Item 3) The following income is considered: Profits from sales of breeding cattle, insofar as they exceed the normal profit, profits from keeping sire animals (stud fees), profits from services, in particular from wage transport, wage thrashing, from renting of movable assets or of buildings or parts of buildings, insofar as these belong to the business assets (rental of apartments to holiday guests), from the rental of riding horses, from hunting leases, from secondary employment in professional associations, from participation in producer, sales and credit unions, profits from the sale or Removal of fixed assets, especially land and buildings"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "With regard to these profits, Section 4 (3) EStG i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 55 EStG apply"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "77 Realized increases in the value of business assets are not covered by the basic amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The basic amount only refers to the profits accruing in the normal course of business"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "For this reason, profits from the sale or withdrawal of fixed assets, insofar as these do not correspond to normal operating procedures, are to be recognized by a surcharge (see also Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "from 11 12 1967 - S-2319 / S-2230 A - St 110/11 2)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "8 Value in use of the apartment (Section 13a Paragraph 2 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "5 EStG) The value in use of the owner's apartment is to be set at one eighteenth of the apartment value specifically shown in the unit value"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The housing value includes the family members belonging to the business owner and his household as well as the buildings and parts of buildings used by the elderly for residential purposes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "81 Insofar as real right of residence has been granted for an apartment recorded in the apartment value (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "in the case of retirement agreements that are secured in the land register), the value in use is to be assigned to the beneficiaries"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The flat value shown in the standard value must be reduced accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "There are no concerns that the proportion of senior citizens' apartments in these cases is 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "of the apartment value, unless otherwise stated in the documents"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "82 farm workers' apartments do not belong to the residential part, but to the economic part, even if they are occupied by family members with their own household"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "They are therefore already in the comparative value of the individual uses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Section 34 (2) no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1 BewG (see also Section 130 Paragraph 4 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "9 Deductions from the basic amount (Section 13a (2) sentence 2 EStG) 91 Rent paid out (Section 13a (5) sentence 1 and"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "2 EStG) Lease interest paid can be deducted up to the twelfth part of the initial value for the leased area and parts of the business"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "In the case of residential buildings that have been leased, the rent applicable to them can be deducted up to one eighteenth of the value of the apartment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Rent payments that are wholly or partially attributable to uses and parts of the business that are excluded from the determination of the initial value (Section 13a Paragraph 3 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1 letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "c EStG) are not to be deducted from the basic amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "They are to be taken into account as operating expenses when calculating the surcharge (Section 13a (6) EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "92 Debt interest To the extent that debt interest represents business expenses, it is unlimitedly deductible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to interest on the mortgage profit levy"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Debt interest due on uses and parts of the business, which is excluded when determining the initial value, must be taken into account as business expenses when calculating the surcharge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "93 Permanent burdens A deduction of permanent burdens, which are business expenses, presupposes according to \u00a7 13a Abs 2 sentence 2 EStG that these have not been taken into account in the unit valuation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The usual permanent loads on the farm, such as the dike and sill loads (incl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "the contributions to the water and soil associations) as well as the real estate tax burden have already been taken into account in the unit assessment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Partial retirement burdens are not operational burdens and can therefore only be deducted within the framework of the special expenses according to \u00a7 10 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Deductible permanent loads are therefore hardly likely to occur in practice"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "10 Questions of doubt I would ask you to report regularly on questions of doubt arising in connection with the application of the provisions of Section 13a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "-------------------- Addition of OFD Saarbr\u00fccken: 10 special depreciations 101 Increased depreciations according to \u00a7 7b EStG The value in use of the apartment belongs according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Point"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "9 on profit from agriculture and forestry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Accordingly, under the conditions of Section 7b EStG, farmers and foresters can take into account increased deductions when calculating profit under Section 13a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Section 52 EStDV 1974 allows the deduction amount to be deducted in full from the average rate profit, even if this results in a loss"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "This regulation is no longer contained in \u00a7 52 EStDV"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The increased withdrawal must therefore no longer lead to a loss"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Section 7a (6) EStG 1975 This applies generally for the first time to buildings acquired or constructed after December 31, 1974, as well as to extensions and extensions completed after December 31, 1974, Section 52 (10) EStG 1975, Section 84 (5) EStDV 1975 102 Increased deductions after \u00a7 7d EStG With the decree of 14 11 1975 - B / II - 699/75 - S-2182 A, the Minister of Finance of the Saarland, in agreement with the Federal Minister of Finance and the supreme tax authorities of the other countries, has to the question of the use of the depreciation allowance according to \u00a7 7d EStG 1975 in the context of the determination of profits according to \u00a7 13a EStG as follows: \"An application cannot be considered in the cases of \u00a7 13a paragraph 1 - 5 EStG because the average rates mean the deduction for wear and tear according to \u00a7 7 EStG and thus the increased deductions that replace them according to \u00a7 7d EStG 1975 are compensated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "If, on the other hand, an asset is used in the manner provided for in Section 7d EStG 1975, the result of which is to be recorded by a surcharge according to Section 13a (6) EStG, the increased deductions can be made according to Section 7d EStG 1975, even if the others are also The requirements mentioned in this regulation are met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "This also applies if a subsidy based on a voluntary agreement within the meaning of Section 7d of the Income Tax Act (EStG) is given as part of such a part of the business"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "\"II Estimated farmers For farmers and foresters who are obliged to keep accounts but do not keep proper books, the profit according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 217 AO to appreciate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The profit is to be determined in accordance with the actual circumstances as far as possible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "An estimate based on \u00a7 13a EStG is ruled out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "If there are no comparative values \u200b\u200bfrom previous years or from similarly structured companies in the tax office district, the following procedure can be used: operating income + value in use of the apartment + profit surcharges from special operations etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "+ rent received"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "wages paid"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Rent and debt interest paid Per hectare of agricultural land (UAA), the following is to be set as the farm income: a) For farms with a root crop share of more than 20%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "der LN = 1100-- DMb) For farms with a root crop content of more than 15 to 20%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "der LN = - 900-- DMc) For farms with a root crop content of 0 to 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "der LN = - 600-- DM To determine the value in use of the apartment, see"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Section III number 2 For bonuses such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "due to abnormal animal husbandry or sales of breeding cattle, the values \u200b\u200bfor the GDL or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 13a - farmers are involved"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "III Book-keeping farmers and foresters 1 General Farmers and foresters who meet the requirements of Section 161 Paragraph 1 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1 letter a, c or e AO i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "V with Section 127 Paragraph 1 EStG, are obliged to keep books"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "It must be taken into account that when checking whether there is a bookkeeping obligation according to Section 161 (1) No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "from 22 5 74 - B / I - 67/74 - S-1160 a A, announced with a ruling from 23 7 74 S-1160 a - 2 - St 231)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "The accounting obligation usually only begins after the tax office has specifically communicated the time of the start"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "In view of the fact that within the framework of the AO reform, the profit limit for farmers and foresters in Section 161 (1) no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1 letter e AO is expected to be increased to DM 15,000 from the 1974/75 financial year and thus a number of farmers and foresters who were previously required to keep accounts but who did not keep books are no longer subject to the accounting obligation, the assessment in these cases is up to to postpone the publication of the new provisions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "2 Value in use of one's own home The value in use of the farmer's and forester's home is included in income from agriculture and forestry if the home does not exceed the size customary for businesses of the same type, Section 13 (2) no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "2 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "To determine the value in use of one's own apartment, reference is made to the BFH rulings of 30 1 1974 BStBl 1975 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "3 and from 28 3 1974 BStBl 1975 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "9 pointed out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "3 Lump sums for self-consumption and meals As a lump sum for self-consumption and meals, the amounts that were set in the ruling of 6 5 1974 - S-2149 - 3 - St 222 a are still to be taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "IV Concluding remarks 1 Application for an extension of the statutory preclusive period of Section 55 (5) EStG. Reference is made to the order of 8 1 1976 - S-2230 - 12 - St 221"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "2 special depreciation acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7\u00a7 76 - 78 EStDV According to the FMS decree of 5 12 1975 - B / II - 658/75 - S-2184 A, announced with a ruling of 19 12 1975 - S-2184 - 2 - St 221, forklifts are among the economic goods of Appendix 1 to \u00a7\u00a7 76 - 78 EStDV"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "3 Partial retirement benefits Partial retirement benefits can in principle be taken into account in full as special expenses (permanent burden) (Section 167 (1) Income Tax Regulations 1972)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "They provide recurring services to the recipient i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 22 no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "1 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "If the apartment left to a senior citizen is a real secured right of use, the value in use must be added to it (BFH judgment of 12 September 1969 BStBl II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "706)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "In this respect, there is no deduction as special expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "For the"}, {"meta": {"name": "0023110.xml"}, "text": "Retirement benefits reduced by the value in use of the rented apartment, the following amounts (annual value) can be applied as a lump sum: a) for married couples entitled to retirement = DM 2200 b) for individuals entitled to retirement = DM 1200 --- accounting income tax / wage tax / church tax Schleswig-Holstein Saarland agriculture farmer"}]