[{"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion D\u00fcsseldorfS-7300 A - St 151S-7300S-7424UStG: 9UStG: 19UStG: 14UStG: 15UStG: 15aUStG: 4/12 USTG: 22/2/1/3 USTDV: 44/4 Involvement of an intermediate lessor Reference: Orders from 10 1 1975 S-7300 A - St 533 29 12 1977 S-7300 A - St 151 18 7 1978 S-7300 / S-7424 A - St 151 1 Cases of intermediate letting can be recognized by the fact that im In connection with the start of business activity, high input tax amounts are incurred and rental and leasing of land and buildings is mentioned as a type of business"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "In such cases, in addition to the option according to \u00a7 9 UStG, there is very often an option declaration according to \u00a7 19 UStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "For monitoring reasons, it is therefore essential to ensure that, in accordance with section 5123 of the guidelines for keeping tax files in the assessment procedure - communicated by order of 6 2 1981 - O-1541 - 2 / O-2000 - 4 - St 614 - the option declarations and, if applicable,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "whose revocation are pre-attached in the sales tax files"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "In addition, input tax reimbursements over DM 1000, which according to \u00a7 41 Paragraph 2 No. 6 and 7 of the new GNOF\u00c4 (decree of FinMin NW of 24 11 1980 O-2000 - 3/7 - II C 2 / S-0061 - 7 - VA 1 Both in the pre-registration and in the assessment procedure are subject to the reservation of the department manager to sign, in particular to check whether there are cases of interim letting"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "2 In the case of interim leases in connection with a so-called builder model, the tax office responsible for the sub-tenant / supervisor or the building owners' association must first clearly and specifically explain whether there are any concerns against an input tax refund (FinMin NW decree of 16 6 1978 S-7424 - 5 - VC 4 communicated by decree of 18 7 1978 S-7300 A - St 151)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "As long as this does not happen or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "is not yet possible due to extensive investigations of the facts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "the tax assessment according to \u00a7 165 Abs 1 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "3 AO, and the reasons must be communicated to the taxpayer"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "3 If, when examining the individual circumstances of the taxpayer, doubts arise with regard to the input tax amounts, the following original documents are to be requested - depending on the individual case - since the recognition of input tax amounts in the case of interim leases means a direct exchange of services between the builder and the companies involved, and an immediate issue of invoices with a separate tax ID Required for the client (\u00a7\u00a7 14 15 UStG): Trust agreement with power of attorney, support and administration contract, rental agreement with rental invoices from the client to the sub-landlord, property purchase contract, option contract for rental / purchase models, general contractor contract, original invoices from the contractors, articles of association of the building owners' association"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "4 Furthermore, \u00a7 15a UStG (for land: 10-year taxable period of use) must be observed, since in many cases builder models are geared towards the immediate sale of the objects after the speculation period according to \u00a7 23 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "The notifications of sale to be attached to the income tax, corporation tax, wealth tax, assessment or unit value files must therefore be checked regularly with a view to the applicability of \u00a7 15a UStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "In the event of later sale or personal use, the tax office's claim for repayment in accordance with Section 44 (4) UStDV 1980 is due in full immediately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "A distribution of the input tax to be corrected over the remaining correction period is only possible in cases in which the taxpayer (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "by revoking the option) from tax liability (\u00a7 4 No. 12 in conjunction with \u00a7 9 UStG) to tax exemption (\u00a7 4 No. 12 UStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "In addition, the applicability of \u00a7 15a UStG can also be determined by comparing line 27 of the annual sales tax returns from calendar year 1980 onwards"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "5 If the non-recognition of an interim tenancy relationship has been issued with invoices or credit notes with a separate tax statement for these sales, this tax liability in accordance with Sections 4 and 5 of the decree of the Minister of Finance of the State of North Rhine-Westphalia on Section 9 UStG of 28 3 1980 S-7198 - 11 - VC 2 communicated by order of 8 5 1980 S-7198 A - St 151 only if the invoices or credit notes are corrected in accordance with \u00a7 14 Paragraph 2 UStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "6 In addition, according to \u00a7 22 Paragraph 2 No. 1 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "3 UStG 1980 the records of the entrepreneur show the sales that the entrepreneur has treated as taxable according to \u00a7 9 UStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "7 If an interim tenancy agreement is recognized within the framework of a builder model (except in the form of a so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "When processing the income tax returns, it is important to ensure that the depreciation can only be calculated from the net amount (i.e. without input tax)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "In addition, in these cases,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "to monitor by setting the test note 761 that the reimbursed input tax is treated under the conditions of \u00a7 9b EStG in connection with 86 Abs 4 EStR at the time of its receipt as operating income or income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "8 If the prerequisites for a deferral for tax claims of the tax office with regard to an expected input tax refund are given, a deferred interest waiver pursuant to Section 234 (2) AO is only to be promised in cases in which the input tax refund claim was justified"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "9 If these principles have not been observed in previous cases, the tax credits paid must be reclaimed immediately in order to prevent the statute of limitations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "I would ask you to discuss the problem area with all relevant departments in the tax office in a specialist meeting"}, {"meta": {"name": "0057884.xml"}, "text": "--- Sales tax North Rhine-Westphalia"}]