[{"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion K\u00f6lnS-2188 - 2 - St 11 A / S-3380 - 5 - St 24S-2188S-3380EStG: 55 Instructions for carrying out the work in connection with the new regulation of land gain taxation 1 General 11 The determination or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "Review of the starting amounts of the land belonging to agricultural and forestry assets under valuation law (Section 55 Paragraphs 2 and 3 EStG) is the objective responsibility of the tax authorities' assessment offices"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to the starting amounts of the land that does not belong to agricultural and forestry assets (Section 55 (4) EStG) as well as for the higher partial values \u200b\u200bto be determined separately by the tax office in accordance with Section 55 (5) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "The assessment bodies must provide assistance to the assessment bodies as far as this is possible according to the assessment documents"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to the technical cooperation of the ALS clerks (ALS) in the form of expert statements based on individual requirements according to the usual form (Appendix available v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "2 6 1966 - O-2025 - 1 - St 512)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "The copies of the inventory sheets of the land register at the assessment offices for information to taxpayers can only be used to check the declarations submitted to the tax office and, if necessary,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "the acquisition or production costs to be determined ex officio i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "of Section 55 (1) EStG 1971 (Section C of FinMin"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "NW decree v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "18 1 1972 - S-3380 - 3 - VC 1 / S-3300 - 92 - VC 1 / S-2188 - 1 - VB 2 communicated by order of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "10 2 1972 StEK BewG 1965 \u00a7 69 No. 5)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "12 For real estate belonging to fixed assets on July 1, 1970, the taxpayers must declare the information required from the real estate cadastre in order to determine the starting amounts as part of the procedure for taxing their income (Section C of the aforementioned decree v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "18 1 1972)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "Only in balance sheets that are drawn up on a key date after December 31, 1973 is the double starting amount to be estimated, as long as it has not yet been determined (cf. the transitional regulation in the FinMin NW decree v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "9 3 1972 No. 1 Paragraph 3 announced by order v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "23 3 1972 StEK EStG \u00a7 4 GewVerw"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "No. 15)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "The starting amounts must be declared at the latest when they are sold or removed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "At the same time, it must be ensured that the taxpayers provide or provide the necessary information to clarify the matter at the latest with the income tax declaration for the relevant calendar year in which the sale or withdrawal occurs"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "Bring documents, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": ": a) Declaration of the operational termination or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "Withdrawal stating the time and the areas affected (including cadastral designation and standard value numbers), b) Presentation of the book values \u200b\u200bof these areas, including any"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "Applications to determine the higher partial value as of 1 7 1970 In the case of later acquisition, information on the acquisition and production costs based on the prescribed list in accordance with No. 2 of the decree v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "23 3 1972 communicated decree FinMin NW v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "9 3 1972 c) Illustration of the determination of the declared sale or sale"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "Withdrawal profit by the taxpayer"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "The valuation bodies and the ALS clerk are only to be involved if the taxpayer has fulfilled the duties of cooperation incumbent on him in the determination of the facts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "2 When carrying out the work, the following division of tasks arises 21 The tax authorities check: a) Are they fixed assets or private assets? b) If there are applications for a higher flat rate value for intensively used areas (Section 55 Paragraph 2 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "1 sentence 2 EStG) and are these possibly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "with the participation of the assessment bodies or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "of the ALS checked? c) Have applications to determine the higher partial value (Section 55 (5) EStG) been submitted and finally processed (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "Disposal v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "12 9 1972 a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": ")? d) Is it a case of sale soon after 1 7 1970 and if the land has obviously not increased in value since 1 7 1970 (No. 6 Paragraph 1 and No. 11 Paragraph 3 of the FinMin NW Decree v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "9 3 1972 - S-2188 - 1 - VB 2 / S-2239a - 1 - VB 2 communicated by order of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "23 3 1972 and FinMin NW decree of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "16 6 1972 - S-2188 - 1 - VB 2 communicated by order v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "29 6 1972 StEK EStG \u00a7 4 GewVerw Nr 15)? 22 The cooperation of the valuation bodies in cooperation with the ALS extends to: a) Review of the book values \u200b\u200bas of 1 7 1970: aa) In difficult cases, comparison of the area sizes and the yield figures with information in the cadastre, unless the taxpayer can submit a cadastral extract"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "bb) If the new real estate cadastre (NLK) is not applicable, check on the 1 7 1970 check whether the average yield figures used agree with the findings at the main point in time 1 1 1964"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "cc) Examination of the allocation of the areas to the uses on the basis of the findings for the unit valuation of agricultural and forestry assets, provided that the taxpayer assigns the areas to uses in a significantly different way than shown in the NLK"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "b) Determination of the sales proceeds: aa) Examination of the amount in DM per square meter at the time of removal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "bb) In the case of lump-sum sales proceeds,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "Examination of the division, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "on the share for land, plant stocks and buildings (unchanged from the previous regulation)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "For the areas used for forestry, the decision v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "12 7 1972 - S-2239 - 5 - St 251 (not published) pointed out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "3 Special features when determining the starting amounts according to \u00a7 55 Paragraph 2 and 3 EStG 1971 31 If the NLK has not yet been drawn up on 1 7 1970 or the earnings indicators are not shown in it, the starting values \u200b\u200bmust be determined in accordance with the provisions of \u00a7 55 Paragraph 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "The same procedure can be used in cases in which the NLK was already available before 1 7 1970, but due to a property briefing before 1 7 1970 during land consolidation proceedings for the reference date 1 7 1970 it is not applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "In the case of properties acquired in exchange after 1 7 1970, the determination of the initial values \u200b\u200bis based on No. 3 of the decree v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "23 3 1972 communicated decree NW v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "9 3 1972 32 The initial values \u200b\u200bfor marked areas are to be determined in the same way as it applies to the areas of the demarcation in which the marked areas are occupied"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "33 Before determining the average yield figure in accordance with Section 55 (3) EStG for any"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "Appropriate proposals are to be submitted to Unit St 24 by the ALS for areas that come into consideration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "4 Particularities in the separate determination of the higher partial values \u200b\u200baccording to \u00a7 55 Abs 5 EStG 1971 41 According to \u00a7 55 Abs 5 EStG, the partial value for land is to be applied as acquisition or production costs if the taxpayer proves that the partial value on 1 7 1970 is higher than twice the starting amount according to \u00a7 55 Abs 2-4 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "If the land was sold or taken before July 1, 1972, according to No. 11 Paragraph 3 of the FinMin NW v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "9 3 1972 announced by order v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "23 3 1972, when determining the higher partial value, it can generally be assumed, even without special proof, that the higher partial value of the land on 1 7 1970 corresponds to the sales proceeds less any sales costs or the value of the land at the time of removal, es unless special circumstances speak against it"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "Special circumstances must always be assumed if there is an obvious disproportion between the partial value on 1 7 1970 and the sales proceeds or withdrawal value of the sale or withdrawal that took place before 1 7 1972 (for further details see FinMin NW v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "16 6 1972 announced by order of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "29 6 1972)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "42 In cases in which a sale or withdrawal has not taken place by June 30, 1972, the taxpayer must provide evidence of the higher partial value as of July 1, 1970"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "Appropriate documents must be enclosed with the application, for which the law does not prescribe a special form (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "Appraisals from experts, certificates from the responsible municipality that the property is located within a certain development area or the information that shortly before or after 17 1970 neighboring properties were sold at prices higher than twice the starting amount)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "43 The application to determine the higher partial value, which must be submitted by December 31, 1975, must specify the area precisely in the cadastre"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "The application can be restricted to parts of a parcel or several parcels"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "In this case, however, it is necessary that the sub-area of \u200b\u200ba parcel for which a higher sub-value is to be determined is identified in an extract from the land map and shown in terms of size"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "A special partial valuation is required for each of the property areas mentioned"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "The areas or partial areas of a parcel for which a higher partial value is determined are to be treated for tax purposes as independent assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "44 Pursuant to Paragraph 55 (5), fourth sentence, of the EStG, the partial value only needs to be determined separately before 1 1 1974 if the taxpayer has a legitimate interest, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "upcoming sale or withdrawal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "The finding is therefore z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "only to these special cases"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "45 The three-part ESt 2 3 and 4 F (72) form introduced with Decree 12 9 1972 (not published) is to be used to determine the partial value for the land on 1 7 1970 in accordance with Section 55 (5) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "46 The assessment body must be notified of the determination of a higher partial value because these areas may"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "must be added to the real estate by way of subsequent determination on 1 1 1971, provided that the higher partial value in individual cases is not based on reasons exclusively related to agricultural and forestry use (decree FinMin NW v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "18 2 1972 - S-3191 - 7 - VC 1 communicated by order of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "7 3 1972 - S-3191 - 7 - St 211 StEK BewG 1965 \u00a7 69 No. 4)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "47 It will be useful to have the pending cases of determining a higher partial value dealt with centrally"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "In this respect, I ask the heads of the tax offices to take appropriate measures"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "In the event of difficulties or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "If you have any questions, please report them"}, {"meta": {"name": "0058540.xml"}, "text": "--- Income tax / wage tax / church tax North Rhine-Westphalia bad gw-31 EStG"}]