[{"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion M\u00fcnster S-2230 - 91 - St 16 - 31S-2230 -EStG: 4 / 1EStG: 4 / 3EStG: 13EStG: 13aEStR: 127 Income tax assessment of farmers and foresters for the assessment period 1984 Reference: Order of 25 7 1985 - S-2230 - 91 - St 16 - 31 ESt- Nr 69/1985 on \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG1 General2 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry according to average rates (\u00a7 13a EStG) 21 Scope of application211 On \u00a7 13a Abs 1 Nr 2 EStG (initial value limit) 212 Add Section 13a, Paragraph 1, No. 3 of the EStG (livestock limit) 22 Determination of profit221 Basic amount222 Value of the work performed223 Rent received224 Profits according to Section 13a, Paragraph 8 of the Income Tax Act2241 Sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals2242 Vegetable growing (agricultural and horticultural use of fruit) 2243 Special gardening, cultivation of asparagus 222244 Cultivation of asparagus Value in use of the apartment226 Lease interest paid, interest on debt, ongoing burdens227 Other additions and reductions3 Determination of the profit from land un d Forestry by comparing the operating income with the operating expenses (Section 4 (3) EStG) 31 Scope32 Determination of profits (Section 17 EStR) 321 Average livestock values322 Use value of the apartment4 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry through bookkeeping (Section 4 (1) EStG) 41 Scope42 Opening balance sheets43 Bookkeeping44 Determination of profit441 Average livestock values442 Value in use of the apartment5 Estimate of profit for farmers and foresters whose profit cannot be determined according to average rates51 General52 Estimation of profit according to standard rates521 Starting amount5211 Reduction of the starting amounts5212 Increase of the starting amounts522 Lease income523 Surcharges for profits not compensated with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits5232 Above normal animal husbandry5233 Agricultural vegetable growing (outdoor vegetable growing) 5234 Vegetable growing (horticultural use), special crop asparagus cultivation, fruit growing (horticultural use), strawberry cultivation524 Value in use of the apartment525 Wage expenses526 Lease expenses, debt interest, permanent depreciation527 after appraisals of other buildings527.Results after appraisals527 Section 76 EStDV6 Other61 Retirement benefits62 Control reports63 Unit value reports64 Use of the assessment files when carrying out the assessment1 General In the future, the assessment decisions for farmers and foresters will be issued in full in the event of significant changes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Changes compared to the previous year's text will then be marked by vertical lines"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "2 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry according to average rates (\u00a7 13a EStG) 21 Scope In addition to Section 127 Para. 3-10 EStR and No. 2 of the BMF's introductory letter of 27 3 1981 (BStBl 1981 I, page 282), reference is made to the following: 211 On Section 13a (1) No. 2 EStG (initial value limit) The initial value determined in accordance with Section 13a (4) EStG is decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Cattle surcharges can therefore not be taken into account as long as they are not the subject of a value update according to \u00a7\u00a7 41 i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "V with 22 para 1 no 1 BewG have been made"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Something else only applies if the requirements of Section 13a Paragraph 4 No. 1 Sentence 4 EStG are met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "212 On Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG (animal population limit) According to Section 127 Paragraph 7 EStR and No. 22 of the introductory letter of 27 3 1981 a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": ", Section 124 a of the EStR must be applied accordingly when examining the VE limits of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The prerequisite for the elimination of the determination of the average rate of profit is that the number of VE sustainedly exceeds the limit of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "With regard to the concept of sustainability, reference is made to Section 135 (4) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the following applies: In the event of a gradual increase in the number of animals, it depends on whether the number of animals converted into VE has been above the limits of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG over the three preceding financial years"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "If this is the case, the requirements of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG are no longer met from the beginning of the fourth financial year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "If, on the other hand, the livestock are increased in one go well beyond the maximum permissible limits - e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "in connection with an expansion of the stable capacities - so that the livestock limits can also be expected in the following financial years, the requirements of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG do not apply from the time the maximum limits are exceeded for the first time (see also No. 3 my order of 21 5 1981 S-2230 - 63 - St 11 - 31 ESt-Nr 41/1981 to \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The maximum number of livestock converted into livestock units in accordance with Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG and Section 13 Paragraph 1 No. 1 EStG can be found in the overview attached as Annex 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "22 Determination of profit The scheme for determining profit according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 3-8 EStG results from the form Annex ESt 2 L / 3 L (84) - Profit determination according to \u00a7 13a EStG -"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "In detail, I would like to point out the following: 221 Basic amount When determining the basic amount according to Section 13a Paragraph 4 EStG, Section 130a Paragraph 3 EStR must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "222 Value of the work performance The initial value (and thus the basic amount) according to Section 13a (4) EStG is based on the net income commonly and sustainably achievable with remunerated external workers (see Section 36 (2) BewG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "To determine the average rate profit, the value of the work performed by the business owner and his relatives who are not employed in the company on the basis of an employment relationship must therefore be added to the basic amount (\u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 No. 2 EStG)."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Section 130a Paragraph 4-6 EStR must be observed here"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "In detail, the following is pointed out: When determining the value of the work performance for the physical cooperation of the business owner and the relatives who are not employed, only the work performance is to be taken into account in the result, which is based on the area recorded in the initial value according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 4 EStG in the individual case not applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The paid workers are to be counted towards the appropriate number of full-time workers (VAK) according to the duration of their employment (\u00a7 13a Abs 5 Nr 5 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to temporary workers employed on a short-term basis, as well as to workers who have been made available by contractors for certain ordering, maintenance or harvesting work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "For the crediting of the paid VAK"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "a breakdown of the wages is necessary, insofar as it) applies to the uses contained in the initial value (Section 13a (4) EStG) and b) to the uses not contained therein"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Make taxpayers in the tax return (form \"Annex L\") to the extent / proportion of their employment or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "the activities of other people (relatives, third parties) in the company or no or obviously incorrect information on the part of the work attributable to special uses, the (physical) work or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "the proportion of the work performed by the business owner, the relatives employed in the business and / or the remunerated workers, if applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "with the assistance of the responsible official agricultural expert (ALS)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "For the details, reference to Annexes 1 and 2 available from 22 3 1983 - S-2522 - 54 - St 16 - 31 To determine the share that is attributable to special uses, the table printed in Felsmann's comment in Section C 219 can also be used the average labor requirement for special branches serve as a guide"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "For owners of a part-time business, the value of the work is to be calculated in accordance with the order of 15 7 1982 - S-2149 - 32 - St 16 - 31 ESt-Nr 70/1982 to \u00a7 13a EStG and according to Section 130a Paragraph 4 Clause 7 EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Examples for calculating the value of the work performed are given in Appendix 2 of this order"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "In this respect, I refer to Section 13a (6) sentence 2 EStG and Section 130a (7) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The rent received also includes income from ground rent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Income from hunting leases is compensated by the basic amount as it relates to areas included in the initial value"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "224 Profits according to Section 13a Paragraph 8 EStG I refer to Section 13a Paragraph 8 EStG and Section 130a Paragraph 8 EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "In addition, please note the following: Profits from operations that were not taken into account when determining the initial value are e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits from the sale of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals (see section 2241), profits from the rental of rooms to holiday guests and from the rental of camping sites (ESt-Kartei NRW \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG A No. 82), as far as it is concerned Income from agriculture and forestry, interest income, insofar as the capital claim is attributable to the business assets, profits from the rental of own horses, insofar as it is income from agriculture and forestry, profits from secondary activities, profits from investments that are used for agricultural and forestry purposes Forestry business assets include, profits from the keeping and care of retired animals, profits from the rearing of animals in the wage system (see decision of 11 6 1985 - S-2149 - 35 - St 16 - 31 ESt-Nr 54/1985 to \u00a7 13a EStG) , Rental income from living space belonging to agricultural and forestry business assets (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Farm workers house)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Profits from the cross-company use of machines, which are achieved in the context of agriculture and forestry, are not to be recorded according to Section 13a (8) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "You have already been paid for by applying the basic amount (ESt-Kartei NRW \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG A Nr 103)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The profits (additional profits) according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 8 EStG are basically to be determined by comparing the operating income and operating expenses (\u00a7 4 Paragraph 3 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "If no records are available, the profits (additional profits) are to be estimated according to the principles of Section 4 Paragraph 1 EStG (Section 130 a Paragraph 8 Sentences 8 to 11 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "When estimating the profits (additional profits) from the sale of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals, from vegetable growing, fruit growing as well as from the special crops asparagus and strawberry cultivation, the following guidelines can serve as a guide"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Their application must not lead to an obviously incorrect taxation (BFH judgment of 16 12 1965 BStBl 1966 III p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "193)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "2241 Sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals As additional profit from the sale of breeding animals and other particularly valuable animals, 80%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "the amount by which the individual sales proceeds including sales tax exceed the following starting values \u200b\u200b(normal prices): Breeding bulls 3750 DMBreeding cows2500 DMBreeding cattle2500 DMMother calves770 DMBreeding boars900 DMBreeding sows820 DMFor breeding and riding horses, the additional profit is 60%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "the amount by which the selling price exceeds the starting value of 6,000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "If sales proceeds of more than DM 13,000 are achieved, the full amount of DM 8,800 (DM 6,000 + 40%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "of 7000 DM)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Wages for paid workers as well as the selling costs (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Auction fees, insurance premiums, transport costs) have already been taken into account when calculating the initial values, so they cannot be assessed separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The additional profit must also be calculated individually for each animal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Offsetting with sales proceeds that are below the initial values \u200b\u200bmay not be carried out in this context"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "2242 Vegetable growing (agricultural and horticultural vegetable growing) To distinguish between agricultural and horticultural vegetable growing, see Section 108, Paragraph 2 and 607, Paragraph 1, No. 1 BewRL 1964.If vegetable growing is attributable to agricultural use, a surcharge in accordance with Section 13a, Paragraph 8 of the Income Tax Act is out of the question"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Vegetables are only grown in the context of agricultural use if headed cabbage (white, red and savoy cabbage), picking peas and picking beans are grown exclusively using agricultural cultivation methods as part of agricultural crop rotation as the main crop"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "On the other hand, if the types of cabbage and / or peas or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Do not alternate beans with other agricultural crops such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Wheat, rye, barley, oats or beets, but one after the other or alternately with the same or different types of vegetables (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Endive, lettuce, lamb's lettuce, spinach, carrots, celery, beetroot, onions, radishes, leeks, tomatoes, kohlrabi, cucumbers, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": ") cultivated, the cultivation is no longer part of the agricultural crop rotation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Rather, it is a vegetable cultivation that is to be assessed according to horticultural principles (vegetable cultivation division of the horticultural use of vegetables, flowers and ornamental plants)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "If, in individual cases, an estimation method tailored to the company's circumstances is not preferable, or if accounting results from comparable farms or empirical records are not available, the profit can be estimated as follows: Horticultural field vegetable cultivation (income mainly from field vegetable cultivation): farm income 30,000 to 40,000 DM / ha Horticultural area Operating income 15,000 to 20,000 DM / ha area used for horticulture Operating income in% of operating income approx"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "50% horticultural vegetable growing with glass plants (income mainly from vegetables grown under glass): operating income 90,000 to 110,000 DM / ha horticultural area operating income 30,000 to 40,000 DM / ha horticultural area operating income in% of operating income approx"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "35-40% of the operating income can be deducted from the wages, interest and lease expenses associated with growing vegetables"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "An accurate estimate in individual cases is usually only possible in close cooperation with the ALS"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "2243 Special culture asparagus cultivation The income per hectare of asparagus cultivation area fluctuates between 20,000 and 34,000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The operating income, from which the wages, interest and lease expenses associated with growing asparagus can also be deducted, is between DM 12,000 and DM 26,000 / ha"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "2244 Fruit growing (horticultural use) The income from fruit growing amounts to - with the exception of strawberry cultivation (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "2245) - to 13,000 to 18,000 DM / ha"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "They depend on the quality of the soil, climate and the age structure of the orchard"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The farm income fluctuates between 5000 and 7000 DM / ha; Proportional wage, interest and lease expenses can also be deducted from this in accordance with numbers 2242 to 2243"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "2245 Strawberry cultivation When determining the average rate of profit, a distinction must be made between whether the land used for strawberry cultivation is harvested by the farmer and his workers or so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Can be left to self-pickers for harvesting (for a fee)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "In the case of harvest by the company, operating income between 30,000 and 35,000 DM / ha and operating income of 15,000 to 18,000 DM / ha can be assumed, while the operating income for self-picking is 20,000 to 22,000 DM / ha and the operating income between 8,000 and 9,000 DM / ha lies"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Numbers 2242 to 2244 apply accordingly with regard to wage, interest and lease expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "225 Value in use of the apartment The apartment within the meaning of Section 13a Paragraph 7 EStG includes the buildings and parts of the building, insofar as they serve the owner of the business, the family members belonging to his household and the retirees for residential purposes (Section 34 Paragraph 3 BewG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "This also applies if the parent's right of residence is secured in rem"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The value in use of the apartment left to the elderly is therefore always to be recorded in the amount of the proportional value of 1/18 of the apartment value specifically shown in the unit value for income from agriculture and forestry and in the corresponding amount as a permanent burden in accordance with Section 10 (1) No. 1a EStG to be taken into account (see BFH judgment of 28 7 1983 BStBl 1984 II, p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "226 Lease interest paid, interest on debt, ongoing charges I refer to Section 13a (3) sentence 2 EStG as well as Section 130a (9) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Interest subsidies from public funds reduce the deductible debt interest"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "With regard to the income tax treatment of the interest reduction subsidies according to the agricultural credit program, see decree of FinM NRW of 21 3 1985 S-2230 - 75 - VB 2 communicated by decree of 12 4 1985 - S-2230 - 59 - St 16 - 31227 Other additions and reductions as such z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The following can be considered: additions and deductions according to \u00a7 6c EStG, increased deductions for residential buildings according to \u00a7 7b EStG i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 52 EStDV, tax relief according to \u00a7 78 EStDV With increased deductions according to \u00a7 7b EStG it should be noted that the loss clause of \u00a7 7a Abs 6 EStG a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "no longer applies for financial years beginning after December 31, 1979 (Section 52 (21) EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "However, the tax relief according to \u00a7 78 EStDV must still not lead to a loss from agriculture and forestry (\u00a7 78 Paragraph 3 EStDV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The other increased deductions according to \u00a7 7d EStG, \u00a7\u00a7 82a, 82b, 82g and 82; EStDV and according to the Protective Building Act cannot be taken into account when determining profits according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 3-7 EStG, because the average rates basically compensate for the depreciation and thus also the increased deductions that replace them (see BFH judgment of 7 June 1984 BStBl 1984 II, p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "663)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "However, if an asset is used in a part of the business whose full income is to be recorded in accordance with Section 13a (8) EStG, increased deductions can also be taken into account when determining the profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "3 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry by comparing the operating income with the operating expenses (Section 4 Paragraph 3 EStG) 31 Scope I refer to Section 127 Paragraph 3 EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "32 Determination of profits (Section 17 EStR) In this regard, I would like to point out the following: 321 Average cattle values become"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise I refer to section 431"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "322 Value in use of the apartment To determine the value in use of the apartment, I refer to the ESt-Kartei NRW \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG Anw"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "No. 100"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the value in use is to be measured according to the circumstances of the individual case, even for farmers and foresters"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "With regard to the value in use of the apartment for elderly people, the BFH judgment of July 28, 1983 (BStBl 1984 II, p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "97) must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the value in use is to be assigned to the owner even in the case of real security and to be taken into account in the corresponding amount as a permanent burden in accordance with Section 10 (1) No. 1a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "4 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry through bookkeeping (Section 4 (1) EStG) 41 Scope of application I refer to section 127 (1) EStR and the BMF letter of 15 December 1981 (BStBl 1981 I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "878 / Appendix 5 to the income tax hand edition)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Cattle surcharges are also to be taken into account when determining the economic value limit according to \u00a7 141 Paragraph 1 No. 3 AO if they are not or not yet the subject of a value update according to \u00a7\u00a7 41 i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "22 para 1 no 1 BewG have been made"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "42 Opening balance sheets In order to check the balance sheets during the transition to the comparison of business assets, I refer to the order of 14 11 1983 - S-2163 - 33 - St 16 - 31 -, ESt-Nr 92/1983 to \u00a7 4 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "43 Bookkeeping On section 13 EStR and the BMF letter of 15 12 1981 BStBl 1981 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "878 is pointed out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "44 Determination of profit 441 Average livestock values \u200b\u200bI refer to section 125 of the Income Tax Regulations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The applicable average livestock values \u200b\u200bresult from the ESt-Kartei NRW to \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG Anw"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "No. 20 For the evaluation of horses from the 1980/81 financial year I also refer to the order of 22 6 1981 - S-2132a - 2 - St 11 - 31 - (ESt-Kartei NRW \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG Anw"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "No. 111)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "442 Value in use of the apartment Section 322 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "5 Estimate of the profit for farmers and foresters whose profit cannot be determined according to average rates51 General For farmers and foresters who are obliged to keep accounts but do not keep proper books, the profit is to be estimated in individual cases according to \u00a7 162 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to those farmers and foresters who are neither obliged to keep accounts nor meet the requirements of \u00a7 13a Paragraph 1 No. 2 and 3 EStG if they do not have any books in the sense of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 4 Paragraph 1 EStG and also the operating income and operating expenses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "of Section 4 Paragraph 3 EStG (Section 127 Paragraph 2-4 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "With the exception of the cases mentioned in Section 127, Paragraph 4, Clause 62, EStR, the estimate must be based on the principles of Section 4, Paragraph 1 of the Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "When making the estimate, all circumstances that are important for the estimate must be taken into account (Section 162 (1) sentence 2 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The aim of the estimate must be to determine the profit actually achieved"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The uncertainties inherent in an estimate are, however, at the expense of the taxpayer, who himself gave cause for the estimate by neglecting his tax cooperation obligations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "It is also important to ensure that farmers who are required to keep accounts and whose profits are estimated are reported to the tax auditor if an audit appears to be suitable to encourage the farmer to keep accounts, or if the audit promises success for other reasons (see also Annex 15 available from 12 9 1984 - S-2522 - 60 - St 16 - 31 -)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "If a tax audit is planned in this sense, the assessment is to be carried out subject to the review (Section 164 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise, according to \u00a7 14 Paragraph 1 ALDA-FEST"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "For the VZ 1984, the following explanatory text must be included in the notification or in all cases where the profit is estimated due to non-compliance with the accounting obligation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "to be attached as an attachment: \"The profit from agriculture and forestry was estimated for the 1984/1985 financial year in accordance with \u00a7 162 AO because you did not declare your profits, although you are obliged to keep accounts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "If you actually achieved a higher profit than the estimated, the tax would have been set too low"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "In this case, there may be tax evasion or frivolous tax reduction"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "You can then, however, by declaring the profit actually achieved under the further conditions of \u00a7\u00a7 371 378 Paragraph 3 AO impunity or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Obtain no fines"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Furthermore, I would like to point out that failure to comply with the accounting obligation can already result in a tax risk"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "\"52 Estimation of the profit according to standard rates Which estimation method is to be used in the individual case is left to the discretion of the tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "If, in individual cases, an estimation method tailored to the particular operational conditions is not to be preferred, or if the accounting results of comparable operations or empirical data are not available, the profit is to be estimated as follows in accordance with the principles of Section 4 (1) EStG: starting amount (section 521) + rental income ( Sect. 522) + surcharges for profits or profits not paid for with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits (Sect. 523) + value in use of the apartment (Sect. 524)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Wage expenses (Section 525)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Lease expenses, debt interest, permanent burdens (Sect. 526) +"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Other surcharges and reductions (Section 527) = profit for the financial year The following guide rates are intended to serve as a guide for an accurate estimate of the profit (Section 127 (2) sentence 2 of the Income Tax Regulation)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "At the same time, a reduction in the estimated profit due to objections to individual points in the valuation process is generally out of the question because special circumstances in an individual branch of the business do not allow any conclusions to be drawn about the profit of the entire business"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The application of the standard rates must not lead to an obviously incorrect taxation (see judgment of the BFH of 16 12 1965 BStBl 1966 III, p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "193)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "When estimating the profit according to the guideline rates, the following must be observed:"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "der LN) with a root crop portion of a) 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "and more of the LN1450-- DMb) less than 15 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "the LN1200-- DM2 for mixed farms (grassland share 31 - 70 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "der LN) with a root crop portion of a) 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "and more of the LN1350-- DMb) less than 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "the LN1300-- DM3 in pasture farming (grassland share 71 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "and more of the LN) 1300-- DM4 For sugar beet farms (root crop content more than 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "the LN, including: sugar beet content more than 20%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "der LN) 1900-- DM Agricultural use includes the agricultural production areas"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Areas for buildings, courtyards, paths, ditches, field borders, water, land, quarries, sand pits and similar areas are therefore not taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Areas for house gardens are also not included"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise, Section 124a Paragraph 3 EStR applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "For the calculation of the relevant root crop, grassland or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The proportion of sugar beet depends on the extent of this proportion in the respective marketing year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The areas under cultivation of root crops do not include those areas on which root crops are only grown as catch crops or as catch crops"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Only those in Paragraph"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "5232 listed meadows and pastures; the other crops mentioned there (forage plants) are not included"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "5211 Reduction of the starting amount In the district of the tax offices of Arnsberg, Brilon, L\u00fcdenscheid, Meschede, Olpe and Siegen, a discount of up to (maximum) 30% from the starting amount can be made on request for companies whose areas are predominantly more than 250 m high, if the average EMZ of the company is less than 25 and in addition particularly unfavorable earnings ratios (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "due to waterlogging, steep slope)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "These requirements must always be checked by the ALS before the application is accepted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "5212 Increase of the starting amounts According to my rulings of 24 3 1983 - S-2230 - 68 - St 16 - 31 - and of 23 12 1983 - S-2230 - 79 - St 16 - 31 -, increased starting amounts of the Taxation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Are the in the annex to the o"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Letter from 1 7 1983 or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "on 17/1984 to the taxpayers concerned and they did not set up or keep any accounts for the 1984/85 financial year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "If the actual profit is not determined in accordance with Section 4 (3) EStG, I ask you to observe the following principles: The starting amounts are usually to be increased if the estimate for the 1984/85 financial year was preceded by at least five profit estimates"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "In the other cases (two or more estimates at the time of the reminder, but not yet five previous estimates), safety margins are considered if in individual cases special circumstances suggest that the use of the starting amounts leads to a profit estimate that is too low"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The tax office decides on the amount and staggering of the security surcharges at its due discretion, taking into account all the circumstances of the individual case"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "I would also ask farmers and foresters whose profit was estimated for the second time in a row as part of the 1984 income tax assessment to comply with their statutory accounting obligations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "the determination of the actual profit according to \u00a7 4 Abs 1 EStG or \u00a7 4 Abs 3 EStG by sending the o"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Remember cover letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "522 Lease income Lease income, ground rent and hunting leases are to be added to the starting amount if they are included in income from agriculture and forestry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "This is the case when the leased or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Hereditary assets belong to the agricultural and forestry business assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "With the o"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Lease income related business expenses (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Property taxes) can also be taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "523 Surcharges for winnings or winnings not settled with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "All profits from sustainable or one-off operating income that are not included in the starting amount are to be added to the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Such surcharges come z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Consideration for additional profits from sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals, profits from abnormal animal husbandry, additional profits from special crops, profits from other special business branches (see \"Special operating income\" on p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "4 of Annex L) Profits from the withdrawal and sale of land (see \"Sale / withdrawal of land\" on p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "2 of Annex L)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The surcharges are generally to be determined by comparing the operating income and operating expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "If no records are available, the profits (additional profits) are to be estimated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The following guidelines can serve as a guide: 5231 Sale of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals Section 2241 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "5232 Abnormal animal husbandry Profits from animal breeding and husbandry are settled with the starting amount (Section 521), provided that the average normal animal population is not exceeded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "For the area of \u200b\u200bthe OFD M\u00fcnster, the animal husbandry paid for with the starting amount is to be applied to forage farms, other farms for the first 20 ha LN16 VE / ha14 VE / h for the next 10 ha LN10 / ha08 / h for the next 20 ha LN09 / ha07 / h for each further ha LN08 VE / ha06 VE / haFodder-growing farms are farms where the forage area is 60 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "and more of the usable agricultural area without courtyard and building space, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "matters"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "In this context, the forage area includes: Meadows (incl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Tree meadows, litter meadows), cattle pastures and arable meadows, furthermore the cultivation areas for clover in pure seed and mixed cultivation, clover grass, alfalfa, seradella, sasparsette, green corn, vetches, sweet lupins and all other forage plants"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Areas on which grain is grown for grain production are not included in the forage area even if the grain is fed to the livestock kept on the farm"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "When calculating the number of animals and converting them into livestock units, animals that do not have a current profit (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "by selling milk) or where the profit is recorded by the young animals obtained from them (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Breeding sows, nurse cows, suckler cows) can only be set against the number of animals sold or consumed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "I refer to the overview attached as Annex 3"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The excess inventory remaining after the normal inventory has been taken into account is to be recognized as a profit for the 1984/85 financial year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "As a rule DM 400 per unit if only broiler poultry are rearing, DM 210 per unit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The surcharge value that is to be applied when laying hens are kept exclusively when the eggs are mainly sold to wholesalers and collection points has not yet been determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "I would therefore ask you to first apply the previous year's value of DM 300 and carry out the assessment provisionally"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "As soon as the determinations are completed, a special instruction will be issued on this point (acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "OFD M\u00fcnster S-2230 - 91 - St 16 - 31 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "11 3 1986 the hammer price for the 1984/85 financial year is 400-- DM per VE)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The amounts deviating from the standard rate can also be used as a guide if the animals are kept predominantly by the aforementioned animals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Wages are not taken into account here and can therefore still be deducted separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "5233 Agricultural vegetable growing (open-field vegetable growing) For the open-air cultivation of cabbage, picking peas and picking beans carried out in the context of agricultural crop rotation according to agricultural cultivation methods (as the main crop), no special guideline rates have been determined for the 1984/85 marketing year because such cases are seldom included in profit estimates occurrence"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Field cultivation of headed cabbage, picking peas and picking beans, which is not carried out in the context of agricultural crop rotation or in accordance with agricultural cultivation methods, must be taken into account according to No. 2242"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "5234 Vegetable growing (horticultural use), special crops asparagus cultivation, fruit growing (horticultural use), strawberry cultivation Sections 2242 to 2245 apply accordingly for the determination of the profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "As a surcharge on the starting amount, however, only the additional profit, i.e."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "the profit reduced by the pro-rata starting amount applied in the individual case"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "524 Value in use of the apartment, Section 322 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "When estimating the profit, the gross value in use must always be applied, because the expenses associated with the apartment - with the exception of interest on debt (Section 526) and the increased deductions (Section 527) - are taken into account when determining the starting amounts (Section 521) and thus are settled"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "525 Wage Expenses For the starting amount (Sect. 521) it is assumed that the business is managed exclusively with unpaid workers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Wage expenses are therefore to be deducted from the starting amount insofar as they relate to the profits settled with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The treatment of wage expenses incurred with profits or income not paid for in the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits (cf. Sect. 523) result from the respective surcharge regulations (cf. Sections 5231 to 5234)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "For the distribution of wage expenses required in individual cases, Sect. 222 Nos. 2 and 3 apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The wage expenses to be deducted also include the expenses for temporary workers employed on a short-term basis as well as for workers who are"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Contractors are made available for certain ordering, maintenance or harvesting work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "If wage expenses in connection with machine expenses are invoiced in one sum by the contractor, there are generally no concerns that the proportionate wage expenses to be taken into account at 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "to estimate the gross amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "If wage expenses cannot be proven, an estimate e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "possible according to documents from comparable companies"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Regarding the need to notify the income tax office in such cases, I refer to section 62 letter c)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "526 Lease expenses, debt interest, permanent charges These expenses can be deducted if they are operating expenses and have not already been taken into account when determining the surcharges according to Sect. 523"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "If, in addition to the rent for the lease of land and / or buildings (net lease), the lessee bears other expenses relating to the leased property (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Property tax, apportionment of the Chamber of Agriculture, building insurance), these expenses are not deductible as business expenses, as they have already been taken into account when determining the starting amounts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "527 Other surcharges and reductions 527 Allocation due to building depreciation when estimating the profit When calculating the starting amount, the deductions for wear and tear from the value of the farm buildings are already taken into account in accordance with Section 7 EStG, because it is assumed that the business is managed by the owner himself"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "In cases of leasing or free transfer of agricultural operations as a whole, the depreciation for the company buildings is available to the lessor or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "to the leaving farmer"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "For this reason, the authorized user (manager of the business) has to increase the starting amount (Section 521) by 100 DM per hectare of leased LN"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "5272 Increased reductions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "increased deductions for residential buildings according to \u00a7 7b EStG and increased deductions according to \u00a7\u00a7 82a, 82g and 82i EStDV into consideration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "These increased deductions are, however, by the depreciation already taken into account in the starting amount according to \u00a7 7 Abs 4 EStG of 2 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "to shorten"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "5273 Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV can be deducted from the starting amount if the register is kept according to \u00a7 7a Paragraph 8 EStG (see order of 8 5 1981 - S-2184 - 59 - St 11 - 31 -)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "In these cases I would ask you to request the directory and to take a copy of the tax files"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "After the expiry of the preferential treatment period of three financial years, the starting amount is to be increased by a surcharge when using the preferential treatment according to \u00a7 76 EStDV, since according to \u00a7 76 Abs. 1 Satz 2 EStDV the residual value is the assessment basis for the further depreciation and otherwise due to the application of the starting amount high depreciation amounts would be taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The surcharge for a financial year is the sum of the special depreciation granted divided by the remaining useful life of the respective asset"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The initial amount must be increased for the remaining period of use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "When making use of the preferential treatment for immovable assets with a useful life of more than 30 years as well as for conversions and extensions of these assets, a correction is not necessary in view of Section 76 (4) sentence 3 EStDV for reasons of simplification"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "In order to ensure that the surcharges are also taken into account in future assessments, the control sheet for profit surcharges (Section 76 EStDV), form no. 724/49, must be kept and attached to the income tax file"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "6 Other 61 Retirement benefits 611 For reasons of simplification, the following can be recognized as the value of the cashless retirement benefits for the assessment period 1984 without special proof: to apply proven actual (proportionate) costs"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "612 If partial retirement benefits do not only consist of benefits in kind and in kind due to farm handover contracts between parents and children, it must be checked in each individual case whether the individual partial benefits are life annuities or permanent burdens (recurring payments) (reference to Section 167 (1) No. 2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "b EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Because of the transitional regulation for existing retirement contracts, I refer to the decrees of the Minister of Finance of the State of North Rhine-Westphalia of 18 10 1984 and of 26 3 1985 - S-2221 - 109 - VB 2 -, communicated by order of 24 10 1984 and 4 4 1985 - S- 2221 - 11 - St 16 - 31 -, ESt-Nr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "81/1984 and 22/1985 on \u00a7 10 EStG as well as my order of 29 11 1985 - S-2221 - 11 - St 16 - 31 ESt-Nr 103/1985 on \u00a7 10 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "62 Control notifications Except in the usual cases (control notifications for the purpose of tax audits, the recording of taxable transactions at other taxpayers, inheritance tax), control notifications are to be prepared in the following cases in particular:"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "to disclose circumstances arising from the files that may affect the amount of the fixed unit value (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Change in areas for special uses, change in animal populations - see also order of 10 6 1976 - S-2230 - 45 - St 11 - 31 -)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Information that may be of importance for an award according to \u00a7 41 BewG can be found on p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "4 of Appendix L summarized"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "I therefore ask, in all cases in which the livestock declared in Annex L obviously exceeds or exceeds the animal population customary in the area"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "in which, for other reasons, a surcharge according to \u00a7 41 BewG may be considered, the assessment body by sending a photo of the S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "4 of Appendix L."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "In this context, I would like to point out that Annex L must also be completed in full by farmers who keep books (reference to Annex 23 at my disposal of 12 9 1984 - S-2522 - 60 - St 16 - 31 -)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Are access or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Leases known, so the lessor or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Inform the leaseholder of the competent assessment office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to the transfer of use free of charge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "This can be done in accordance with No. 3 of the order of 27 1 1981 - S-2230-63 - St 11-31"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "For the rest, I would ask you to ensure that taxpayers on S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "2 of Annex L the addresses of the lessee / lessor, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "specify exactly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "In particular, cases without signal \"A\", in which wage expenses are claimed, and cases with significant wage expenses are to be reported to the responsible income tax office for examination by the income tax field audit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "This also applies if wage expenses are set at an estimated amount when determining the profit (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "Section 525 Paragraph 4)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "63 Standard value notifications Unit value notifications for agricultural and forestry assets must always be evaluated promptly, particularly because of the possible effects on the way in which the taxpayer's profit is determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "64 Consultation of the valuation files when carrying out the assessment In particular when determining profits in accordance with Section 13a of the Income Tax Act (EStG) and in valuation cases, I ask that you refer to the assessment files for the assessment and review of the values \u200b\u200bto be applied in the individual case when calculating profits"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "The plants were not included"}, {"meta": {"name": "0059034.xml"}, "text": "--- Income tax / wage tax / church tax Accounting North Rhine-Westphalia Agriculture Agriculture"}]