[{"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion M\u00fcnchenS-2000 - 9 St 212S-2530 - St 203S-2530 -S-2000 -Bibliography of the relevant administrative instructions: BremenS-2530 - St 203 of 18041984 Reference: My order of 15031983 - S-2530 - St 203 Amendments to the Income Tax Act, which will take effect in 1983 and later"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "The law on the new regulation of the taxation of single parents, which is expected to be passed in the first half of 1984, has not yet been taken into account (cf. judgment of the BVerfG of 3 11 1982 BStBl II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "717), which will be applicable retrospectively to all cases in which this is possible according to the regulations of the AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "For the sake of clarity, clarifying or editorial changes are not included; Likewise, the inclusion of such changes that only affect the wage tax area has not been included"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "Relevant laws: Second law to improve the household structure of December 22, 1981 BStBl 1982 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "235 ff"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "Budget Accompanying Act 1983 of December 20, 1982 BStBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "972 ff"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "Law to promote the willingness of foreigners to return of 28 November 1983 BStBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "565 Law amending the Political Parties Act and other laws of December 22, 1983 BStBl 1984 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "7 ff"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "Law to strengthen the competitiveness of the economy and to restrict tax advantages (Tax Relief Act 1984) of December 22, 1983 BStBl 1984 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "14 ff"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "Act to promote the formation of assets by employees through equity investments (Asset Participation Act) of December 22, 1983 BStBl 1984 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "23 ff"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "Changed regulation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "LawContent of the amendmentRemarks\u00a7 2a EStGbRestriction of loss compensation for foreign losses from non-active activities 8 EStGa Elimination of the degressive depreciation for buildings erected abroad Section 7 g EStGe Introduction of special depreciation for small and medium-sized companies applies to acquisition or production after May 18, 1983 Section 10 Paragraph 6 No. 2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "e) EStGc Tax-free early repayment of building society savings in certain cases applies to return migration after September 30th"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "1983 \u00a7 10 c EStGb Reduction of the pension allowance for civil servants, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 10 d EStG doubling of the maximum amount for the loss carry back to 10 million"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "DM \u00a7 15, Paragraph 2 of the Income Tax Law definition of commercial income; Clarification that tax savings are not intended to make a profit \u00a7 21 a Paragraph 4 EStGb Introduction of an extended debt interest deduction for objects that fall under \u00a7 21 a EStG Only when production begins after September 30"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "1982 \u00a7 32 Abs 5 to 7 EStGa Reduction of the age for the child allocation ex officio from 18 to 16 years \u00a7 32 Abs 8 EStGb Introduction of a child allowance of 432/216 DM \u00a7 33 a Abs 3 EStG Abolition of the deduction of child care costs for single parents! But see \u00a7 53 a EStG \u00a7 46 Abs 2 Nr 2 b EStG Introduction of a further assessment when using different income tax tables \u00a7 51 Abs 1 Nr 2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "q) Income Tax Act; \u00a7 82 a EStGDVe limitation of increased deductions to certain new technologies applies to completion after June 30, 1983 \u00a7 51 Paragraph 1 No. 2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "r cc) EStG; \u00a7 82 g EStDV extension of the benefit for five years (DV draft) \u00a7 51 para 1 no 2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "u) EStG; \u00a7 82 d EStDVe Reintroduction of special depreciation on assets that serve research and development applies to acquisition or manufacture after May 18, 1983 Changes to the EStG, which are to be applied from 1984: Changed regulation Mass"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "Content of the amendment \u00a7 10 b EStGd Treatment of party donations to non-profit organizations \u00a7 14 a EStGe Replacement of the unit value by the economic value as the assessment basis for the beneficiary limit; Increase in non-harmful other income by 50 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "Section 16 (4) sentence 3 of the Income Tax Act doubling of the tax exemptions and maximum limits in the case of old-age and disability-related business sales 3 EStG Exclusion of the consideration of losses from renting and leasing (exception: 7 b-properties) up to the year of completion from the consideration in the prepayment procedure \u00a7 39 a Abs 1 Nr e 6 EStG parallel regulation to \u00a7 37 Abs 3 EStG for the wage tax reduction procedure \u00a7 51 Paragraph 1 No. 2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0060794.xml"}, "text": "w) EStG; \u00a7 82 f EStDV extension of the benefit by six years --- income tax / wage tax / church taxBayernBremen income tax"}]