[{"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion BremenS-2530 - St 203S-2530 -Amendment of the income tax law in 1985My order of June 6, 1985 - S-2530 - St 203Anlg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": ": - 1 - In 1985, too, the Income Tax Act and Implementation Ordinance were significantly changed and supplemented"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "To facilitate the work in the assessment, wage tax and tax audit area, I am sending you a systematic overview of the new regulations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "The 1985 Income Tax Act in the version dated December 12, 1985 (BStBl 1985 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "223) and the 1981 Income Tax Implementation Ordinance in the version of 23 6 1982 (BStBl 1982 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "592) underwent changes in 1985 through the law on performance-enhancing tax reductions and relief for the family (Tax Reduction Act 1986/1988 - StSenkG 1986/1988) of 26 June 1985 (BStBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "391 ff"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "), Act to Simplify Housing Regulations (Housing Law Simplification Act 1985 - WoVereinfG 1985) of 11 7 1985 (BStBl 1985 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "498 ff, 503), law on the granting of childcare allowance and childcare leave (Federal Childcare Allowance Act - BErzGG) of 6 December 1985 (BGBl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "1985 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "2154 ff, 2160), Act for the Implementation of the Fourth, Seventh and Eighth Directive of the Council of the European Communities on the Coordination of Company Law (Accounting Directive Act - BiRiLiG) of 19 12 1985 (BStBl 1985 I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "704), law to improve the depreciation conditions for farm buildings and for modern heating and hot water systems from 19 12 1985 (BStBl 1985 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "705), Tax Adjustment Act 1986 of 19 12 1985 (BStBl 1985 I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "735 ff"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "745)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "The individual changes are listed in the appendix, sorted according to \u00a7\u00a7"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "The date of first-time application is also specified and reference is made to the respective amendment standard"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "The overview follows on from the overview sent with the purchase order"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Annex: Provision Compilation of the amendments made in 1985 to the EStG / EStDV content Amendment standard valid from (see overview in Section 1 (2) EStG expansion of the regulation on extended unrestricted tax liability also to relatives who are not German citizens if they do not earn any income, who are taxable abroadf\u00a7 1 para 3 EStG Extension of the extended unrestricted tax liability to employees - incl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "the beneficiary - of the federal government or a country with residence abroad without diplomatic or consular status; for the child allowances, the unrestricted tax liability is replaced by the household membership of the childrenf\u00a7 1 para 4 EStG editorial changef\u00a7 2 para 5 EStG editorial consequential change in the definition of the Taxable income due to the reorganization of \u00a7 32 EStG1986a\u00a7 3 No. 9 EStG Abolition of the restriction of early retirement benefits, tax exemption regulation for which are granted as current payments 1985f\u00a7 3 No. 62 sentence 1 2 half-sentence EStG Tax exemption of the employer's contribution to the health insurance of an employee subject to insurance, that the substitute health insurance contribution is higher than the contribution to the statutory health insurance 1986 f\u00a7 3 No. 64 EStG amendment of the provisions on the tax exemption of purchasing power compensation due to the new \u00a7 1 paragraph 3 EStG as acquisition costs is the value with de m the goodwill in the balance sheet has been recognized on the first balance sheet date after December 30, 1986 or would have been recognized if there had been an obligation to draw up a balance sheet on this date, the start of the normal useful life is the beginning of the first financial year starting after December 31, 1986"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "f\u00a7 3 No. 67 EStG Tax exemption of childcare allowance1986c\u00a7 4 Par.5 No. 1 EStG Abolition of the labeling requirement for promotional giftsef\u00a7 6 Par.1 No. 1 Clause 4 Para 3 Clause 3 EStG unrestricted value context does not apply to the cases of attribution according to \u00a7 6 Par.3 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "2 EStGd \u00a7 6 Abs 1 Nr 2 Satz 1 EStG Goodwill depreciable economic good \u00a7 6 Abs 3 Satz 1 EStG Prerequisite for the use of increased deductions, special depreciations and certain other tax benefits is corresponding disclosure in the commercial balance sheet (relevance of the commercial balance sheet in the year in which the tax relief is claimed ) d\u00a7 6 (3) sentence 2 EStG Additions in the commercial balance sheet also lead to increases in profits in the tax balance sheet (relevance of the commercial balance sheet in the years after the tax break has been claimed) d\u00a7 7 (1) sentence 3 EStG usefulness of the goodwill 15 yearsd\u00a7 7 para 4 Income tax linear depreciation of 4 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "for farm buildings for which the application for a building permit was made after 31 3 1985e \u00a7 7 Abs 5 EStG new dergressive depreciation scale for farm buildings for which the application for building permit was made after 31 3 1985e \u00a7 9b Abs 3EStG a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Elimination of the provision on recording self-consumption tax i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 30 UStG a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "as part of the acquisition or production costsf\u00a7 10 para. 1 no. 1 EStG increase of the maximum amount in the case of limited real splitting to DM 18,0001986a\u00a7 10 para. 1 no. 3 sentence 2 EStG loan for the acquisition of residential property i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 12a II WoBauG no longer benefited1986b\u00a7 10 paragraph 3 No. 1 EStG discontinuation of the child-related increase in pension expenses1986a\u00a7 10 paragraph 4 sentence 3 EStG editorial adjustment to the amendment of the WoPG1986a\u00a7 10 paragraph 5 EStG editorial adjustment to the change of the SparPG and WoPG 10c ESta in the provisions on the lump-sum provision due to the discontinuation of the child-related increase in the provision expenses 1986a, section 10c, paragraph 3, last sentence of the Income Tax Act, abolition of the limit on the assessment basis for the lump-sum provision, 1986a, section 14a, paragraph 1 of the Income Tax Act (Section 14a, paragraph 3 of the Income Tax Act), increase in the tax exemption and the tax exemption limits in the event of alienation Abandonment of smaller agricultural and forestry operations, extension of the period of validityf\u00a7 14a Para"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Land to compensate for deviating heirsf\u00a7 14a (5) EStG Introduction of a tax exemption of 90,000 DM for the sale of agricultural and forestry land for debt repaymentf\u00a7 15 (1) EStG Remuneration for the services of the co-entrepreneurs to the partnership are also to be added to the profit if they are the partner or a Legal successor only accrues after the establishment of the partnership has ended"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Correspondence in accordance with the legal requirements of Section 15a, Paragraph 4 of the Income Tax Act (EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Paid recurring payments with unlimited corporation tax liability of the donor 1986f\u00a7 22 No. 1 sentence 2 2 clause of the Income Tax Law Exception from the prohibition of recording of \u00a7 22 No. 1 clause 2 1 clause of the EStG for recurring payments from corporations with unlimited tax liability, exempt from corporation tax etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "If the payments are not made in fulfillment of charitable, charitable or church purposes 1986f\u00a7 24b EStG Extension of the training place deduction amount by five years\u00a7 25 para 3 sentence 3 EStG declaration obligation when choosing the special assessment1986a\u00a7 26 para 1 EStG reintroduction of the special assessment for the year of Marriage 1986a, Section 26 (2) of the Income Tax Act, exercise of the right to vote in favor of the special assessment, 1986a, Section 26a, Section 2 of the Income Tax Act, editorial adjustment to Section 33c of the Income Tax Act 1986a, Section 26c of the Income Tax Act, principles of the special assessment for the assessment period of the marriage 1986a, Section 32, paragraphs 1 to 6 of the income tax allowances, 1986a, Section 32, paragraphs 7 of the income tax allowances Income tax increase of the household allowance to 4536 DM1986a\u00a7 32a paragraph 1 EStG new tariff formula1988a\u00a7 52 paragraph 23b EStG new tariff formula\u00a7 33 paragraph 3 last sentence EStGB consideration of children when calculating the reasonable burden\u00a7 33a paragraph 1 EStG change the requirements, the maximum amount and the a Non-billing amount with deduction of maintenance payments1986a\u00a7 33a para 1a EStGFree allowance for expenses of the parent who is not entitled to allocation \"to maintain the parent-child relationship\" 1986a\u00a7 33a para 2 EStG Increase of the training allowances and change the requirement for their grant1986a\u00a7 33a para 3 No. 2 EStG editorial change1986a Section 33a (4) of the Income Tax Act (EStG) Disregarding income and payments that are based on periods outside of the support or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "1986f\u00a7 33a Abs 5 EStG\u00a7 33 EStG for expenses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 33a para 1a EStG not applicable1986a\u00a7 33b para 5 EStG requirements for the transfer of the physically disabled or surviving dependents lump sum due to a child1986a\u00a7 33c EStG Change of the child exemption regulation1986a\u00a7 34f EStG editorial adjustment to the changed \u00a7 32 EStG1986a\u00a7 37 Income Tax Act clause 3 are the advance payment procedure for children in the amended \u00a7 32 EStG 1986a\u00a7 38 Paragraph 1 Clause 1 No. 2 EStGB Establishment of the duty to deduct wage tax for temporary workers in Germany, if the foreign lender is not a domestic employer1986f\u00a7 38b No. 2 EStG Tax class II, if the household allowance is to be taken into account (editorial adjustment) 1986a\u00a7 38c EStG Consequential changes to the wage tax tables Due to the changes in the pension lump sum, the child allowances, the household allowance and the 1986a \u00a7 39 Paragraph 3 EStG entry of the number of child allowances and the number of children on the LSt card by the municipality or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "the tax office1986a\u00a7 39 para 3 EStG application for consideration of children on the LSt card must be made on an official form1986f\u00a7 39 para 4 sentence 1 EStG editorial follow-up amendment1986a\u00a7 39 para 5 sentence 1 EStG editorial follow-up change1986a\u00a7 39 para 5 sentence 2 EStG exclusion of the entry of a higher one Number of children in the year of marriage1986a\u00a7\u00a7 39a, 39b, 39c EStG changes and editorial adjustments to wage tax procedural regulations as a result of the amended \u00a7\u00a7 32 and 39 EStG1986a\u00a7 39c paragraph 3 EStG editorial adjustment to the new \u00a7 1 paragraph 3 EStG1986f\u00a7 39d EStG change in wage tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Procedural rules for Beschr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Taxable employees as a result of the new regulation in Section 50 (4) EStG1986a, Section 41 (2) sentence 2 EStG business premises fiction for foreign lenders who are obliged to deduct income tax1986f, Section 42 (2) EStG, deadline for the annual income tax settlement extended to two yearsf Section 42b (2) EStG editorial adjustment to the change in 39 EStG1986a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "1 EStG Deadline for submitting the capital gains tax registration (correction of an editorial mistake) f\u00a7 46 Paragraph 2 Sentence 1 No. 2b EStG Editorial adjustment to the amended \u00a7 10c EStG1986a\u00a7 46 Paragraph 2 Sentence 1 No. 4a EStG on the training allowance1986a\u00a7 46 Paragraph 2 Sentence 1 No. 5 EStGAmtsveranlagung in the case of marriage in the assessment period 1986a\u00a7 46 Paragraph 2 Sentence 1 No. 7 EStGAmtsveranlagung when choosing the special assessment 1986a\u00a7 49 Paragraph 1 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "1 EStG editorial adjustment to the addition of the new \u00a7 1 Abs 3 EStGf\u00a7 49 Abs 1 Nr 2 before lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "a EStG editorial follow-up amendment to the amendment to Section 49 Paragraph 1 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "c EStG a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "f\u00a7 49 para 1 no 2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "c Income tax expansion of the limited tax liability of shipping and aviation companies in the case of participations in pool contracts and similar operating groups 1986f\u00a7 49 para 1 no 2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "d EStG expansion of commercial income subject to limited taxation to income generated in Germany from artistic or sporting activities 1986f \u00a7 49 Paragraph 1 No. 2 Letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "e EStG sale of a significant stake in a domestic corporation regardless of this"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "subject to tax, whether this is held in a foreign business or private assetf\u00a7 49 para 1 no 6 EStG, transfer of rights regardless of this"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "stpfl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "the type of institution in which the domestic rights are exploited (clarification) 1986f\u00a7 49 para 3 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "3 EStG lump-sum taxation for income from pool contracts etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 49 Paragraph 1 No. 2 Letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "c EStG not applicable 1986f\u00a7 50 para 4 EStG elimination of the child allowance and the associated household allowance for employees with limited tax liability Consideration of the maintenance expenses for children acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Section 33a (1) EStG1986a, Section 50 (5) sentence 3 EStG, additional collection of income tax (wage tax) if the prerequisites for the extended, unrestricted taxation were not subsequently met, 1986f\u00a7 50a (4) no.1 EStG, introduction of a tax deduction for those according to Section 49 (1) no.2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "d EStG income to be recorded 1986 F \u00a7 51 Paragraph 1 No. 2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "d EStG authorization to issue a DV to regulate the taxation of temporary workers resident abroad1986f\u00a7 51 para 1 no 2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "q EStG authorization to amend \u00a7 82a EStDVe \u00a7 51 Paragraph 1 No. 2 Letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "w EStG authorization to extend the special depreciation for ships and aircraft according to \u00a7 82f EStDV by 5 yearsf\u00a7 51 para 1 no 2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "z EStG authorization to amend Section 74a EStDVf"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Loss clause i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 82f Abs 5 u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Paragraph 7 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "1 EStDV 1977 while maintaining the requirement of 30% self-financingf \u00a7 52 Abs 21 Sentences 7 to 10 EStG a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Special regulation for Berlin properties in view of the general standardization of common usage in Section 15 (3) No. 2 EStG no longer applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 33a EStG 1953a, \u00a7 52, Paragraph 26 of the Income Tax Law Preservation of ownership for the child-related tax reduction when using \u00a7 7b of the Income Tax Act (\u00a7 34f of the Income Tax Act) a \u00a7 52, Paragraph 26d and"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "26e EStG a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Deleted paragraphs overtaken by the passage of timef\u00a7 53b EStG Abolition of the special provisions for childcare costs from 1971 to 1983a\u00a7 74a EStDVLifo assessment also approved for rhodium and copperf\u00a7 76 EStDVA depreciation allowance extended by 6 yearsf\u00a7 78 EStDVA tax allowance extended by 6 years AfA for the installation of modern heating and hot water systems in buildings that are at least ten years old F\u00a7 82a Paragraph 3 S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "1 Income tax deduction of maintenance expenses for \u00a7 21a EStG objects no longer dependent on the requirement of \"first implementation\" of the measureF\u00a7 82a para 3 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "2 EStDV Purchase of new individual stoves favors if there is no central heating and the apartment has been completed for at least 10 years; to be applied for the first time for the assessment period 1981, on application also as far as tax assessments for the assessment periods 1981 to 1984 are already final; In the case of employees who are not assessed for income tax, the annual wage tax adjustment is carried out for the calendar years 1981 to 1984 if this is applied for by June 30, 1986, in deviation from Section 42 (2) sentence 3 EStG. Creation of a sound legal basis for the regulation in A 11 Paragraph 2 No. 1 LStREfirst for the fiscal year that ends after December 31, 1985 First to apply for the fiscal year that begins after December 31, 1986 Also applies to assessment periods prior to 1987 if tax assessments are not final or are subject to review First to apply for write-ups that in the trade balance for the financial year ending after 1 1 1986 to be applied for the first time for the financial year beginning after December 31, 1986"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "In the case of goodwill that the taxpayer acquired in return for the first business year beginning after December 31, 1986, Section 7 (1) sentence 3 shall apply with the proviso that, for the first time for the 1985 assessment period, Section 9b (3) EStG a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "after the regulation of \u00a7 30 UStG a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Overtaken for the first time for sales or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Withdrawals made within the framework of the time regulations of Section 14a Paragraph 1 Paragraph 4 and Paragraph 5 EStG after December 31, 1985 Also to be used for assessment periods prior to 1986 (see also Section 2 Paragraph 2 No. 1 GewStG a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": ") Also applicable for assessment periods before 1986"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "The activity of a company is deemed to be a commercial enterprise from the point in time at which the requirements of Section 15 (3) were met for the first time"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Insofar as tax assessments are not final or are subject to review, profits resulting from the sale or removal of assets are not taken into account in the cases of Section 15 (3) No. 2 EStG if the asset is after October 30, 1984 and before was sold or withdrawn on April 11, 1985 or if, in the case of a sale after April 10, 1985, the sale is based on a legally binding contract or an equivalent legal act concluded after October 30, 1984 and before April 11, 1985"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Sentence 3 does not apply if profits are attributable to corporations or to persons in which the participation is part of business assets or insofar as Section 17 EStG or Section 23 EStG would exist without the application of sentences 1 and 2"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Sentences 3 and 4 apply accordingly to the amounts that are deemed to be profit in accordance with Section 52 (21) sentence 4 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0069835.xml"}, "text": "Interim tariff valid for the assessment periods 1986 and 1987 for the first time for the LJA for the calendar year 1986 Clarification of the previous legal situation Clarification of the previous administrative opinion First for fiscal years ending after 31 December 1984 Plants and facilities must be completed after 30 June 1985 and before 1 1 1992 Maintenance costs for work to be used, which are concluded after June 30, 1985 and before November 1, 1988 For single stoves that are purchased after June 30, 1985 and before January 1, 1992 --- income tax / wage tax / church taxBremen income tax"}]