[{"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion K\u00f6lnS-2230 - 55 - St 113S-2230 -S-2230EStG: 4 / 1EStG: 4 / 3EStG: 6cEStG: 7 / 4EStG: 7a / 6EStG: 7bEStG: 7dEStG: 10/1 / 1aEStG: 13EStG: 13aEStG: 52 / 21EStR: 13EStR: 17EStR: 124aEStR: 125EStR: 125aEStR: 127EStR: 130EStR: 130aEStR: 135EStR: 167BewG: 22BewG: 34 / 3BewG: 36 / 2BewG: 41EStDV: 141 / 1EStDV: 82EStDV: 78EStDV: 78EStDV: 78 3AO: 150AO: 162AO: 164AO: 371AO: 378/3 Income tax assessment of farmers and foresters for the assessment period 19851 General 2 Determination of profit from agriculture and forestry according to average rates (Section 13a EStG) 21 Area of \u200b\u200bapplication 211 Re Section 13a (1) No. 2 EStG (Initial value limit) 212 On \u00a7 13a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG (Animal herd limit) 22 Determination of profit 221 Basic amount 222 Value of work 223 Rent income received224 Profits according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 8 EStG 2241 Sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals 2242 Vegetable growing (agricultural and horticultural vegetable growing) 2243 Fruit growing 2244 Asparagus growing 2245 Strawberry growing 2246 Trout pond wi uality 225 Value in use of the apartment 226 Lease interest paid, interest on debt, ongoing burdens 227 Other additions and reductions 3 Determination of profit on agriculture and forestry by comparing operating income with operating expenses (Section 4 (3) EStG) 31 Scope 32 Determination of profit 321 Average livestock values \u200b\u200b322 Value in use of Apartment 4 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry through bookkeeping (Section 4 (1) EStG) 41 Scope 42 Opening balance sheets 43 Bookkeeping 44 Determination of profit 441 Average livestock values \u200b\u200b442 Value in use of the apartment 5 Estimate of the profit for farmers and foresters whose profit cannot be determined using average rates is 51 General 52 Estimation of the profit according to standard rates 521 Starting amount 522 Lease income 523 Surcharges for profits or income not settled with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits 5231 Sales of breeding cattle and other valuable animals 5232 Abnormal livestock farming 5233 Field vegetable growing (agricultural use) 5234 Vegetable growing (horticultural use), fruit growing, asparagus and strawberry growing as well as trout pond farming 524 Usage value of the apartment 525 Wage expenses 526 Other lease expenses, debt interest, permanent charges 527 Reductions 5271 Allocation due to building depreciation in the case of profit estimates 5272 Increased deductions 5273 Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV 6 Other 61 Retirement benefits 62 Control notifications 63 Unit value notifications 64 Use of valuation files when carrying out the assessment 65 Review of Annex L 1 General The assessment orders for farmers and foresters are issued annually published in full"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "2 Determination of profit from agriculture and forestry according to average rates (Section 13a EStG) 21 Scope of application In addition to Section 127 Paragraphs 3 - 10 EStR and No. 2 of the BMF's introductory letter of 27 March 1981 (BStBl 1981 I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "282) the following is pointed out: 211 Regarding Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 2 EStG (initial value limit) The initial value determined in accordance with Section 13a Paragraph 4 EStG is decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Cattle surcharges can therefore not be taken into account as long as they have not been made the subject of a value update by the valuation body in accordance with \u00a7\u00a7 41 in conjunction with 22 para. 1 no. 1 BewG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Something else only applies if the requirements of Section 13a Paragraph 4 No. 1 Sentence 4 EStG are met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "212 On Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG (animal population limit) According to Section 127 Paragraph 7 EStR and No. 22 of the BMF's introductory letter of 27 3 1981 a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": ", is to be applied accordingly when examining the VE limits of Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG Section 124a EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The prerequisite for the elimination of the determination of the average rate of profit is that the number of VE sustainably exceeds the limits of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "For the term sustainability, reference is made to Section 135 (4) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In the case of a gradual increase in the number of animals, it therefore depends on whether the number of animals converted into VE has been above the limits of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG over the three preceding financial years"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "If this is the case, the requirements of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG are no longer met from the beginning of the fourth financial year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "If, on the other hand, the livestock are increased in one go well beyond the maximum permissible limits - e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "in connection with an expansion of the stable capacities - so that the livestock limits can also be expected in the following financial years, the requirements of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG apply from the time the maximum limits are exceeded for the first time"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The maximum number of animals permitted in accordance with Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 3 and Section 13 Paragraph 1 No. 1 EStG, converted into VE, can be found in the overview attached as Annex 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "22 Determination of profit The scheme for determining profit according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 to 8 EStG results from the form Annex ESt 2 L / 3 L (84) - Profit determination according to \u00a7 13a EStG -"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In detail, I would like to point out the following: 221 Basic amount When determining the basic amount according to Section 13a Paragraph 4 EStG, Section 130a Paragraph 3 EStR must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "222 Value of the work performance The basic amount according to \u00a7 13a Abs 4 EStG is assumed that the business is managed exclusively with paid workers (see \u00a7 36 Abs 2 BewG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The value of the work performed by the business owner and his relatives who are not employed in the company on the basis of an employment relationship to be determined in accordance with Section 13a (5) EStG must therefore be added to the basic amount (Section 13a (3) No. 2 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Section 130a, Paragraphs 4 to 6 EStR must be observed here"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In detail, the following is pointed out: When determining the value of the work performance for the physical work of the business owner and the relatives who are not employed, only the work performance is to be taken into account in the result, which is based on the area recorded in the initial value according to \u00a7 13a para 4 EStG in the individual case not applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The paid workers are to be counted towards the appropriate number of full-time workers (VAK) according to the duration of their employment (\u00a7 13a Abs 5 Nr 5 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to temporary workers employed on a short-term basis, as well as to workers who have been made available by contractors for certain ordering, maintenance or harvesting work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "For the crediting of the paid VAK"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "a breakdown of the wages is necessary, provided that it relates to the uses contained in the initial value (Section 13a Paragraph 4 EStG) and the uses not contained therein"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Make Stpfl in the tax return (form \"Annex L\") to the extent / proportion of their employment or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "the activities of other people (relatives, third parties) in the company or no or obviously incorrect information on the part of the work attributable to special uses, the (physical) work or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "the proportion of the work performed by the business owner, the relatives employed in the business and / or the remunerated workers, if applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "with the assistance of the responsible official agricultural expert (ALS)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The table in the Felsmann comment in Section C 219 on the average labor requirement for special branches of business can also serve as a guide to determine the share that is attributable to special uses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "For the value of the work performed by the owner of a part-time business, see Section 130a Paragraph 4 Sentences 7 and 8 EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "For examples of calculating the value of the work, see Annex 2 223 Received rental interest. Reference is made to Section 13a (6) sentence 2 EStG and Section 130a (7) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The rent received also includes income from ground rent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Income from hunting leases is compensated by the basic amount as it relates to areas included in the initial value"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "224 Profits according to Section 13a Paragraph 8 EStG Reference is made to Section 13a Paragraph 8 EStG and Section 130a Paragraph 8 EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In addition, please note the following: Profits from operations that were not taken into account when determining the initial value are, for example,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": ": Additional profits from sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals (see section 2241), profits from renting rooms to holiday guests and from camping sites (ESt-Kartei NW \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG A No. 82), insofar as income from land is concerned - and forestry, interest income insofar as the capital claim is attributable to the business assets, profits from riding schools and rental of own horses, insofar as it is income from agriculture and forestry, profits from secondary employment, insofar as it is income from agriculture and forestry, Profits from investments that belong to the agricultural and forestry business assets, profits from the keeping and care of retired animals, profits from the rearing of animals in the wage system, profits from the rental of living space belonging to the agricultural business assets (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Rental residential property)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Profits from the cross-company use of machines, which are achieved in the context of agriculture and forestry, are not to be recorded according to Section 13a (8) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "You have already been paid for by applying the basic amount (ESt-Kartei NW \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG A Nr 103)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The profits (additional profits) according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 8 EStG are basically to be determined by comparing the operating income and operating expenses (\u00a7 4 Paragraph 3 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "If no records are available, the profits (additional profits) are to be estimated according to the principles of Section 4 Paragraph 1 EStG (Section 130a Paragraph 8 Sentences 8 - 11 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "When estimating the profits (additional profits) from sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals, from growing vegetables and fruit, growing asparagus and strawberries and from trout pond farming, the following guidelines can serve as a guide"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Their application must not lead to an obviously incorrect taxation (see BFH judgment of 16 12 1965 BStBl 1966 III p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "193)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "2241 Sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals From the sale of breeding cattle, only extraordinary income is to be recorded as a surcharge according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 8 No. Judgment of 11/15/1984 BStBl 1985 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "156)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Extraordinary income is to be considered as exceeding the individual selling price including sales tax: Breeding bulls 4200 DMBreeding cows and cattle 3200 DMBreeding boars1100 DMBreeding sows1000 DM For breeding and riding horses the additional profit of 60%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "the amount by which the selling price exceeds the value of 7500 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "If sales proceeds of more than 16,250 DM are achieved, the full amount of 11,000 DM (7,500 + 40%) is to be recognized as additional profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "of 8,750 DM)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Wages for paid workers as well as selling costs (auction fees, insurance contributions, transport costs, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": ") are taken into account in the amount of these values, so they cannot be deducted separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The additional profit has to be calculated individually for each animal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Offsetting with sales proceeds that are below these values \u200b\u200bis not permitted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The same procedure must be followed if above-average prices are achieved for breeding animals other than those specified or for other particularly valuable animals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The underlying value in these cases results from the tax production costs of the animal species in question plus 45%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "2242 Vegetable growing (agricultural and horticultural vegetable growing) For the delimitation of agricultural and horticultural vegetable growing, see Sect. 108 Paragraph 2 and 607 Paragraph 1 No. 1 BewRL 1964 Is vegetable growing in Wj"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "1985/1986 to be attributed to agricultural use, a surcharge according to \u00a7 13a Abs 8 EStG is not possible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Vegetables are only grown in the context of agricultural use if headed cabbage (white, red and savoy cabbage), picking peas and picking beans are grown exclusively using agricultural cultivation methods as part of agricultural crop rotation as the main crop"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "On the other hand, if the types of cabbage and / or peas or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Do not alternate beans with other agricultural crops such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Wheat, rye, barley, oats or beets, but one after the other or alternately with the same or different types of vegetables (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Endive, lettuce, lamb's lettuce, spinach, carrots, celery, beetroot, onions, radishes, leeks, tomatoes, kohlrabi, cucumbers, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": ") cultivated, the cultivation is no longer part of the agricultural crop rotation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Rather, it is a vegetable cultivation that is to be assessed according to horticultural principles (vegetable cultivation division of the horticultural part of the vegetable, flower and ornamental plant cultivation)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In the case of vegetable growing (horticultural use), income fluctuates between DM 15,000 and DM 80,000 per hectare"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "You are dependent on z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "of soil quality, irrigation possibilities, under glass areas, number of harvests"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The profit can be 30 to 65 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "of revenues are estimated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The profit is influenced by the type of marketing (auction in the wholesale market, sale on the farm, sale on the weekly market) and the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In the case of vegetable growing without roofed growing areas or with roofed growing areas up to 3%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "of the total vegetable growing area, the profit can also be estimated according to the number of unpaid family workers fully employed in vegetable growing as follows: for a vegetable growing area - up to 2 ha 16,000 DM / FAK - from 2 to 4 ha 22,000 DM / FAK - over 4 ha38000 DM / FAK This estimation method is particularly suitable for cases in which the operating income has not been specified or has obviously been incomplete"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "A correct estimate in individual cases is i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "only possible in close cooperation with the ALS"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "2243 Fruit growing The income fluctuates i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "between 15,000 and 35,000 DM per hectare"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "They depend on the type of fruit, the types of fruit, the age structure of the orchard, the quality of the soil and the climate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Special natural events such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Late frosts can lead to lower income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The profit can be as high as 30 to 50 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "of revenues are estimated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "It is influenced by the type of marketing (auction in the wholesale market, sale from the farm, sale at the weekly market) and the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "No. 2242 last paragraph applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "2244 asparagus cultivation The income fluctuates i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "between 24,000 DM and 34,000 DM per hectare"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The profit can be 30 to 60 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "of revenues are estimated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "It is influenced by the type of marketing (auction in the wholesale market, sale from the farm, sale at the weekly market) and the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "No. 2242 last paragraph applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "2245 Strawberry cultivation The income fluctuates i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "between 25,000 DM and 50,000 DM per hectare and the profits between 40 and 60 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "of receipts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The amount of income and profits are influenced by the type of marketing (sale on the farm, auction or by self-pickers) and by the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "No. 2242 last paragraph applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "2246 Trout pond farming If no information is given on the income, the following framework rates can be used for the profits: Operating mode Framework rates Medium rate Labor requirement DM / qmDM / qmVAK / ha Full operations (mainly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Edible fish production (principle: 35 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "of income) 10-40 2004 Breeding farms (mostly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Brood fish production (principle: 40 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "of income) 4-401804 In individual cases, the profit can increase by up to 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "be increased or decreased"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "An increase in profit comes into consideration, in particular, if fish farming is carried out exclusively or predominantly or if table trout are largely refined into smoked trout"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "A reduction can be considered if it can be proven that losses would have to be accepted due to low water inflow and poor water quality"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The above profit rates do not yet take into account wages, rent, lease and debt interest; the costs (shares) attributable to the pond management can therefore still be deducted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "225 Value in use of the apartment The apartment i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 13a Paragraph 7 EStG includes the buildings and parts of buildings, insofar as they serve the owner of the business, the family members belonging to his household and the retirees for residential purposes (\u00a7 34 Paragraph 3 BewG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "This also applies if the right of residence of the senior citizen is secured in rem; the value in use is to be recorded in the amount of one eighteenth of the flat value specifically shown in the unit value in the income from agriculture and forestry and to be taken into account in the corresponding amount as a permanent burden in accordance with Section 10 (1) no 1983 Federal Tax Gazette 1984 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "226 Lease interest paid, interest on debt, ongoing charges Reference is made to Section 13a (3) sentence 2 EStG and Section 130a (9) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Interest subsidies from public funds reduce the deductible debt interest"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Regarding the income tax treatment of the interest reduction subsidies according to the agricultural credit program see decree of FinMin NRW of 21 3 1985 S-2230 - 75 - VB 2 announced with order of 1 4 1985 S-2230 - 62 - St 113 227 Other additions and reductions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The following can be considered: additions and deductions according to \u00a7 6c EStG, increased deductions for residential buildings according to \u00a7 7b EStG i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "V with \u00a7 52 EStDV, tax relief according to \u00a7 78 EStDV Here, the increased deductions according to \u00a7 7b EStG must be taken into account before the tax relief of \u00a7 78 EStDV"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In the case of increased deductions in accordance with Section 7b of the Income Tax Act, it should be noted that the loss clause of Section 7a (6) of the EstG a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "no longer applies for financial years beginning after December 31, 1979 (Section 52 (21) EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "However, the tax relief according to \u00a7 78 EStDV may still not lead to a loss from agriculture and forestry (see \u00a7 78 Paragraph 3 EStDV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The other increased deductions according to \u00a7 7d EstG, \u00a7\u00a7 82a, 82g, and 82i EStDV and according to the Protection Building Act cannot be taken into account when determining profits according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 to 7 EStG, because the average rates mean the depreciation and thus also the other The higher deductions that occur are generally compensated (see BFH judgment of 7 6 1984 BStBl 1984 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "663)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "However, if an asset is used in a part of the business whose full income is to be recorded in accordance with Section 13a (8) EStG, increased deductions can also be taken into account when determining the profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "3 Determination of the profit on agriculture and forestry by comparing the operating income with the operating expenses (Section 4 (3) EStG) 31 Scope of application Reference is made to Section 127 (3) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "32 Determination of profits Reference is made to section 17 EStR and the following: 321 Average livestock values \u200b\u200bThe average assessment permitted for book-keeping farmers and foresters (section 125 EStR) can, under certain conditions, also be used when determining profits in accordance with Section 4 (3) EStR in accordance with section 125a EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise reference is made to No. 441"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "322 Value in use of the apartment To determine the value in use of the apartment, reference is made to the ESt card index NW \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG A No. 100"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the value in use is to be measured according to the circumstances of the individual case, even for farmers and foresters"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "With regard to the value in use of the apartment for elderly people, the BFH judgment of July 28, 1983 (BStBl 1984 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "97) must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the value in use is to be assigned to the owner even in the case of real security and to be taken into account in the corresponding amount as a permanent burden in accordance with Section 10 (1) No. 1a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "4 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry through bookkeeping (\u00a7 4 Paragraph 1 EStG) 41 Scope of application To Section 127 Paragraph 1 EStR as well as to the BMF letter of 15 12 1981 BStbl 1981 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "878 (Appendix 5 to the income tax hand edition) is pointed out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Cattle surcharges are also to be taken into account when determining the economic value limit according to \u00a7 141 Paragraph 1 No. 3 AO if they are not or not yet the subject of a value update according to \u00a7\u00a7 41 i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "V with 22 para 1 no 1 BewG have been made"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "42 Opening balance sheets To check the opening balance sheets when transitioning to the comparison of business assets, reference is made to the order of 12 1 1984 S-2230 - 53 - St 113"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "43 Bookkeeping In Section 13 EStR and the BMF letter of 15 12 1981 a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "being point out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "44 Determination of profit 441 Average livestock values \u200b\u200bReference is made to Section 125 EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The applicable cattle average values \u200b\u200bresult from the ESt-Kartei NW \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG A No. 20 For the evaluation of horses from the 1980/81 business year, the order of 17 7 1981 - S-2132a - 1 - St 111 ESt-Kartei NRW, \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, ANr 111)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "442 Value in use of apartment no.322 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "5 Estimate of the profit for farmers and foresters whose profit cannot be determined according to average rates 51 General For farmers and foresters who are obliged to keep accounts but do not keep proper books, the profit is to be estimated in individual cases according to \u00a7 162 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to those farmers and foresters who are neither obliged to keep accounts nor meet the requirements of \u00a7 13a Paragraph 1 No. 2 and 3 EStG if they do not keep books within the meaning of \u00a7 4 Paragraph 1 EStG and also the operating income and - have not recorded expenditures within the meaning of Section 4 Paragraph 3 EStG (Section 127 Paragraph 2 - 4 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The estimate has - with the exception of the in Section 127 Paragraph 4 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "6, second half-sentence of the EStR - to be carried out in accordance with the principles of Section 4 (1) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "When making the estimate, all circumstances that are important for the estimate must be taken into account (Section 162 (1) sentence 2 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The aim of the estimate must be to determine the profit actually achieved"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The uncertainties inherent in an estimate are, however, at the expense of the taxpayer, who himself gave cause for the estimate by neglecting his tax cooperation obligations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "It must also be ensured that farmers who are required to keep accounts and whose profits are estimated are reported to the tax auditors if an examination appears to be suitable to encourage the farmer to keep accounts or if the examination promises success for other reasons"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "If a tax audit is planned in this sense, the assessment is to be carried out subject to the review (Section 164 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise, according to \u00a7 14 Paragraph 1 ALDA-FEST"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The following explanatory text must be included in the notification or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "to be attached as an attachment: \"The profit from agriculture and forestry for the financial year 19"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "was estimated according to \u00a7 162 AO because you did not declare your winnings or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "because you declared a profit that was not determined by bookkeeping, although you are obliged to keep the books"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "If you actually achieved a higher profit than the estimated, the tax would have been set too low"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In this case, there may be tax evasion or a frivolous tax reduction"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "However, you can then by declaring the actual profit under the further requirements of \u00a7\u00a7 371 378 Paragraph 3 AO criminal or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Obtain no fines"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Furthermore, I would like to point out that failure to comply with the accounting obligation can already result in a tax risk"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "\"52 Estimation of the profit according to standard rates Which estimation method is to be used in individual cases is left to the discretion of the tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "If, in individual cases, an estimation method tailored to the particular operational conditions is not to be preferred, or if there are no circumstances particularly influencing the operating result, such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Seed propagation or field vegetable cultivation exist or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "have been determined in the course of a previous tax audit and accounting results of comparable companies or empirical records are not available, the profit is to be estimated according to the principles of \u00a7 4 Paragraph 1 EStG as follows: starting amount (No. 521) + lease income (No. 522) + surcharges for Profits not paid for with the starting amount or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits (no.523) + value in use of the apartment (no.524)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Wage expenses (No. 525)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Lease expenses, interest on debt, permanent burdens (No. 526) +"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Other surcharges and reductions (No. 527) = profit for the financial year The guide rates listed below are intended as a guide for an accurate estimate of the profit (Section 127, Paragraph 2, S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "2 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "At the same time, a reduction in the estimated profit due to objections to individual points in the valuation process is generally out of the question because special circumstances in an individual branch of the business do not allow any conclusions to be drawn about the profit of the entire business"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The application of the standard rates must not lead to an obviously incorrect taxation (see BFH judgment of 16 12 1965 BStBl 1966 III p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "193)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In detail, the following should be taken into account when estimating profits according to standard rates: 521 Starting amount The starting amount per hectare of usable agricultural area for the 1985/1986 marketing year is: 1 for pasture farming (grassland share 71%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "and more of the LN) 1400 DM2 for mixed farms (grassland share 31 to 70 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "der LN) with a root crop content of a) less than 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "the LN1400 DMb) 15 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "and more of the LN1500 DMc) If the root crop content is more than 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "the LN and is in it a sugar beet content of more than 20%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "of the LN, the starting amount increases to 2100 DMd) If the root crop portion exceeds a total of 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "of the LN, are each started 5 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Additional share of root crops to be added to the above starting amounts per 200 DM3"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "der LN) with a root crop portion voa) less than 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "the LN1400 DMb) 15 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "and more of LN1700 DMc) No. 2 c) and 2 d) apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "4 In the case of dairy cow husbandry, the starting amounts (No. 1-3) are to be increased according to the average dairy herd of the farm as follows: a) less than 05 cows / ha LN200 DMb) 05 to less than 1 cows / ha LN300 DMc) 1 to less than 15 Cows / ha LN400 DMd) 15 and more cows / ha LN600 DM Only the pure agricultural production areas belong to agricultural use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Areas for buildings, courtyards, paths, ditches, field borders, water, land, quarries, sand pits, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Areas are therefore not considered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Areas for house gardens are also not included"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise, Section 124a (3) EStR applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "For the calculation of the relevant root crop, grassland or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Sugar beet share depends on the size of these shares in the respective marketing year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The areas under cultivation of root crops do not include those areas on which root crops are only grown as catch crops or as catch crops"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Only the meadows and pastures listed in No. 5232 are to be regarded as grassland; the other crops mentioned there (fodder plants) belong to field forage cultivation, the areas of which belong to the field"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "With regard to the increase in the starting amounts by a security surcharge of up to a maximum of 30% to be made in cases of repeated profit estimates from the 1983/1984 financial year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "reference is made to the order of 5 4 1983 S-2150a - 2 - St 113"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "522 Lease income Lease income, ground rent and hunting leases, reduced by proportionate operating expenses, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Property taxes are to be added to the starting amount if they are included in income from agriculture and forestry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "This is the case when the leased or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Hereditary assets belong to the lessor's agricultural and forestry business assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "523 Surcharges for winnings or winnings not settled with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits All profits from sustainable or one-off operating income that are not included in the starting amount are to be added to the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Such surcharges come z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Consideration for additional profits from sales of breeding cattle and other valuable animals, profits from abnormal animal husbandry, additional profits from special crops, profits from other special business branches (see \"Special operating income\" on p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "4 of Annex L), profits from the withdrawal and sale of land (see \"Sale / withdrawal of land\" on page 2 of Annex L)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "5231 Sales of breeding cattle and other valuable animals As additional profit from the sale of breeding cattle and other valuable animals, the amounts by which the individual sales proceeds including sales tax exceed the following values: Breeding bulls 3400 DMBreeding cows and cattle 2600 DMBreeding boars900 DMBreeding sows 800 DMThe extra profit for breeding and riding sows is DM800 with 60 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "the amount by which the selling price exceeds the value of 6000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "If sales proceeds of more than DM 13,000 are achieved, the full amount of DM 8,800 (DM 6,000 plus 40 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "of 7000 DM)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Wages for paid workers as well as selling costs (auction fees, insurance contributions, transport costs, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": ") are taken into account in the amount of the above values, so they cannot be deducted separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The additional profit has to be calculated individually for each animal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "A netting with sales proceeds that are below the above values \u200b\u200bmay not be carried out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The same procedure is to be followed if above-average prices are achieved for breeding animals other than those specified or for other valuable animals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The value to be used in these cases results from the tax production costs of the animal species in question plus an assumed profit surcharge of 20% included in the initial value for the area with normal animal husbandry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "5232 Abnormal animal husbandry Profits from animal breeding and husbandry are settled with the starting amount (No. 521), provided that the average normal animal population is not exceeded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "As animal husbandry paid for with the starting amount, for the area of \u200b\u200bthe regional finance office in Cologne, other farms for the first 20 ha LN22 VE / ha14 VE / ha for the next 10 ha LN16 VE / ha08 VE / ha for the next 20 ha LN15 VE / ha07 VE / ha over 50 ha L maximum of 90 VE50 VE The animal husbandry in VE that is covered with the starting amount can also be found in the overview attached as Annex 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Forage farms are farms where the forage area is 60 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "and more of the usable agricultural area without courtyard and building space, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "matters"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In this context, the forage area includes: Meadows (incl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Tree meadows, litter meadows), cattle pastures and fields, as well as the cultivation areas for clover in pure seed and mixed cultivation, clover grass, alfalfa, seradella, sainfoin, green corn, vetches, sweet lupins and all other forage plants"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Areas on which grain is grown for grain production are not included in the forage area even if the grain is fed to the livestock kept on the farm"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "When calculating the number of animals and converting them into livestock units, Section 124a, Paragraph 2 of the Income Tax Regulations must be used"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The average herds (lines 79 to 85 of Appendix L) and the animals produced (lines 86 to 92 of Appendix L) are to be summarized"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Care must be taken that no animals are recorded twice"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "For the excess inventory remaining after the normal inventory has been taken into account, the following is to be set as profit for the 1985/1986 financial year: as a rule, 400 DM / VE with exclusive ownership (90 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "and more) of fattening poultry 200 DM / VELeghennen300 DM / VEMfattening pigs 350 DM / VE wages are not taken into account, so they can still be deducted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "5233 Field vegetable cultivation (agricultural use) Field vegetable cultivation is understood to mean the cultivation of vegetables according to agricultural cultivation methods within the framework of agricultural crop rotation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "A distinction must be made between field vegetable cultivation in annual cultivation and field vegetable cultivation as a replica"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The additional profit not settled with the starting amount (No. 521) is to be set for the 1985/1986 marketing year: For field vegetable cultivation in annual cultivation: 7,000 DM per hectare minus the amount per hectare per hectare stated in the starting amount for this area, as a replica: 5,000 DM per hectare (without abbreviation)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "It is up to the taxpayer to provide evidence of the actual proceeds from field vegetable growing"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In these cases, a discount of 25 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "be acknowledged"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The remaining amount is only to be reduced in the case of field vegetable cultivation in annual cultivation by the amount per hectare / UI set in the starting amount for this area"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The above standard rates do not take into account wages and can therefore be deducted separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "5234 Vegetable growing (horticultural use), fruit growing, asparagus and strawberry growing as well as trout pond farming No. 2242 to 2246 apply accordingly for the determination of the profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "As a surcharge on the starting amount, however, only the additional profit, i.e."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "the profit reduced by the pro-rata starting amount applied in the individual case"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "524 Value in use of apartment no.322 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "When estimating the profit, the gross value in use must always be applied, because the expenses associated with the apartment - with the exception of interest on debt (No. 526) and the increased deductions (No. 527) - are taken into account when determining the starting amounts (No. 521) and are thus compensated are"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "525 Wage expenses The starting amount (No. 521) is based on the assumption that the business is managed exclusively with unpaid workers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Wage expenses are therefore to be deducted from the starting amount insofar as they relate to the profits settled with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The treatment of wage expenses incurred with profits or income not paid for in the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits (see No. 523) are related to the respective surcharge regulations (see No. 5231 to 5235)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "For the distribution of wage expenses required in individual cases, No. 222 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "2 and 3 apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The wage expenses to be deducted also include the expenses for temporary workers as well as for the workers who are"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Contractors have been made available for certain ordering, maintenance or harvesting work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "If wage expenses in connection with machine expenses are invoiced in one sum by contractors, there are generally no concerns that the proportionate wage expenses to be taken into account at 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "appreciate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "If wage expenses cannot be proven, an estimate e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "possible according to documents from comparable companies"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Because of the need to notify the income tax office in such cases, reference is made to No. 62 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "c) pointed out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "526 Lease expenses, interest on debt, permanent charges Such expenses can be deducted if they are operating expenses and have not already been taken into account when determining the surcharges according to No. 523"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The lease payments then attributable to the profit settled with the starting amount are not fully deductible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The lease also covers expenses that are already included in the starting amount as operating expenses (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Property tax, apportionment of the Chamber of Agriculture)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The lease payments are therefore to be reduced by the amount contained therein, which is allotted to such expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "There are no concerns about reducing this amount to 10 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "to estimate the rent payments"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In special individual cases, it may be justified to reduce the amount to 5 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "lower if excessive and no longer local rent is paid"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "527 Other surcharges and reductions 5271 Allocation due to building depreciation when estimating profit When calculating the starting amount, the deductions for wear and tear from the value of the company buildings are taken into account in accordance with Section 7 EStG, because it is assumed that the business is managed by the owner himself"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Insofar as this depreciation is due to someone other than the manager of the business, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "the lessor in the case of leasing, are to be added to the initial amount of the LN (No. 521) when estimating the profit: For buildings essentially erected before 1 1 1965: 100-- DM per hectare LN, for buildings primarily built after 31 12 1964 Buildings: 150 DM per hectare of land"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "It is up to the tenant to prove the AfA in detail"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "5272 Increased deductions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "increased deductions for residential buildings according to \u00a7 7b EStG and increased deductions according to \u00a7\u00a7 82a, 82g and 82i EStDV into consideration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "These increased deductions are, however, by the depreciation already taken into account in the starting amount according to \u00a7 7 Abs 4 EStG in the amount of 2 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "to shorten"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "5273 Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV can be deducted from the starting amount if the register is kept according to \u00a7 7a Paragraph 8 EStG (cf. order of 27 5 1981 S-2184 - 7 - St 111)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In these cases, I ask you to request the directory and to attach a copy of the income tax file"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "After the expiry of the preferential period of three financial years, the starting amount must be increased by a surcharge when claiming the preferential treatment according to \u00a7 76 EStDV, since according to \u00a7 76 Paragraph 1 Clause 2 EStDV the residual value is the assessment basis for further deductions for wear and tear and by applying the starting amount otherwise too high depreciation amounts would be taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The surcharge for a financial year results from the sum of the special depreciation granted divided by the remaining useful life of the respective asset"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The initial amount must be increased for the remaining period of use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In order to ensure that this surcharge is also taken into account in future assessments, the control sheet for profit surcharges (Section 76 EStDV), form no. 724/49, must be kept and attached to the income tax file"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "6 Miscellaneous 61 Retirement benefits 612 For non-cash retirement benefits, the following values \u200b\u200bcan be used as a basis for Vz 1985 without individual proof: For meals- for an old-age divider 2910 DM- for an elderly couple 5240 DM for heating and lighting 610 DM However, there are no concerns regarding the value for heating and lighting, applications from Taxpayers on the basis of the pro rata, based on the energy bills, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "the actual costs determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "613 If partial retirement benefits do not only consist of benefits in kind and in kind due to farm handover agreements between parents and children, it must be checked in each individual case whether the individual partial benefits are life annuities or permanent burdens (recurring payments)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Section 167 (1) no.2 letter c) EStR 1981 is based on the BFH judgment of 28 July 1983 (BStBl 1984 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "97) outdated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Due to the transitional regulation in existing retirement contracts, the decrees of FinMin NRW of 18 10 1984 26 3 1985 and 25 4 1986 - S-2221 - 109 - VB 2 are announced with orders of 26 10 1984 23 4 1985 and 13 5 1985 S-2221 - 28 - St 113 pointed out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "62 Control notifications Except in the usual cases (control notifications for the purposes of the Bp, the recording of taxable transactions with other taxpayers, inheritance tax), control notifications are to be prepared in the following cases in particular: The assessment body responsible in the individual case must be informed of the taxpayer's or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "to disclose circumstances arising from the files that may affect the level of the fixed unit values \u200b\u200b(e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Change in areas for special use, changes in animal populations - see also order of 4 10 1977 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "3122 - 4 - St 241)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Information that may be of importance for an award according to \u00a7 41 BewG is summarized on page 4 of Annex L."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "I therefore ask in all cases in which the livestock declared in Annex L obviously exceeds or exceeds the animal population customary in the area"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "in which, for other reasons, a surcharge according to \u00a7 41 BewG may be considered, the assessment body can be informed by sending a copy of page 4 of Annex L."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Are access or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Leases known, so the lessor or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Inform the leaseholder of the competent assessment office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to the transfer of use free of charge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "This can be done in accordance with No. 3 of the order of 4 2 1981 S-2230 - 46 - St 111"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "For the rest, I ask you to ensure that the taxpayers on page 2 of Annex L the address of the lessee / lessor, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "specify exactly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "In particular, cases without signal \"A\", in which wage expenses are claimed, and cases with significant wage expenses are to be reported to the responsible income tax office for examination by the income tax field audit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "This also applies if wage expenses are set at an estimated amount when determining the profit (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "No. 525 section 4)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "63 Unit value notifications Unit value notifications for agricultural and forestry assets must always be evaluated promptly, particularly because of the possible effects on the way in which the taxpayer's profit is determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "64 Consultation of the valuation files when carrying out the assessment In particular when determining profits in accordance with Section 13a of the Income Tax Act and in cases of assessment, I ask that you refer to the assessment files for the assessment and review of the values \u200b\u200bto be applied in the individual case when calculating profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "65 Review of Annex L According to Section 150 (1) and (2) AO, book-keeping farmers are also obliged to fill out tax returns, including the annexes, and thus in particular also Annex L, completely and truthfully"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "This applies in particular to the area data in lines 32 to 50 of Annex L, which are not only indispensable for the taxation of valuation farmers, but also"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "also serve to check the applicable profit determination method, to test profits and to be able to monitor value updates"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The section \"Sale / Withdrawal of Land\" contains the essential basic information required to examine profits from sales and withdrawals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "If the required information can be clearly found in the individual case from the balance sheet or similar documents, a reference in Annex L to the relevant documents is sufficient"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The information on p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "4 to the livestock is for the demarcation of the agricultural from the commercial animal breeding or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "Animal husbandry, for checking the accounting requirements and, if necessary,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "the applicable type of profit determination is important"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "I would therefore ask you to work towards ensuring that farmers and foresters who keep books also fill out Appendix L in full in future"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "If this does not happen, the system must be returned for the purpose of completion"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "It should be advisable to advise consultants who, to the knowledge of the tax office, look after farmers and foresters to a large extent, in good time before submitting their next tax returns, of the requirement to fill out Annex L in full"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "The plants were not included"}, {"meta": {"name": "0077309.xml"}, "text": "---- Criminal tax lawIncome tax / wage tax / church taxAccountingValuationProcedural law / tax codeNorth Rhine-WestphaliaAgriculture"}]