[{"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The Federal Minister of Finance IV B 6 - S-2347 - 13 / 87S-2347S-2342B / II - 445/87 - S-2347 AS-2347 - 3 - St 222III B 21 - S-2347 - 1/8732 - S-2347 - 2/2 - 53789S-2347 - 5 St 21S-2347 - 2 St 23 / 21S-2347 A - 4 - II B 21S-2342 A - 34 - St II 30S-2347 A - 5 - St II 30S-2342 - 1550 - 210054 - S-2347 - 3 / 85S-2347 - 1/87 - St 231S-2347 - 3 - 351S-2347 A - 6 / 87S-2347 -S-2342 -S-2347 | SBStBl-1987-I-0632 repealed for tax items that were realized after 31122004 by BdF IV C 6 - O-1000/07/0018 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "29 3 2007 (coordinated state decree - \"Letter to contain the flood of norms\") Bibliography of the corresponding administrative instructions in terms of content: SaarlandB / II - 445/87 - S-2347 A from 31081987OFD Saarbr\u00fccken S-2347 - 3 - St 222 from 23091987BerlinIII B 21 - S -2347 - 1/87 from 31081987StZBl-1987-1419Bayern32 - S-2347 - 2/2 - 53789 from 31081987EStK \u00a7 19a EStG card 11OFD Nuremberg S-2347 - 5 St 21 from 01101987OFD Munich S-2347 - 2 St 23/21 from 06101987HessenS-2347 A - 4 - II B 21 from 31081987 Reference: a) Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "17081984 - S-2342 A - 34 - St II 30b) LStK Part B \u00a7 19 a EStG No. 101OFD Frankfurt am Main S-2347 A - 5 - St II 30 from 08101987 Bremen S-2342 - 1550 - 2100 from 31081987 Reference: Decree of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "23071984 - S-2342 - 2100Hamburg54 - S-2347 - 3/85 of 31081987LStK \u00a7 19a EStG p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "8 No. 3OFD Hamburg S-2347 - 1/87 - St 231 from 05101987 Lower SaxonyS-2347 - 3 - 351 from 31081987LStK \u00a7 19a EStG No. 2Baden-W\u00fcrttembergS-2347 A - 6/87 from 31081987LStK part B \u00a7 19a EStG No. 102EStG: 19aFinSen BR Decree S-2342 - 1550 - 2100 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "29 2 1988 BdF IV B 6 - S-2342 - 40/84 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "23 7 1984 BStBl 1984 I 416 Zacharias / Hebig FR 1987 473 Richter Inf 1988 issue 24 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "VI Tax-privileged transfer of asset shares to employees from 1987; here: application of \u00a7 19a EStG reference: meeting with the highest tax authorities of the federal states from 23 to 26 June 1987 (LSt III / 87) section 1 personal scope section 2 definition of asset participation section 3 transfer of asset participation section 4 value of the asset participation section 5 determination of tax-free monetary benefit Section 6 Conversion of wages Section 7 Acquisition of tax-privileged investments with capital-forming benefits Section 8 Determination of securities Section 9 Obligations to record and provide certificates Section 10 Disposals during the blocking period Section 11 Obligations to notify Section 12 Subsequent taxation With reference to the result of the discussions with the The highest tax authorities of the states and with the Federal Minister for Labor and Social Affairs apply subject to the approval of the Federal Council to the ordinance adopted by the Federal Government to change the wage tax durc Regulation for the application of \u00a7 19a EStG from January 1, 1987, the following (the lines in the margin make the changes compared to the BMF letter of July 23, 1984 - IV B 6 - S-2342 - 40/84 - BStBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "416 - recognizable): Section 1 Personal scope of application \u00a7 19a EStG applies to employees who are subject to unlimited and limited income tax and who are currently employed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Therefore, the transfer of asset shares to former employees of the employer is generally not tax-privileged"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "There is only an exception if former employees still receive the free or discounted asset participation as wages for their actual work in the course of winding up their previous employment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Section 2 Definition of asset participations (1) The asset participations, the transfer of which is tax-privileged according to \u00a7 19a EStG, are finally listed in \u00a7 19a Paragraph 3 in conjunction with Paragraphs 4 to 6 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "According to this, investments in assets in the employer's company (company investments) as well as investments in assets in other companies (non-company investments) can be granted tax-deductible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Asset sharing can only be granted tax-privileged if its term does not end before the blocking period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(2) The following shares can be granted tax-deductible: shares issued by domestic or foreign employers; This also includes shares in a company that is associated with the employer's company as the controlling company (Section 18 (1) AktG), shares in domestic companies, shares in foreign companies that are either admitted to official trading on a German stock exchange or to the regulated market or are included in the regulated Regulated Unofficial Market"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(3) An income bond is a security that is made out to the bearer, name or to order and in which the payment of a certain sum of money - usually redemption at nominal value - is promised"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "It is irrelevant whether redemption is planned after the deadline, termination or return"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "It is also irrelevant whether claims for the value of money are documented in addition to claims for amounts of money; so lies z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "an income bond is also provided if redemption is agreed at the price of a corresponding share, but at least for a certain sum of money"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The prerequisite in all cases is that, in addition to a certain amount of money, interest is promised that is related to the profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The designation as interest does not matter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "In addition to the profit-related interest rate, a fixed interest rate can be promised or paid"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "a profit-independent minimum interest rate must be agreed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "In this case, an income bond can only be given tax-deductible if either the declaration required in Section 19a Paragraph 4 No. 1 EStG is available or the conditions required in Section 19a Paragraph 4 No. 2 EStG are met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The minimum interest rate within the meaning of Section 19a (4) No. 2 EStG is determined by the issue price, not the nominal value or the current price of the income bond"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(4) Convertible bonds and income bonds that are registered bonds of the employer can only be surrendered with tax relief if the employee's claims from the bond are guaranteed by a domestic credit institution at the employer's expense or are secured under private law by a domestic insurance company; a change of the surety or the insurance company during the blocking period is permitted if the new surety or the new insurance company assumes the obligations that have arisen up to now"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The lock-up period is not affected by the occurrence of the security case"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Security is not required if the employer is a domestic credit institution"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(5) A profit participation certificate is a security if it certifies a profit participation right and is made out to the holder, name or order"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "A participation certificate can in principle be issued by companies of any legal form"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Profit participation rights can be all property rights, as typically due to shareholders"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "They differ from membership rights in the lack of control and management rights"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "A profit participation certificate can only be given tax-privileged if the content of the profit participation right is the right to the profit of a company"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The promise of a profit-independent minimum or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Fixed interest is fundamentally not in line with this"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "A profit-independent minimum or fixed interest does not exist if the interest payment is dependent on sufficient profit, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "in the event of a share in the loss (see Section 10 (5) of the German Banking Act)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "A profit-independent minimum interest rate is permitted, however, if either the declaration required in Section 19a Paragraph 5 in conjunction with Paragraph 4 No. 1 EStG is available or the conditions required in Section 19a Paragraph 5 in conjunction with Paragraph 4 No. 2 EStG are met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The minimum interest rate within the meaning of Section 19a Paragraph 5 in conjunction with Paragraph 4 No. 2 EStG is determined by the issue price, not by the nominal value or the daily rate of the profit participation right"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Are other rights agreed in addition to the right to profit of a company, which can also be typical property rights of a shareholder (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Subscription rights), this does not preclude the acceptance of a profit participation right"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The tax-privileged transfer of a profit participation certificate also requires that repayment at nominal value has not been promised"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "This requirement is z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "fulfilled in the following cases: Exclusion of repayment (non-cancellability, no withdrawal of the participation certificate); Refundability in the event of termination, return or after expiry of the deadline if the repayment claim is based on the performance of a company (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "is aimed directly at a share of the liquidation proceeds or is based on the stock exchange price of a corresponding share in the company); Refundability in the event of termination, return or after the deadline if participation in the loss has been agreed; Refundability upon termination, return or after expiry of the deadline, if repayment may only be made from profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "If repayment at nominal value has been promised, it can be an income bond (Paragraph 3)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(6) A business credit with a cooperative can only be transferred if the employee is already a member of the cooperative or is accepted as a member by the cooperative"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "This is usually possible with credit unions, consumer unions, or construction and housing cooperatives"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Post, savings and loan associations are equal to credit unions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The free or discounted transfer of business assets at a cooperative to its employees is compatible with Section 22 (4) of the Cooperative Act, if the employee's member contributes to the amount of the monetary benefit from the employer's cooperative"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(7) A capital contribution or a share in a GmbH can be transferred if the articles of association, membership agreement or assignment agreement is notarized"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "A capital contribution can already be made if the GmbH articles of association have been concluded, but the company has not yet been entered in the commercial register (foundation stage)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "If the entry is not made, Section 10 Paragraph 2 No. 9 and Section 11 Paragraph 1 No. 3 and Paragraph 3 must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(8) A silent partnership can be left to any legal form in a company if the company, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "because of the type of business conducted or because of its legal form, is considered a trade"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The distinction between a silent partnership and a profit-sharing loan depends on whether the contractual partners pursue a common purpose (cf. the BFH judgment of June 21, 1983 BStBl II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "563)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The express agreement of control rights of the employee can be an indication of the pursuit of a common purpose"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "If there is no common purpose between the contractual partners, there is a participation loan (Paragraph 9)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(9) A loan claim against the employer can only be granted tax-privileged if the employee's claims from the loan claim are secured; Paragraph 4 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Loan claims against the employer also include loan claims against a domestic company which, as the controlling company, is associated with the employer's company (Section 18 (1) AktG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(10) A profit-sharing right in the employer's company, for which no profit-sharing certificate with the character of securities has been issued, can be granted tax-privileged if the conditions of paragraph 5 are met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "If repayment at nominal value has been agreed, it is a participation loan (see paragraph 9)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The profit-sharing rights in the employer's company also include profit-sharing rights in a domestic company which, as the controlling company, is associated with the employer's company (Section 18 (1) AktG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Section 3 Provision of property investments (1) Property investments can be made available to employees by the employer himself"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "It does not matter whether the employer is the legal owner of the asset participation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Asset sharing is also made available by the employer if the employee has the asset sharing by a representative of the employer, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "a credit institution"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(2) In the context of a current employment relationship, asset shares can also be transferred by a third party"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "These include"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "the cases in which the asset participations are transferred from a company that is affiliated with the employer's company in a group (Section 18 AktG), a third party for whom the employer reimburses all or part of the expenses incurred by the transfer"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "It does not matter whether the employer is involved in the transfer"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Section 4 Value of the asset participation (1) The determination of the value of asset participation within the meaning of Section 19a (3) EStG is based on Section 19a (8) EStG, regardless of whether the tax relief under Section 19a (1) EStG is used"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Disposal bans do not reduce the value"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(2) If employees receive listed asset holdings within the meaning of Section 19a Paragraph 3 No. 1 to 3 EStG no later than 9 months after the date of the resolution on the transfer, they are to be valued at the lowest stock exchange price on the day of the resolution, subject to sentence 4 (Section 19a Para 8 sentence 2 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "If a controlling company resolves in the sense of Section 18 (1) AktG to transfer such asset shares to employees of the group, the date of this resolution is decisive for the valuation; this also applies if the dependent company reproduces the transfer decision of the controlling company in its own resolution without acquiring the securities from it"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "If the dependent company acquires the securities, the day on which the resolution is passed is decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "If a listing is not available on the decisive date of the resolution, the asset participations are valued at the last rate listed in official trading within 30 days prior to this day (Section 19a (8) sentence 3 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(3) If employees receive listed asset investments within the meaning of Section 19a Paragraph 3 No. 1 to 3 EStG after 9 months from the date on which the resolution was passed, they are to be valued at the lowest stock exchange price on the day of the provision (Section 19a Para 8 sentence 5 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The day of booking out by the person providing the transfer or his / her vicarious agents is deemed to be the day of release"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(4) Investments in assets within the meaning of Section 19a Paragraph 3 No. 1 to 3 EStG, for which a price has not been determined on the date of the resolution and within thirty days before the date of the resolution, neither in the official market nor in the regulated market nor in the regulated unofficial market to apply the fair value on the day of the transfer; If a price is determined on this day, this is the common value"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "For reasons of simplicity, the value of new shares that have not yet been listed on the stock exchange but are already fully entitled to dividends can be derived from the price of the old shares on the day of the resolution"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "In the case of new shares that have not yet been listed on the stock exchange and are not yet fully entitled to dividends, a total discount of 10 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "of the stock exchange price of the old shares, no more than 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "be made from the nominal value of the share"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The calculated value applies to all new shares that are made available to the employee within nine months of the decision date"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "After 9 months, the price of the old shares on the day of transfer is to be used"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "For the evaluation within a group, paragraph 2 sentences 2 and 3 are to be applied"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(5) Whether non-securitized participations in assets within the meaning of Section 19a Paragraph 3 Nos 7 9 10 and 11 EStG are to be assessed at a higher or lower value than the nominal value due to special circumstances (Section 19a Paragraph 8 Sentence 7 EStG), depends on the principles of the sections 55 and 56 VStR to decide"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Then z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "In the case of a loan claim within the meaning of Section 19a Paragraph 3 No. 10 EStG, the valuation below the nominal value is usually justified if the claim is interest-free (Section 55 Paragraph 2 No. 1 VStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "On the other hand, z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "In the case of such a loan claim against the employer that is justified for the employee, the valuation of the nominal value is generally justified if the claim is subject to high interest and cannot be terminated by the debtor (employer) for a longer period of time (Section 55 (3) VStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "An agreement according to which the employer cannot terminate the loan claim until the expiry of the six-year blocking period is possible, but is not stipulated as a prerequisite for tax relief under Section 19a (1) sentence 2 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Section 19a (1) sentence 2 EStG only requires a contractual obligation on the part of the employee (creditor) not to dispose of the claim for his part during the blocking period, unless circumstances arise in his person that allow his early disposal according to Section 19a (2) sentence 5 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The debtor cannot terminate the loan for a longer period within the meaning of Section 55 (3) VStR if it has also been clearly agreed that the employer may not terminate the loan claim during the six-year blocking period; this does not result from an agreement corresponding to the wording of Section 19a (1) sentence 2 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(6) The average value of capital contributions or shares in a GmbH, for which no separate determination has been made (see \u00a7 3 AntbewVO), is to be determined by a fictitious share valuation according to the principles of \u00a7 11 Paragraph 2 BewG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The determination is made by the tax office responsible for the GmbH"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Capital contributions or shares in a GmbH, which did not exist at the beginning of the calendar year, are generally to be valued with the paid-in capital"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "In companies that z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "have arisen through conversion from a partnership or a sole proprietorship or within the scope of a business split from an existing company, however, the determination of the common value must be carried out by the company tax office of the GmbH according to the principles of sections 77 to 79 VStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The income percentage can be derived from the previous operating results of the partnership or sole proprietorship, whereby the effects of the changed legal form may be"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "must be taken into account by making corrections to the operating results"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(7) If a stock corporation or a partnership limited by shares grants its employees its own shares on the basis of a resolution that was passed before January 1, 1987, these shares are then also valued at the lowest stock market price on the day the resolution was passed. if the shares are transferred after December 31, 1986; the nine-month period does not apply (Section 52 (19a) EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Treasury shares are only those that certify membership rights in the employer's company"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Therefore it is z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "in the case of shares of a group parent company, not own shares of the group subsidiary (BFH judgment of 11 July 1986 BStBl 1987 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "300) with the result that if such shares are made available to employees of the group subsidiary, the stock exchange price on the day of the resolution passed before 1987 is not decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Treasury shares are also not considered if employees directly acquire new shares in the course of a capital increase that were not previously owned by the corporation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "If the corporation is the owner of the new shares, they are to be valued at the stock exchange price on the decision date prior to 1987 when they are transferred to the employees if there was a stock exchange price for the new shares on that day"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "If a stock exchange price was not available on the day of the resolution or within thirty days prior to this day, the market price on the day of the transfer is decisive; the simplification regulation of paragraph 4 sentence 2 does not apply"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Section 5 Determination of the tax-free pecuniary benefit (1) The pecuniary benefit results from the difference between the value of the asset participation (see Section 4) and the price at which the asset participation is left to the employee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The tax exemption of the pecuniary benefit is double limited, namely to half the value of the asset participation, but at most to 500 DM annually (Section 19a (1) sentence 1 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "From this it follows that the pecuniary benefit is only part of the taxable wages insofar as it exceeds half the value of the property participation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "If the monetary benefit is higher than 500 DM in the calendar year, the part of the monetary benefit exceeding 500 DM is part of the taxable wages even if half of the value of the asset participation is not exceeded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Examples: Personal contribution of the employeeValue of the participationTax-freeTaxableWith free leasing-1005050-1000500500-1200500700With discounted leasing400800400-1005002501505001000500-550110050050 (2) The maximum tax-free amount is based on the employment relationship"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Employees who are employed consecutively or next to one another in several employment relationships in a calendar year can therefore claim the tax-free maximum amount several times"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(3) If the employer bears the ancillary costs for establishing or acquiring equity interests (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Custody fees, stock exchange sales tax, notary fees, entry fees in connection with business credits at a cooperative and costs for entries in the register), the assumption of these costs is not wages"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Section 6 Conversion of wages The granting of an asset participation is not free of charge or at a reduced price if the asset participation takes the place of the wages owed in whole or in part"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Section 7 Acquisition of tax-privileged investments in assets with capital-forming benefits The purchase price of reduced-priced assets can also be paid by the employee with capital-building benefits within the meaning of 5 VermBG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The prerequisite for this is that the provisions of 5 VermBG are observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "In particular, the freedom of choice prescribed in \u00a7 12 5 VermBG must be available"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "This is not the case if the employer only allows capital-forming benefits to be invested in the form of asset participation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Section 8 Determination of Securities (1) Securities within the meaning of Section 19a Paragraph 3 No. 1 to 6 EStG are to be determined by the fact that they are kept in safe custody with the employer or with a bank in special or collective custody"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(2) The safekeeping must be identified as follows: If the securities are kept in safekeeping by the employer, the safekeeping and the blocking period must be recorded in the payroll account (see Section 9, Paragraph 1)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "If the securities are held in custody by a bank, a blocking note must be made in the custody books"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "In the case of third-party custody or collective custody, a blocking note in the customer account with the first custodian bank is sufficient"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(3) In the case of custody by a credit institution, the employee must submit a safekeeping certificate (Section 9 Paragraph 3) to the employer within three months of the acquisition of the securities in the cases of Section 3 Paragraph 1 and Paragraph 2 Clause 2"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Violation of the submission deadline leads to subsequent taxation of the tax-free pecuniary benefit (see Section 10, Paragraph 1, Sentence 2)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(4) A change of custodian within the blocking period is permitted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Paragraph 3 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Section 9 Obligations to record and provide certification (1) In the cases of Section 3 Paragraph 1 and Paragraph 2 Clause 2, the employer must note the tax-privileged transfer of asset shares in the employee's payroll account, in a collective wage account or in other records and thereby note the amount of the tax-free record any monetary benefit left as well as the beginning and end of the blocking period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "If securities within the meaning of Section 19a Paragraph 3 No. 1 to 3 EStG are transferred, the day on which the resolution on the transfer and the day of the transfer are also recorded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(2) If securities are kept in safe custody by the employer, it must be evident from the list above that they are kept in safe custody for the six-year blocking period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(3) The bank that takes securities into custody in accordance with Section 8 Paragraph 2 No. 2 must certify this to the employee (safe custody certificate)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Section 10 Disposals during the lock-up period (1) A disposal of assets within the meaning of Section 19a (3) EStG and the repeal of the determination of securities within the meaning of Section 19a (3) No. 1 to 6 EStG during the lock-up period leads to subsequent taxation of the tax-free pecuniary benefit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The same applies if the submission deadline in Section 8 Paragraph 3 (2) is not met if the employee or his or her spouse who is not permanently separated has died after receiving the share in the property or if one of them has a degree of disability greater than or equal to when 90 occurred; the employee got married after receiving the asset participation, but before the early disposal or the early cancellation of the determination and at the time of the early disposal or the early cancellation of the determination at least two years have passed since the start of the blocking period; the employee has become unemployed after receiving the asset participation and the unemployment (cf. section 44 para 4 no 3 LStR) has existed for at least one year without interruption and still exists at the time of the early disposal or the early cancellation of the determination; the employee is a citizen of Yugoslavia, the Republic of Korea, Morocco, Tunisia or Turkey and the Federal Republic of Germany incl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Has left Berlin (West) permanently after receiving the asset participation; the employee's employment relationship has been terminated after receiving the asset participation and he has taken up self-employment; the purchase price of securities lent at a reduced price has been paid in full or in part with capital-forming payments that have been invested in a savings contract for securities or other asset investments (Section 5 (1) 5 VermBG), and against the securities before the expiry of the blocking period pursuant to Section 19a (1) EStG other securities within the meaning of Section 19a Paragraph 3 No. 1 to 6 EStG are exchanged"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "This exchange is only possible if the securities are kept at the bank"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The proceeds from the sale including any price gains are to be used until the end of the following calendar month to acquire the other securities to be determined for the remainder of the blocking period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Remaining amounts do not result in subsequent taxation if they do not exceed DM 300; Amounts remaining from several sales transactions are to be added together; the employee accepts an exchange or compensation offer from a securities issuer during the blocking period; Securities are presented to the issuer for redemption after the draw or termination by the issuer before the expiry of the blocking period; the asset participation has become worthless without the involvement of the employee and therefore the blocking period is not observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Worthlessness within the meaning of Section 19a (2) sentence 4 EStG is to be assumed if the employee does not exceed 10 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "the value of the asset participation that was used to determine the pecuniary benefit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "If the amounts repaid exceed the 10-percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Limit, the subsequent taxation is only omitted if the employee sets the amounts received or other investments in assets acquired with a bank for the remainder of the blocking period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Section 11 Obligations to notify (1) The employer must notify the employee's tax office within one month that the employee has not submitted the safekeeping certificate (Section 8, Paragraph 3) or that the employee has sold securities or taken them out of custody within the blocking period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The notification can be omitted if the custodian can be proven by a certificate that the securities have been placed in safekeeping again in compliance with Section 8 Paragraphs 1 and 2, or the employee about non-securitized asset participations within the meaning of Section 19a Paragraph 3 No. 7 to 11 EStG has decreed before the expiry of the blocking period through sale, repayment, assignment or loan"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The report is to be made regardless of whether there is a harmless disposition; this is only checked by the tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(2) The credit institution that holds securities in accordance with Section 8 Paragraph 1 No. 2 must notify the employee's tax office of residence within one month that the employee has sold the securities or taken them out of custody within the blocking period; Paragraph 1 No. 2 last sentence applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The obligation to notify does not apply in the case of a harmless order in accordance with Section 10 Paragraph 2 No. 1 to 8 (3) In the case of non-company non-securitized asset participations within the meaning of Section 19a Paragraph 3 No. 7 to 9 EStG, the employee must notify his tax office of residence within one month that he is within the Has had the blocking period over the asset participation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "(4) Non-prejudicial dispositions must be proven as follows: In the event of marriage, by submitting the marriage certificate or an extract from the family register; in the event of death by presenting the death certificate or certificate of inheritance; in the event that a degree of disability of more than 90 occurs, by presenting an ID in accordance with Section 4 (5) of the Severely Disabled Persons Act; in the case of unemployment of the employee by submitting the documents specified in Section 44 Paragraph 4 No. 3 LStR; in the case of leaving the Federal Republic or Berlin (West) by submission z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "the certificate from an embassy or consulate of the Federal Republic of Germany; in the case of taking up self-employment by submitting documents about the termination of the employment relationship and notification to the municipality in accordance with Section 138 (1) AO; in the cases of Section 10 Paragraph 2 No. 7 to 9 by submitting suitable documents"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "Section 12 Subsequent taxation The following applies to the subsequent taxation of tax-free pecuniary benefits when transferring assets: Based on the notification, unless there is a non-injurious disposition, the employee has to pay wage tax of 20%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "to collect the post-taxable pecuniary benefit through tax assessment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The subsequent taxation with the tax rate of 20 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "does not apply if the amount to be subsequently charged does not exceed DM 20"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "In the case of the annual income tax adjustment and the assessment of income tax, the benefit taxed after no.1 or the tax-free benefit that remains taxable is part of the wages for the calendar year in which the harmful disposal falls"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "A wage tax determined in accordance with number 1 is to be offset"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "The employer or the bank are only liable for the wage tax to be claimed if the notification obligations (Section 11) have been violated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0079736.xml"}, "text": "--- Income taxIncome tax / income tax / church taxSaarlandBerlinBayernHesseBremenHamburgLower SaxonyBaden-W\u00fcrttembergFederal republic"}]