[{"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The Federal Minister of Finance IV B 7 - S-1901 - 392 / 88S-1900O-1008S-2000S-1900 - 51 - St 115 / O-1008 - 8 - St 612S-2000 - 31 / St 21S-1901S-1900 - 51 - St 115 / O-1008 - 8 - St 612S-1900 -O-1008 -S-2000 -S-1901 -O-1008-Repealed for tax items that were realized after 31122004 by BdF IV C 6 - O- 1000/07/0018 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "29 3 2007 (coordinated state decree - \"Letter to contain the flood of norms\") Bibliography of the relevant administrative instructions: NWOFD Cologne S-1900 - 51 - St 115 / O-1008 - 8 - St 612 of 25/08 / 88BYOFD Nuremberg S-2000 - 31 / St 21 from 19/09 / 88OFD Munich S-2000 - 9/6 St 212 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "12 10 1988 Felix BB 1988 2011 (on Art"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "15 StRefG 1990) Tax Reform Act 1990: here: Compilation of the changes in the Tax Reform Act 1990 I am sending you a compilation of the changes in the Tax Reform Act 1990 that are significant for the tax administration with a brief reproduction of the content"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Changes that are of a purely editorial nature or contain adaptations to other changed regulations are only mentioned if this appears appropriate for better understanding"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The compilation can m"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Provide a quick overview of the legal changes and should therefore also be suitable for forwarding to the regional tax offices and tax offices"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Changes to the Income Tax Act (Article 1 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) 1 Tax liability The 1986 Tax Adjustment Act of 19 12 1985 (BGBl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "2436, Federal Tax Gazette I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "735) with effect from VZ 1981 amended provision of Section 1 Paragraph 2 EStG is to be applied retrospectively from VZ 1975 (Section 52 Paragraph 2 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "2 Negative foreign income The benefits of the Foreign Investment Act (AIG) will - with the following exception - be canceled from the assessment period 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The possibility of offsetting losses from foreign permanent establishments previously contained in Section 2 AIG is retained through adoption in Section 2a Paragraph 3 and 4 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "3 Tax-free income The tax exemption for service and prospective salaries that are paid as maternity allowance for the period of maternity leave (\u00a7 3 No. 1 letter d EStG) is deleted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "From VZ 1990, the tax exemption according to \u00a7 3 No. 11 EStG is made dependent on the fact that the recipient is not obliged to provide a certain economic or artistic consideration or to an employee activity with the payments (so far \u00a7 3 No. 44 letter b EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The amendment to Section 3 No. 13 EStG creates an express legal basis for the tax exemption of the separation allowances that have already been treated as tax-free"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The tax exemption of marriage and childbirth grants according to Section 3 No. 15 EStG is now set at DM 700"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Section 3 No. 16 EStG now finally regulates which income-related expenses the employer can reimburse the employee outside the public service without tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The reimbursement of other income-related expenses by the employer is no longer tax-free in future"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The compensation that was previously exempt from tax under the Federal Disease Act for reasons of equity is now expressly exempt from tax under Section 3 No. 25 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Tip exemption (\u00a7 3 No. 51 EStG), is increased from 1200 to 2400 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The provision of Section 3 No. 63 EStG, which was changed with effect from VZ 1989, is intended to ensure that certain income in Germany only remains tax-free if it is actually used in the GDR for income tax or a tax equivalent to income tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The tax exemption according to \u00a7 3 No. 68 EStG for certain interest savings and interest subsidies by the employer is abolished from 1989; Interest savings and interest subsidies from loans received before 1989 remain tax-free for a further 12 years up to the calendar year 2000 (see Section 52 (2c) EStG), but only if the benefits do not exceed those granted in the calendar year 1988"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "4 Tax exemption for certain wage supplements From 1990 onwards, with regard to the extent of the tax exemption for wage supplements, there is no longer any distinction between whether and to what extent wage supplements are regulated by law or stipulated in collective agreements or not"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Section 3b EStG therefore provides for a uniform tax treatment of wage supplements"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Paragraph 3 contains a special regulation for those employees who spend more than 50 percent of the time in the wage payment period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Do night work and have started night work before 000 o'clock"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "For these, the surcharge increases to 40 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In addition, the preferential Sunday and public holiday work for these employees is extended to 400 a.m."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Furthermore, a transitional regulation has been created in Section 52 (3) EStG, which is intended to prevent future taxation of statutory or collective bargaining supplements for Sunday, public holiday and night work leading to net wage losses at the time of their taxation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "5 Regulations for determining profits From the assessment period 1990 onwards, according to Section 4 (5) No. 2 EStG, entertainment costs for business reasons may only amount to 80%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "reasonable and documented expenses are deducted as operating expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "If employees of the taxpayer take part in the entertainment, the deduction is to 80%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "limited"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Only the costs of the pure employee entertainment (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "at company parties) are fully deductible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The official form previously required for proof is no longer required; written information is sufficient"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The innkeeper\u2019s signature on the restaurant\u2019s bill is also no longer required"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The already applicable limit of 140 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "the highest daily allowance amounts of the Federal Travel Expenses Act, up to which additional meal expenses may be deducted, is determined in \u00a7 4 (5) No. 5 EStG itself; \u00a7\u00a7 8 8a EStDV are thus dispensable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "From the assessment period 1990 onwards, according to the new number 8a of Section 4 (5) EStG, interest on evaded business taxes (Section 235 of the Tax Code) may no longer be deducted as business expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Regarding the deductibility of the other interest on tax claims, reference is made to the statements on Section 10 (1) No. 5 and Section 12 (3) EStG and the amendments to the Corporate Income Tax Act (to Section 10 No. 2 KStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Anniversary provisions that were formed in balance sheets up to December 30, 1988 or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "are still formed, must be dissolved in accordance with Section 5 (4), Section 52 (6) EStG on the following three balance sheet dates by at least one third increasing the profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "On balance sheet dates from December 31, 1988 to December 31, 1992 inclusive, anniversary provisions may not be formed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "According to this, provisions may only be set up for entitlements arising from January 1, 1993 if the employment relationship has existed for at least 10 years, the service anniversary requires an employment relationship of at least 15 years and the commitment is made in writing"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "From the assessment period 1990 onwards, the taxpayer who determines his profit in accordance with \u00a7 5 EStG can, in addition to the previously permitted valuation methods for inventory assets, also use the so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Apply Lifo assessment procedure (Section 6 Paragraph 1 No. 2a, Section 51 Paragraph 1 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "z EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This valuation method assumes that the most recently purchased or manufactured assets are first resold or consumed (last in-first out)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The prerequisite is that the goods are of the same type, the commercial law principles of proper bookkeeping are not violated, the trade balance is proceeded accordingly and the discounted import goods discount is not used"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "A change to another valuation method is only possible with the consent of the tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "As a result of the general introduction of the Lifo valuation of inventories for fiscal years ending in the assessment period 1990, the previously existing special regulation, which provided for the Lifo method for certain precious metals and copper, can be lifted from this point in time"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Due to the limitation of the price increase reserve and the halving of the import goods discount, reference is made to the statements on Section 51 (1) No. 2 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In the event of the sale of certain fixed assets (\u00a7\u00a7 6b, 6c EStG), the profit from the sale can in future also be transferred to assets that were acquired or manufactured in the financial year prior to the sale (\u00a7 6b (1) sentence 1 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The capital gain can be transferred: at 100%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "in the case of the sale of land, buildings and growth on or facilities in the land, at 50%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "in the case of the sale of wear-and-tear movable assets with a normal useful life of at least 25 years, of ships, of shares in corporations and of living inventory of agricultural and forestry operations in connection with a business conversion"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "There is no possibility of transferring shares in corporations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The changes apply to sales after December 31, 1989 (Section 52 (9) EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "6 Provisions for determining the excess of income over income-related expenses a) Employee discounts and other pecuniary benefits From 1990, a fundamental revision of the tax treatment of employee discounts and corresponding pecuniary benefits, which are basically to be recorded as wages, comes into force"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "When assessing the price advantage, the usual market price is no longer used, but the final price actually demanded by the employer himself in general business transactions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In cases in which the employer does not offer his goods to third-party end consumers, the final price that is charged by the retailer closest to the employer is decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "A price reduction of 4% is made from this final price"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "performed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In order to keep the administrative expenses within reasonable limits, the price advantages are only taxed if they exceed DM 2,400"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This regulation is limited to goods and services that are manufactured, sold or provided in the employer's company"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "It does not apply to employees of group companies"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In addition, the goods may not be manufactured, sold or provided primarily for the needs of the employer's employees"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This means that z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The discount allowance of DM 2,400 cannot be taken into account for canteen meals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Deputates, such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "house drinks and free tobacco, on the other hand, are subject to the discount scheme"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The discount allowance applies to each individual employment relationship"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In the case of several employment relationships that are entered into at the same time next to one another or one after the other over the course of a calendar year, the discount allowance can be granted multiple times"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The previously existing option of taxing pecuniary benefits from the free or discounted sale of goods and services in accordance with Section 40 EStG will not be affected by the new regulation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In these cases, the unreduced customary final price, an official value in kind or an officially fixed average value for taxation is used; the pecuniary benefits are not reduced by the discount allowance"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b) Mileage flat rate and deductible expenses for work equipment As of 1989, the kilometer flat rate according to \u00a7 9 EStG for journeys between home and work place when using a car is increased to DM 043 and when using a motorcycle or scooter to DM 019 (\u00a7 52 para 13 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "From 1990 the lump-sum kilometer amount was DM 050 when using a car and DM 022 when using a motorcycle or scooter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In addition, it is made clear that even the use of a leased car is only subject to the kilometer flat rate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In the case of several apartments, trips to the more distant apartment - if there is no double housekeeping - are only recognized as journeys between home and work place if the more distant apartment is not only used occasionally and is considered to be the focus of the employee's life interests"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "So then z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Flights by a foreign employee to his home country are no longer taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The kilometer lump sum applies from 1990 even if additional trips are required on working days outside of regular working hours"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In Section 9 Paragraph 1 No. 6 EStG, the application of Section 6 Paragraph 2 EStG to work equipment, which was previously essentially permitted by Section 30 Paragraph 3 LStR for reasons of simplification, is anchored in law"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "At the same time, it is made clear that when determining the deductible expenses for work equipment, the provisions on the deduction for wear and tear and reduction in substance mentioned in Section 9 No. 7 EStG must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The other changes to \u00a7 9 EStG are of an editorial nature"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "c) New flat-rate employee amount \u00a7 9a No. 1 EStG brings the new flat-rate employee amount of DM 2000"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Employees whose income-related expenses exceed the lump sum can claim these for tax purposes as before"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "As before, the deduction of the employee lump sum must not lead to negative income from non-self-employed work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "7 Special expenses a) Regulations of Section 10 EStG sentence 3 of Section 10 (1) No. 1 EStG, which contains an unnecessary clarification on real splitting, is repealed to avoid misunderstandings (see Section 32 (6) last sentence EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "According to Section 10 Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG, from VZ 1990 onwards, contributions made to building societies to obtain building loans can only be deducted half as special expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The limitation of the special expenses deduction from building loan contributions to one and a half times is lifted from VZ 1988"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In Section 10 Paragraph 1 No. 5 EStG, the deduction of special expenses from certain burden equalization charges according to Section 211 Paragraph 1 No. 1 and 2 LAG from VZ 1990 is replaced by the corresponding deduction of interest on back tax claims (Section 233a AO), deferral and suspension interest (Section 234 237 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Reference to the amendment to Section 12 No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The equation contained in \u00a7 10 Paragraph 1 No. 7 Sentence 4 EStG of expenses for domestic training or further education for personal use with expenses of the taxpayer for his vocational training or further training in a non-exercised profession according to \u00a7 10 Paragraph 1 No. 7 Sentence 1 EStG deleted from 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Job-related expenses e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "for training as a housekeeper or to refresh the knowledge of a housekeeper who does not practice her profession can still be deducted in accordance with Section 10 Paragraph 1 No. 7 Clause 1 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In Section 10 (2) EStG - introductory sentence - the word \"contributions\" has been replaced by the word \"amounts\" with the aim of making it clear that expenses only belong to the pension expenses to the extent that they are special expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The ban on borrowing in accordance with Section 10 (2) No. 1 EStG is lifted from VZ 1988"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The amendment to Section 10 Paragraph 2 No. 3 - new - EStG is an editorial adjustment to an amendment to 5 VermBG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Section 10 (3) EStG contains the following changes, which will take effect from 1990: Introduction of the legal definitions \"basic maximum amount\", \"advance deduction\" and \"half maximum amount\"; Increase in advance deduction to DM 4000/8000 (single / married); Final list of the reduction cases in which the taxpayer is relieved of his retirement provision and - contrary to the applicable law - of his health insurance through tax-free benefits from third parties; the reduction takes place in a flat-rate procedure in which the reduction amount is calculated on the basis of a uniform assessment basis with different percentages due to the relief of old-age and health care"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The retirement pension reduction rate is 9 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": ", which in health care to 3 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "has been fixed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "If there are several cases of reduction in parallel, the sum of the wages, the income according to \u00a7 22 No. 4 EStG and the profit is the assessment basis for the reduction"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "If the taxpayer receives relief for both retirement and health care, the advance deduction is 12%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "to reduce the relevant assessment base"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The prohibition of cumulation according to \u00a7 10 Abs 5 EStG has been lifted from VZ 1990; In the end, however, it remains guaranteed by the right to vote according to Section 10 (4) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b) Special expenses lump sum, pension lump sum In \u00a7 10c (1) EStG, the special expenses lump sum has been reduced to 108/216 DM (single / married persons) from AP 1990; higher expenses acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 10 Paragraph 1 No. 1 1a, 4 to 7 and \u00a7 10b EStG can be considered as special expenses upon proof"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The flat-rate pension amount of DM 300/600 is canceled"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "From 1990, the general flat-rate pension is expanded to include the advance deduction for special expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This increases the flat rate pension for employees subject to social insurance in the lower and middle wage ranges"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "c) Deduction of losses In Section 10d of the Income Tax Act, the time limit on loss carryforwards is lifted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This applies for the first time to unbalanced losses that arose in VZ 1985"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Remaining losses are to be determined separately from VZ 1990 through notices"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "8 Non-deductible expenses In \u00a7 12 No. 3 EStG it is made clear that the prohibition of deducting taxes from income and other personal taxes as well as sales tax for personal consumption and for supplies or other services that are withdrawn, also for ancillary services within the meaning of \u00a7 3 Paragraph 3 AO applies, which are attributable to these taxes, with the exception of interest on back tax claims (\u00a7 233a AO), deferral and suspension interest (\u00a7\u00a7 234 237 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Reference to Section 10 Paragraph 1 No. 5 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "9 Changes to the individual types of income a) Discounts for severance payments to heirs who are giving up and for debt repayment in agriculture and forestry In paragraphs 4 and 5 of Section 14a of the Income Tax Act, sliding regulations are introduced which, if the relevant income limits are exceeded, result in a gradual reduction in the tax exemptions Compensation for heirs and debt repayment lead"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The new regulations apply to sales and withdrawals from 1986 onwards"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In addition, the exemption for debt repayment under paragraph 5 will be extended by four years until the end of 1992"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b) Freelance work The tax exemption for freelance professions according to Section 18 (4) EStG will be abolished from 1990 onwards"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "c) Employed work The repeal of paragraphs 3 to 5 of Section 19 EStG is due to the elimination of the Christmas exemption of DM 600 and the employee exemption of DM 480, which are included in the new flat-rate employee amount of DM 2000 according to Section 9a EStG rise up"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "d) Transfer of asset shares to employees Profit bonds and profit participation certificates of the credit institutions are only beneficiary from 1990 if the credit institution transfers them to its own employees (\u00a7 19a EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "e) Income from capital assets The amendment to Section 20 (1) No. 1 EStG makes it clear that hidden profit distributions also belong to the other remuneration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "As of 1989, the amendment to Section 20 (1) No. 6 EStG limits the tax exemption of income from insurance policies with a term of at least twelve years to interest of 35%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "(so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "accounting interest)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In the case of insurance policies with a term of less than twelve years, the calculated interest is subject to income tax as before"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "All other income is also taxable regardless of the term of the insurance"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The tax inflow is already assumed, even without actual payment, if the insurance contract is credited with extra interest"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Section 20 (1) no.4 EStG makes it clear that the difference between the purchase price and the redemption amount in the case of compounded and discounted securities and claims (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "From an economic point of view, it has the character of interest and thus belongs to the income from capital assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "f) Age relief amount In Section 24a of the Income Tax Act, the maximum limit for the age relief amount is raised from 3000 DM to 3720 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This means that the retirement allowance will no longer apply to recipients of retirement income who do not receive pension payments (Section 19 (2), Section 22, No. 4, lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b EStG) or income from life annuities (Section 22 No. 1 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "a EStG), balanced"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "(Applies from 1990) 10 Assessment regulations In the case of separate assessments of spouses, from 1990 onwards, according to Section 26a (2) of the Income Tax Act, special expenses are only deducted from the assessment of the spouse who paid them, waiving a joint determination"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The flat rate taxation according to \u00a7 31 EStG will be abolished from 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "11 Tariff regulations a) Child allowance The child allowance (Section 32 (6) EStG) will be increased from 1990 to DM 3024 from DM 2,484"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In the case of children of parents who are not married to one another or of spouses living permanently apart, one parent can have the child allowance transferred to the other parent if the latter does not essentially (previously: not or only to an insignificant part) meet his or her maintenance obligations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b) Household allowance The household allowance (Section 32 (7) EStG) will be increased from 1990 onwards, like the basic allowance, from DM 4752 to DM 5616"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In addition, its use is made dependent on the child to be taken into account being registered in the home of the single parent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "So far, the assignment of the child has been sufficient"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Children of unmarried parents or spouses who are permanently separated and who are registered with both parents are allocated to the parent in whose apartment they were first registered in the calendar year for the household allowance"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "If none of the parents has priority, they are to be assigned to the mother or, with her consent, to the father; consent cannot be revoked"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "c) Retirement allowance The retirement allowance (Section 32 (8) EStG) will be abolished from 1990; but see also \u00a7 24a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "d) Income tax rate In the provision of \u00a7 32a EStG on the income tax rate, the basic tax-free amount is increased from DM 4,752 / DM 9504 to DM 5616 / DM 11232 (single / married persons) with effect from 1990, the tax rate in the lower proportional zone of 22%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "on 19 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "lowered, a linearly rising marginal tax burden introduced, the top tax rate of 56 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "on 53 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "degraded; it applies to parts of the taxable income over DM 120,000 / DM 240000"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "e) Progression reservation As of 1990, the catalog of tax-free wage replacement benefits that are subject to the progression reservation has been considerably expanded in Section 32b (1) No. 1 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "All wage replacement benefits are now only recorded with their benefit amounts; the previous extrapolation to a gross amount is not applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "As before, the new employee lump sum of DM 2000 will be deducted from the wage replacement benefits, provided that it has not had an impact on income from employment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The providers of social benefits are obliged to issue the beneficiaries with certificates of the wage replacement benefits for submission to the tax office and obliged to inform the recipient of the benefits - similar to the so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Withholding tax - to point out the obligation to declare"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The progression proviso is no longer applied in the annual income tax adjustment, but only in the assessment procedure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "f) Extraordinary burden In Section 33a (1) of the Income Tax Act, the maximum amounts for the deduction of maintenance expenses will be increased from 1990 DM 4500 to 5400 DM and from 2484 DM to 3024 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The group of people for whom maintenance expenses can be deducted up to the maximum amount of the child tax allowance will be expanded to include children, for whom the taxpayer can in future also receive a training allowance under Section 33a (2) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The tax exemption (Section 33a (1a) of the EStG) for maintaining the parent-child relationship, which parents who are responsible for cash maintenance receive, will be abolished in 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Training allowances (Section 33a (2) EStG) can also be used for children abroad who have not yet reached the age of 27 at the beginning of the calendar year, in addition to the tax reduction under Section 33a (1) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to children whose completion of vocational training has been delayed beyond the age of 27 due to the completion of basic military service or community service, up to their 29th birthday"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "For the crediting of own income and remuneration of the above-mentioned children, in addition to the amount that is not subject to credit under Section 33a (1) of the Income Tax Act, no further crediting amount can be claimed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The new regulation applies with regard to children abroad from 1988 and with regard to children whose completion of vocational training has been delayed due to basic military service / alternative service from 1990. In Section 33a (3) EStG, the maximum amount for taking into account expenses incurred by a taxpayer through employment help in the household because of a helpless person or comparable expenses due to placement in a home, increased to 1,800 DM from full-time 1990 onwards"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "According to the new sentence 3 of Section 33a (4) EStG, training grants that are received for part of the calendar year only reduce the pro-rata maximum amounts and training allowances for the calendar months for which the grants are intended"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Section 33b EStG is essentially editorially adapted to the changes to the terms in the Disabled Persons Act (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Handicapped instead of physically handicapped)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "g) Tax rates for extraordinary income In Section 33b (6) - new - of the Income Tax Act (EStG), a flat-rate care allowance of DM 1800 from VZ 1990 has been introduced for taxpayers who are exposed to extraordinary burdens from caring for a helpless person"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "For extraordinary income within the meaning of Section 34 (2) EStG, the tariff reduction in Section 34 (1) EStG with half the average tax rate as of 1990 is no longer granted without restrictions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "To this extent, it can still be considered as a base discount for extraordinary income of up to DM 2 million"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Another partial amount of up to DM 3 million is subject to a two-thirds average tax rate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Extraordinary income in excess of DM 5 million is no longer eligible for collective bargaining"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Income that represents remuneration for a multi-year activity, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Wage back payments are added to the remaining income with one third for the purposes of tax calculation, the income tax attributable to this third is tripled and this tripled income tax is added to the income tax calculated without including the extraordinary income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The new regulations are applicable for the first time from 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The addition to Paragraph 3 No. 1 of \u00a7 34b EStG ensures that the restriction of \u00a7 34 EStG does not affect the tax relief under \u00a7 34b EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "There is no application requirement for the application of the provision"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Both changes apply from 1990. 12 Tax reductions In relation to Section 34c (4) EStG Foreign income from the operation of merchant ships in international traffic is, as before, subject to half the average tax rate without restriction"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The discount is also applicable to the foreign parts of the profits from the sale of commercial ships operated in international traffic"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The tariff reduction in accordance with Section 34, Paragraph 1 of the Income Tax Act applies to the portion of such capital gains that is deemed to be made domestically"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The amendment to \u00a7 34f EStG means that the so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Building child benefit raised from DM 600 to DM 750 as a tax reduction, all other things being equal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "13 Tax collection Section 36 (2) No. 2 EStG regulates the proportionate taxation and offsetting of capital gains tax when selling fixed-income securities"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Without taking into account the capital gains tax to be withheld at the time of interest payment, 10 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "credit the accrued interest received as capital gains tax, taking into account any accrued interest paid"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "14 Income tax deduction a) Income tax tables In tax brackets V and VI, the marginal tax burden is set at 53 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "limited (\u00a7 38c EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b) Income tax card (\u00a7 39 EStG) a) There is no need to enter the number of children on the income tax card, this does not apply to Berlin"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b) In future, the full child allowance of DM 3024 can also be entered on the income tax card if the other parent has been living abroad for years, with maintenance payments from the other parent e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "long-term unemployment is unlikely, the other parent is civilly released from his or her maintenance obligation or the other parent has irrevocably consented to the transfer"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "If in these cases the child tax allowance of DM 1,512 has already been entered on the income tax card of the other parent, this should not change"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Both the parent benefiting from the registration and the other parent affected by the transfer of the child allowance are assessed for income tax after the end of the calendar year (Section 46 Paragraph 2 No. 4a EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "c) Exemptions for wage tax deduction (\u00a7 39a EStG) From 1990 the entry of the retirement allowance on the wage tax card no longer applies"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In addition, the tax reduction for each child increases from DM 2,400 to DM 3,000 in accordance with Section 34f of the Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "However, this only applies if the beneficiary property was manufactured or purchased after December 31, 1989"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "For privileged objects manufactured or purchased before January 1, 1990, the tax reduction is still DM 2,400 (Section 52 (26) EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "For the entry of an exemption amount on the income tax card, the application limit in the field of income-related expenses is based only on the part of the income-related expenses that exceeds DM 2000, in line with the new flat-rate employee amount from 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise, however, the application limit is reduced to DM 1200"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This means that income-related expenses alone can only lead to an exemption if they total more than DM 3200"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Special expenses and extraordinary expenses can be taken into account individually if they total more than DM 1200"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Are z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Special expenses and extraordinary burdens together only 1000 DM, so income-related expenses of more than 2200 DM must be proven if an exemption is to be entered on the income tax card"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "d) Implementation of the wage tax deduction Most of the changes (\u00a7 39b EStG) are editorial follow-up changes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In deviation from Section 34 (1) of the Income Tax Act, the full tax is levied on compensation over DM 2 million"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The changes to \u00a7\u00a7 39c and 39d EStG are mainly of an editorial nature"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "d) Flat-rate wage tax In Section 40 of the Income Tax Act, the flat-rate limit of DM 1,000 per year for flat-rate wage tax with a company-specific flat rate tax rate is increased to DM 2,000"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The wage tax flat rate (25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": ") in the case of reduced or free meals is expressly permitted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In addition, in the cases of Section 40 (2) EStG, the flat-rate wage tax is no longer dependent on the approval of the tax office; nor does it have to be a large number of cases"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In Section 40a of the Income Tax Act, the daily wage limit for short-term employment is set to DM 120 and the flat rate tax rate to 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "raised"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "For employment on a small scale and for low wages, a flat tax rate of 15% applies from 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In addition, the limits on the duration of employment and wages applicable to the flat-rate wage tax for part-time employees are related to the wage payment period; In addition to the weekly limits, monthly limits are determined that are derived from the weekly limits"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In addition, the hourly wage limit will be increased from DM 12 to DM 18"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "For temporary workers in agriculture and forestry companies, the flat rate tax increases from 2 to 3 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The future security allowance regulated in Section 2 (3) No. 2 LStDV no longer applies from 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Instead, in Section 40b of the Income Tax Act, the flat-rate limit of DM 2,400, up to which contributions and grants may be taxed at a flat rate, is increased to DM 3,000"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Likewise, from 1990 the flat rate wage tax for certain future security benefits of 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "on 15 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "elevated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "e) Income tax deduction and annual income tax adjustment The record-keeping obligations that previously existed in accordance with \u00a7\u00a7 41 41b EStG are extended to include the subsidy for maternity benefit under the Maternity Protection Act and compensation under the Federal Disease Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "However, only the benefits actually paid need to be recorded by the employer"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "By entering the capital letter U in the wages account, the employer must note the cases in which the employment relationship continues, but the employee is not entitled to wages"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The employer is not obliged to write out pay slips for his employees in certain cases"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Pay slips must be written out for the last time for the 1987 calendar year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The changes to \u00a7 41c EStG are based on the abolition of the payslip procedure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In the case of other payments that represent remuneration for an activity that extends over several years, an annual income tax adjustment can be carried out in accordance with Section 42 (4) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The application of the progression proviso in the annual income tax adjustment is no longer possible in future; such cases will be assessed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The changes to \u00a7\u00a7 42a, 42b EStG are mainly of an editorial nature"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The tax relief for employee inventions expires at the end of 1988"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The local responsibility of the tax office for annual income tax adjustment will in future be based on the provisions of the tax code (\u00a7 42c EStG); the previous rules of jurisdiction apply for the last time to the 1987 calendar year. Paragraph 2 No. 2 of Section 42d of the Income Tax Act concerns a revision of the wording of the law"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The exclusion of liability already regulated in \u00a7 10 Paragraph 3 LStDV is incorporated into the law"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The institute of recognition, according to which a wage tax liability notice does not need to be issued if the employer recognizes the obligation to pay, is extended to the additional demand for flat-rate wage tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "15 Investment income tax a) Investment income with tax deduction The provision of \u00a7 43 EStG regulates a core area of \u200b\u200bthe new investment income tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "It determines what interest from capital claims of any kind, z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "from deposits and bonds - apart from income from life insurance policies and from unit certificates in investment funds, for which there are separate regulations - from 1989 the tax deduction from capital income in the amount of 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "subject"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Since the creditors and debtors of the investment income are generally not known for the capital claims referred to in Section 43 (1) No. 8 (a) EStG, these capital income are in all cases subject to tax deduction by the domestic debtor (issuer)."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Interest from simple loan claims (Section 43 (1) (b) EStG) is generally only subject to tax deduction if the debtor is a domestic credit institution"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Domestic branches of foreign credit institutions are treated the same as domestic credit institutions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In the following five cases, however, no tax is to be withheld: 1 for capital income from credit transactions where the creditor is also a domestic credit institution (interbank business), 2 for interest from savings deposits with a statutory notice period without any additional agreement, 3 for interest from current accounts, if the Credit with a maximum of 05%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "interest is paid, 4 for interest from a building society loan agreement, if the taxpayer has been granted a home construction premium or an employee savings allowance - regardless of the year - for expenses to the building society, 5 for investment income up to a maximum of ten German marks credited only once per calendar year (De minimis rule)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Section 43 (1) no.8 letter c EStG regulates the exception to the principle that the debtor of the investment income must be a domestic credit institution"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "After that, other debtors, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "all other companies and legal entities under public law to deduct the tax if the creditor of the investment income has its seat, management, domicile or habitual residence abroad"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Domestic branches of foreign credit institutions are deemed to be domestic creditors"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Only domestic investment income is subject to capital gains tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Therefore, no tax is to be deducted from interest on foreign bonds, since in these cases the debtor (issuer) has residence, management or headquarters abroad (Section 43 (3) EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b) Capital gains tax for life insurances \u00a7 43a Abs 1 Nr 2 EStG regulates the tax deduction in the amount of 10 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "for insurance income that is subject to income tax as of 1989 due to the amendment to Section 20 (1) No. 6 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The tax deduction of 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "With the exception of interest and the income paid out during the term of the insurance contract, all income from insurance policies with a term of at least 12 years is subject"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In addition, the capital gains tax deduction of 25 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "exist for previously taxable income from insurance policies with a term of less than twelve years"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Insurance for which a term of at least twelve years was agreed, but which, due to early surrender, only reaches a term of less than twelve years, is treated like insurance for which a term of less than twelve years was intended from the outset"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In these cases, however, in order to postpone taxation of the 10% tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In order to avoid taxed income, insurance policies with a term of less than twelve years still apply a tax deduction of just 10% from the outset"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": ", so that at the end of such a contract a possible final profit share and the accounting interest add to the capital gains tax deduction of 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "subject"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "c) Refrain from withholding tax The possibility of refraining from tax deduction on income from life insurance will be eliminated from 1989 (Section 44a EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In return, the taxpayer has a right to reimbursement in accordance with Section 44b (1) EStG or an assessment option (Section 45b EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In contrast, in cases in which they are themselves debtors of investment income, the credit institutions can refrain from withholding tax on investment income upon submission of a so-called NV certificate or a corresponding certificate from a tax-exempt or limited taxable corporation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "d) Reimbursement of capital gains tax The regulation of Section 44b EStG relates the new capital gains tax to income from life insurance and in particular to interest from securitized capital claims (Section 43 (1) No. Federal Office of Finance"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "e) Reimbursement of capital gains tax to certain creditors Tax-exempt corporations and legal entities under public law with limited tax liability are subject to the new capital gains tax of 10% to be levied from 1989 onwards"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "not charged (\u00a7 44c EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Credit institutions can therefore refrain from withholding tax on interest payments to such creditors (Section 44a (5) EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In other cases, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In the case of income from securitized capital claims, the Federal Office of Finance reimburses the capital gains tax withheld and paid by the issuer in accordance with Section 44b (1) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "f) Exclusion of the reimbursement of capital gains tax The buyer of dividend or interest coupons will not be reimbursed the capital gains tax retained by the issuer because he is not a creditor of the capital income in relation to the issuer (Section 45 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This is because the credit or reimbursement of capital gains tax is only possible for the shareholder or holder of the bond"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "g) Registration and certification of capital gains tax According to \u00a7 45a EStG, the regulations on registration and certification of capital gains tax also apply to the new capital gains tax of 10% to be levied from 1989 onwards"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Since with the tax deduction of 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "the income tax is generally settled on income from life insurance, the insurance companies only have to issue a certificate of withheld and paid capital gains tax at the request of the policyholder, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "because the policyholder wants to include the income in the income tax assessment (Section 45b sentence 4 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "h) Special treatment of investment income from life insurances The new \u00a7 45b EStG basically stipulates the compensation for income from life insurance which, according to \u00a7 43a EStG, the tax deduction of 10 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "subject"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "At the request of the taxpayer, however, this income must be included in the assessment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The associated crediting of the withheld capital gains tax can result in a full refund"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "16 Assessment of income subject to tax deduction Section 46 EStG contains the following changes: The assessment limits in Section 46 (1) EStG have been expanded to DM 54,000 / DM 27,000"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The exemption limit in \u00a7 46 Paragraph 2 No. 1 EStG of DM 800 now applies to taxable ancillary income and to all tax-free income subject to progression (therefore \u00a7 46 Paragraph 2 No. 2a and 2c letter b EStG repealed)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The remaining tax-free amount according to \u00a7 13 Abs 3 EStG is in the case of ancillary income i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 46 Paragraph 2 No. 1 EStG (and Paragraph 3) as well as for losses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 46 Paragraph 2 No. 8 Letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b considered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The obligation to assess wages from - side by side - several employers is no longer dependent on income (Section 46 (2) No. 2 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to pension payments (Section 46 Paragraph 2 No. 3 and 3a EStG repealed) and for spouses with the tax class combination III and V or VI (Section 46 Paragraph 2 No. 3a EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The assessment obligation according to \u00a7 46 Paragraph 2 No. 4a EStG has been extended to the - new - cases in which a child allowance has been certified in advance on the income tax card of the parent with unlimited tax liability, a child tax allowance is transferred to the other parent or a child according to \u00a7 32 Para 7 sentence 2 EStG is assigned to the father (see also no.11 letter b paragraph 2)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Due to the revised assessment of \u00a7 46 Paragraph 2 No. 5 EStG, childcare costs taken into account in advance in the wage tax procedure must in certain cases be subsequently checked by assessment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "On the basis of the supplemented section 46 (2) EStG penultimate sentence, the application for assessment must be made by submitting the income tax return"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The regulation of section 46 (6) EStG on local jurisdiction has been repealed since 1988"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "17 Changes in the taxation of limited taxpayers The new capital gains tax to be levied under Section 43 of the Income Tax Act from 1989 also applies to capital income that previously did not belong to the domestic income of limited taxpayers within the meaning of Section 49 of the Income Tax Act (Section 49 (1) No. 5 of the Income Tax Act)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "So that those liable to limited income tax - subject to a partial or full refund of the capital gains tax levied on the basis of an agreement to avoid double taxation - can also be covered by the new capital gains tax, the scope of domestic income has been expanded in the sense of the limited income tax liability"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The newly approved deduction of interest on certain tax claims in Section 10 (1) No. 5 EStG also applies to persons subject to limited income tax (Section 50 (1) EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "For children abroad with limited tax liability, training allowances will also be granted in future according to Section 33a (2) EStG (Section 50 (4) EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This regulation already applies to the assessment period 1988 (Section 52 (23) EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "18 Amendment of the authorization provisions, price increase reserve (Section 51 Paragraph 1 No. 2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b EStG): Price increase reserves according to \u00a7 74 EStDV can only be created in financial years that end before January 1, 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Reserves existing at this point in time can be continued within the previously permitted period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Import goods discount (Section 51 Paragraph 1 No. 2 Letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "m EStG): The valuation discount for certain economic assets of the current assets of foreign origin (so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Import goods discount) can only be up to 15% for the fiscal year ending in the assessment period 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "and for all financial years ending thereafter only in the amount of up to 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "to be entitled to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "19 Section 51 (1) no.2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "n Income Tax Act; \u00a7 81 EStDV By changing the authorization in \u00a7 51 Paragraph 1 No. 2 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In the EStG, special depreciation for coal and ore mining according to \u00a7 81 EStDV is limited to assets and measures that are acquired or manufactured before January 1, 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to the deduction of operating expenses from the costs of the preliminary room"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "20 Income tax as a benchmark tax From the assessment period 1990, the deduction amounts for children by which the fixed income tax or annual wage tax as benchmark tax for annex taxes is to be reduced to 300 or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "150 DM reduced for each child to be considered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The change has an indirect effect on the church tax, which the church tax rates of the federal states refer to the regulation in \u00a7 51a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "21 Change in application regulations, unless already shown in the relevant material regulations: By changing the date in sentence 3 of Section 52 (15) EStG, the transitional regulation of the Home Ownership Promotion Act (retention of the old law for up to twelve years) also opens for agricultural residential buildings, for which the building application was made between March 1, 1986 and January 1, 1987"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "With the new sentence 10 in Section 52 (15) of the Income Tax Act, extraction gains are included in the tax exemption of the extraction gain in accordance with sentence 7 when agricultural and forestry business premises are developed for the first time with owner-occupied apartments"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The discount is limited to one apartment used for their own residential purposes and one apartment for elderly people and will apply from 1987"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The regulation also applies to traders and freelancers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The application of the limitation of the compensation and deduction of losses in the case of limited liability according to \u00a7 15a EStG to losses in buildings that have been subsidized with public funds, postponed to fiscal years beginning after December 31, 1994 (\u00a7 52 Paragraph 19 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "22 On Section 53 EStG By way of a transitional provision, Section 33a (1) EStG is adapted for the calendar years 1988 and 1989 to the system applicable from 1990 (see the second sentence of the comments on Section 33a (1) EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This is necessary because the increase in the maximum amounts according to Section 33a (1) EStG does not apply until 1990, but the training allowances for children abroad (Section 33a (2) EStG) can already be used with effect from 1988"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Amendment of the Corporate Income Tax Act (Article 2 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) 1 Tax exemptions a) The tax exemption for organs of state housing policy (\u00a7 5 Paragraph 1 No. 11 - old - KStG) is repealed with effect from 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Credit institutions that have already been exempt from corporation tax as organs of state housing policy will be included in the exemption catalog of Section 5 (1) No. 2 KStG from this point in time"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b) The tax exemption for non-profit housing companies according to \u00a7 5 Paragraph 1 No. 10 - old - KStG will be limited from 1990 to acquisition and business cooperatives as well as associations whose activity essentially consists in renting out self-made or acquired apartments to members or on the basis of them a cooperative license agreement"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Non-privileged activities lead to partial tax liability for companies"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "If the income exceeds more than 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "of the total revenue, the company becomes fully taxable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "c) Non-profit settlement companies within the meaning of the Reich Settlement Act (Section 5 (1) No. 12 KStG) remain tax-free as long as they mainly carry out settlement, agricultural structure improvement and land development measures in rural areas, with the exception of housing construction"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Do they do other activities, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "housing construction, they are partially taxable from 1990 with the surpluses from these activities"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "If the income from these activities predominates, the companies become fully taxable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "d) With effect from 1990, the tax exemption for non-profit companies i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "of the Reichsheimst\u00e4ttengesetz (Reichsheimst\u00e4tten Act), which are permitted to issue homes (Section 5 (1) No. 13 - old - KStG); legal persons who act as restructuring agencies or development agencies (Section 5 (1) No. 17 - old - KStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In order to make it easier for non-profit housing and settlement companies to switch to tax liability, they can apply for the tax exemption for another year until December 31, 1990 (Section 54 (3) KStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Corresponding regulations have been included in the Trade Tax Act (\u00a7 3 No. 2 15 and 17 \u00a7 36 Paragraph 3 GewStG) and in the Wealth Tax Act (\u00a7 3 Paragraph 1 No. 2 13 and 15 \u00a7 25 Paragraph 3 VStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "2 Loss deduction, denial of loss deduction in the case of the purchase of a shell Losses that have not been compensated for can also be deducted from the income determination for corporations in the years following the year of loss (Section 8 (1) KStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The requirements for the loss deduction are based on Section 10d EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In this provision, the previous time limit of five years has been repealed, for the first time for unpaid losses of the assessment period 1985. The newly inserted Section 8 (4) KStG ensures that a corporation can only carry forward an unpaid loss with tax effect if it is not only legally but also economically identical to the person who suffered the loss"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In the case of the corporation named as the main application, there is no economic identity if more than 3/4 of the shares are transferred to new shareholders and the company then resumes its business operations with new business assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Typical restructuring cases do not fall under the deduction prohibition of Section 8 (4) KStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The prohibition of loss deduction applies accordingly to the compensation of the loss from the beginning of the financial year until the time of the transfer of shares (Section 8 (4) sentence 3 KStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The regulation is to be applied for the first time for the assessment period 1990 (\u00a7 54 Abs 1 KStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "If the legal transactions that led to the loss of economic identity were concluded after June 23, 1988, the regulation is also to be applied for assessment periods beginning before January 1, 1990 (Section 54 (4) KStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "A corresponding regulation is contained in the Trade Tax Act (\u00a7 10a, \u00a7 36 Paragraph 6 GewStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "3 Reduction in corporate tax rates As of 1990, the corporate tax rate for retained earnings will be 56%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "on 50 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "reduced (Section 23 (1) KStG); the dividend rate of 36 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "stays unchanged; the previously reduced corporate income tax rate of 50%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "for the corporations not included in the crediting procedure of 50%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "on 46 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "reduced (Section 23 (2) and (3) KStG); the special corporate income tax rate for ZDF of 8%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "on 74 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "the fees from advertising mails are reduced"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The rounding-off rule of Section 23 (4) KStG, according to which income has to be rounded down to DM 10 in order to calculate corporate income tax, has already been deleted with effect from the 1988 assessment period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "4 Taxation of foreign income components (\u00a7 26 KStG) a) The reduced corporate income tax rate for foreign income from the operation of merchant ships in international traffic i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "of Section 34c (4) EStG will be increased from the previous 28 percent from the 1990 assessment period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "on 25 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "degraded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b) Distribution-related partial value depreciation If a domestic corporation holds a significant stake in a foreign corporation, the profit distributions of the foreign subsidiary to the domestic parent company are exempt from German corporation tax under most double taxation agreements or indirect tax credit according to Section 26 (2) or (3) KStG in Can be claimed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Are for profit distributions z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "If open or hidden reserves are used, the value of the participation decreases"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "If it falls below the previous book value, the loss in value can be taken into account to reduce tax by means of partial depreciation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Similar tax reductions can result from the sale of the participation or from the dissolution or reduction of the capital of the foreign company"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "These possibilities for a tax reduction are excluded by Section 26 (8) of the KStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The aim is to prevent losses in value associated with a tax-exempt dividend distribution from reducing the tax on the other income of the parent company"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The provision of Section 26 Paragraph 8 KStG is to be applied for the first time if the profit reduction is due to profit distributions after June 23, 1988 (Section 54 Paragraph 7 KStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "A corresponding regulation has been inserted into the trade tax law (\u00a7 8 No. 10 \u00a7 36 Paragraph 4 GewStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "It also applies there to holdings in domestic corporations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "5 Transitional regulation for the breakdown of equity due to the reduction in the tax rate of 56 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "on 50 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In order to ensure that the distribution of the portion of income that was subject to corporation tax of 56% in the period before 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "have succumbed to the previous corporate tax reduction of 20%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "leads, \u00a7 54 (8) KStG provides that a positive partial amount EK 56 from the time before 1990 is to be continued for a transitional period of five years in addition to the new partial amount EK 50"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "After that, EK 56 in the amount of 56/44 of its inventory is to be added to EK 50; EK 02 is to be reduced by 12/44 of the stock of EK 56"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "6 Back payment and reimbursement interest on non-deductible taxes According to current law, interest relating to personal taxes or sales tax on personal consumption is excluded from deduction (Section 10 No. 2 - old - KStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "From 1990, according to the amended number 2 of \u00a7 10 KStG, the interest on additional tax claims as well as deferral and suspension interest can also be deducted for these types of tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "While natural persons can claim this interest as special expenses (Section 10 Paragraph 1 No. 5 EStG), the comparable interest rates for corporations will in future reduce the profit from commercial operations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In order to ensure that trade tax is charged regardless of the legal form, this interest must be added back when determining the trade income of corporations (Section 8 No. 11 GewStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Refund interest on non-deductible taxes will be recorded as income for natural persons and corporations as before"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "For evasion interest (\u00a7 235 AO) and other ancillary services that are attributable to non-deductible taxes, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Surcharges for late payments and late payments remain with the previous prohibition on deduction"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In addition, evasion interest is excluded from the deduction insofar as it relates to deductible taxes (Section 4 (5) No. 8a EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "7 Other projects: External shareholder financing The Bundestag has removed the regulation on external external financing proposed by the Federal Government (Section 8a KStG - draft) from the Tax Reform Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In a resolution, however, it has expressed its will to implement a comprehensive regulation of shareholder external financing (so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "big solution) to be included in the next tax amendment law and to come into force at the same time as the Tax Reform Act 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The BMF letter of March 16, 1987 (BStBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "373) is decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Changes to the Trade Tax Act and the Trade Tax Implementing Ordinance (Articles 3 and 4 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) 1 Change to the addition regulations for interest In the addition regulations in \u00a7 8 No. 1 GewStG, the term \"interest\" is replaced by the term \"fees\" from 1990 onwards"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This ensures that, in addition to remuneration with a fixed interest rate, profit-related remuneration (such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "participatory loans) as well as other payments related to a debt that are of interest (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Damnum), must be taken into account when adding"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "For editorial reasons, the term \"debt interest\" is replaced by the term \"fees\" in the addition rule in Section 12 (2) No. 1 GewStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "2 Regulation of the distribution-related partial value depreciation - \u00a7 8 No. 10 GewStG -: Profit reductions that have arisen through the application of the lower partial value of the participation in a corporation or through its sale or withdrawal and are related to a profit distribution that is not subject to trade tax may according to the new Number 10 of \u00a7 8 GewStG from June 24, 1988 (\u00a7 36 Paragraph 3 GewStG) no longer reduce the commercial income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "3 Interest on tax claims According to \u00a7 8 No. 11 GewStG, interest on tax claims may not reduce the commercial income of corporations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In this way, equality with the other commercial operations is achieved"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "4 Loss carryforward According to the provisions of the Income Tax Act, according to \u00a7\u00a7 10a, 36 Abs 5 GewStG, deficits that arose from the collection period 1985 onwards can be carried forward without limitation (unlimited loss carryforward)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The deficits that can be carried forward are also determined separately from the reporting period 1990, as is the case with income tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "5 Prepayments According to the new sentence 2 of Section 19 (1) GewStG, traders with a different business year from the reporting period 1990 onwards have to pay their advance payments on the annual tax during the business year that ends in the reporting period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The change corresponds to the regulation in Section 49 (3) KStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "According to Section 36 (7) of the GewStG, the new regulation does not apply to commercial enterprises established before January 1, 1986 with a different business year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Furthermore, according to the amended paragraph 5 sentence 2 of \u00a7 19 GewStG, advance payments are only charged if the individual advance payment rate is at least 100 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "6 The changes to the dismantling regulation of \u00a7 31 GewStG are due to the elimination of the Christmas or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Employee allowance in the Income Tax Act (\u00a7 19 EStG) and the change in the tax exemption for certain housing companies (\u00a7 3 No. 15 GewStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "7 The other changes adapt the trade tax law to changes in other laws (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Changes to \u00a7 3 GewStG) or are of an editorial nature"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "8 Continuous debts with credit institutions - \u00a7 19 GewStDV -: From the survey period 1990 onwards, based on \u00a7 12 of the Banking Act, the scope of the investments to be covered with equity capital will be redrafted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In addition, the regulation now also includes leased items and loans to company affiliated companies that are not banks"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The legal consequences of \u00a7 19 GewStDV will only come into effect in the future if the asset items from transactions that are decisive for the classification as a credit institution predominate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Up to now, the comparison of gross profit between banking and non-banking transactions had to be used"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Changes to the Investment Allowance Act (Article 6 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) The Investment Allowance Act is repealed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This eliminates the regional allowance, the investment allowance for research and development investments and the investment allowance for certain energy investments"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "It is envisaged that all investments completed before January 1, 1990 will be subsidized without restriction through investment grants, investments made after December 31, 1989 and before January 1, 1991 as well as advance payments made before January 1, 1991 on acquisition costs and partial production costs will be favored, if with the investment started before April 1, 1989"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Changes to the Berlin Promotion Act (Article 7 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) 1 VAT part"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "on 2 or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "lowered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In the lower value-added area, the preferential tariff will be redesigned (\u00a7\u00a7 1 Abs 7 1a Abs 2 BerlinFG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The buyer preference (\u00a7 2 BerlinFG) for roasted coffee and semi-finished cocoa products is canceled if the manufacturer in Berlin (West) has a value added quota of 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "not reached"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In the case of cigarettes and smoking tobacco, manufacturer preference will be improved in the interests of preserving jobs in Berlin (Section 4 (3) no.7 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b BerlinFG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The reduction in the manufacturer's preference due to the lowering of the base preference and the redesign of the preferential tariff is thus compensated for in the Berlin tobacco industry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "At the same time, the customer preference is reduced to a corresponding extent (Section 4 Paragraph 3 No. 7 Letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b BerlinFG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "2 Income tax part a) Increased deductions (\u00a7 14 BerlinFG) The increased deductions of 75 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "for movable assets of the fixed assets in Berlin are limited to new assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In addition, the increased deductions according to \u00a7 14 BerlinFG for employee housing are no longer applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "For this purpose, only increased deductions according to \u00a7 14a BerlinFG (up to a total of 50 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "in the first 3 years)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "b) Berlin loan (Sections 16 and 17 BerlinFG) The transfer of loan claims against payment in accordance with Sections 16 and 17 BerlinFG is equivalent to repayment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The new regulation applies for the first time to loans that are assigned after March 22, 1988"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The commitment period to the Berlin permanent establishment is increased from 3 to 8 years for ships for the acquisition or manufacture of which loans are used in accordance with \u00a7 16 BerlinFG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Loans according to \u00a7 16 BerlinFG may no longer be used for the acquisition or manufacture of aircraft"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The new regulations apply for the first time to loans that are passed on to companies after December 31, 1989"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "c) Investment allowance according to \u00a7 19 BerlinFG The investment allowance according to \u00a7 19 BerlinFG is limited by lowering the so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Basic allowance of 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "on 75 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": ", but no more than 22,500 DM annually, lowering of the investment allowance rates from previously 25, 30 and 40 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "to uniformly 15 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "for movable assets and from previously 20 and 25 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "to uniformly 10 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "in buildings"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "At the same time, the increased allowance for trucks, tractors and motor vehicle trailers in manufacturing companies is no longer applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The production of buildings in the energy sector is excluded from the subsidy"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "On the other hand, subsequent production work on movable assets will also be promoted in the future and the increased investment allowance of 15 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "extended to movable assets of all kinds"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The transitional regulation is designed in accordance with the transitional regulation for the repeal of the Investment Allowance Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Amendment of the Foreign Investment Act (Article 8 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) Reference is made to the comments on Section 2a Paragraphs 3 and 4 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Amendment of the law on capital investment companies (Article 9 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) The tax deduction from capital income in the amount of 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "From 1989 onwards, income from units in investment funds is also subject to this, regardless of whether it is income from special securities funds, from investment funds or from property special funds"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Income from foreign bonds, from the sale of securities and the sale of real estate is exempt from tax if there is more than two years between the purchase and the sale"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Amendment to the Valuation Act (Article 10 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) 1 Special business assets From the valuation date January 1, 1989, corporations, in particular corporations, are treated as individuals and partnerships with regard to the treatment of special business assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "It is also made clear that assets of special business assets II are also to be included in the unit valuation of the partnership"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The addition to the special business assets always takes precedence over the addition to the business assets of the co-entrepreneur (Section 97 Paragraph 1 No. 5 Sentence 2 BewG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Receivables and debts between the company and a partner will in future be treated like assets belonging to special business assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "An exception only applies to claims and debts from regular business transactions between the company and a partner or from the surrender of short-term sums of money for the company or for a partner (Section 97 Paragraph 1 No. 5 Sentence 3 BewG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "2 Other changes Section 103a sentence 2 BewG clarifies the treatment of provisions for anniversary bonuses from 1989 onwards; these are only deductible if strict conditions are met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "3 The repeal of section 104a BewG serves to simplify the administration and removes the deductibility of the business assets of the members of certain cooperatives from 1990 onwards.4 The tax concessions for business assets serving the public water supply according to section 117 (1) no.1 BewG will be repealed from 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "5 The amendments to section 102 (1) sentence 1 and section 2 sentence 1 of section 104 (3) 12 and 14 of section 110 (1) no.6 and section 111 BewG adapt the provisions to other changes in the law or are of an editorial nature only"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "6 Paragraph 124 regulates the application date for the provisions amended by the Tax Reform Act 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Amendment to the Wealth Tax Act (Article 11 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) 1 The amendment to Section 3 VStG follows corresponding changes to corporation tax and trade tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "2 Paragraph 6 of the VStG is adapted to the terms of the Disabled Persons Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "3 Paragraph 25 of the VStG regulates the application date for the provisions changed by the Tax Reform Act 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Amendment to the Value Added Tax Act (Article 12 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) 1 Change to personal consumption"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "c sentence 2 UStG is related to the new regulation of the deduction of entertainment expenses from income tax (Section 4 (5) sentence 1 no.2 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The addition ensures that the percentage of the hospitality expenses that are to be regarded as reasonable and incurred by the company, but which, according to Section 4 (5) sentence 1 no.2 of the Income Tax Act, may not reduce profit, are not taxed as personal consumption"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "2 Tax withholding amount for small businesses The tax withholding amount according to \u00a7 19 Paragraph 3 UStG will be abolished from 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "At the same time, the non-collection limit in Section 19 (1) UStG has been raised from DM 20,000 to DM 25,000 in sales for the previous year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Amendment of the Fire Protection Tax Act (Article 13 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) Fire protection tax amounts that are to be paid later on the basis of an external audit are to be set in one sum together with the tax for the current registration period from the entry into force of the Tax Reform Act 1990; This eliminates the previously time-consuming process according to which the tax has to be reset for all registration periods concerned"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Amendment of the Insurance Tax Act (Article 14 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) The premiums paid from January 1, 1989 for accident insurance with premium refund are subject to insurance tax at a reduced rate of 14%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Changes to the tax code (Article 15 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) 1 Protection of bank customers The new section 30a of the tax code is the content of the banking decree of August 31, 1979 (BStBl I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "590) has been completely adopted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Legally clarified that on the occasion of an external audit at credit institutes, the tendering of control reports on credit balances and deposits of bank customers is omitted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The previous limits for determining investment income remain unchanged"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "2 Tax assessment for tax registrations According to Section 167 (1) AO, in cases in which a tax is to be reported due to legal obligation, a tax assessment is only required if the assessment leads to a different tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This regulation is clarified to the effect that the taxpayer can also be claimed by way of a tax assessment if he has to withhold the tax for the account of another and does not do so or does so improperly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "3 Interest on additional tax claims and tax refunds The newly inserted provision of \u00a7 233a AO regulates the general interest on additional tax claims and tax refunds"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "It is intended to compensate for the fact that the taxes for the individual taxpayers, for whatever reasons, are set and due at different times"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In the future, additional tax claims and tax refunds should in principle accrue interest after 15 months (waiting period) from the end of the tax year until the due date of the claim"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Notwithstanding this, the waiting period for income tax is 21 months if the income from agriculture and forestry outweighs the other income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The interest ends when the additional tax claim or tax refund is due for the first time, but at the latest after 4 years"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The limitation to 4 years takes account of the fact that external audits are often only carried out a long time after the end of the individual tax year for reasons for which the taxpayers are not responsible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Due to the time limitation of the interest run, the taxpayers are set up for the interest payment as if the tax assessment was carried out promptly on the basis of the external audit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "As before, however, the tax assessment itself is possible until the statute of limitations has expired"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The types of interest under previous law and the late payment surcharges, apart from the evasion interest, have in common that they intervene at the earliest with the first due date of the tax, which requires a tax assessment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Interest on additional tax claims and tax refunds for a period between the end of the tax year and the due date was not previously planned"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "It occurs in addition to the applicable interest and default law"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "For reasons of practicality, the fixed interest rate of the applicable law (\u00a7 238 AO) is adhered to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Thereafter, the interest for additional tax claims and tax refunds for each full month of the interest run is 05 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The general interest rate applies for the first time to claims that arise after December 31, 1988 (see Article 16 No. 2 of the Tax Reform Act 1990)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "For the 1989 income tax that arises at the end of the 1989 calendar year, this means"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "that additional claims and reimbursements will bear interest from April 1, 1991"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The interest on additional tax claims as well as deferral and suspension interest will be deductible in future"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "For the rest, reference is made to the statements on Section 10 (1) No. 5, Section 12 No. 3 EStG and Section 10 No. 2 KStG regarding the deductibility of interest"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "4 Evasion interest and litigation interest The changes to \u00a7\u00a7 235 236 AO are related to the introduction of interest on back tax claims and tax refunds according to \u00a7 233a AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "By offsetting interest on arrears and reimbursement interest, overlaps with the interest on evaded taxes and the payment of litigation interest on reimbursement amounts should be prevented"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "5 Suspension interest In the decision of the BFH of December 10, 1986 (BStBl 1987 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "389) it remains to be seen whether, in the event of a retrospective suspension (annulment) of enforcement, suspension interest can be claimed for the period of retroactive effect"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The amendment to \u00a7 237 AO makes it clear that the interest period always begins on the day on which the effect (possibly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Retroactive effect) of the suspension (also cancellation) of the execution occurs"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "6 Determination of interest The changes to \u00a7 239 AO are related to the introduction of interest on back tax claims and tax refunds according to \u00a7 233a AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "On the one hand, it regulates when the assessment period for the interest on additional tax claims and tax refunds begins and, on the other hand, it determines that the assessment period does not expire as long as a tax assessment and its cancellation or amendment is still permissible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Amendments to the Introductory Act to the Fiscal Code (Article 16 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) The amendment to the transitional regulation in Article 97 \u00a7 1 EGAO stipulates that the amended procedural provisions of the Fiscal Code are to be applied to all proceedings pending when the Tax Reform Act 1990 came into force, unless otherwise specified"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Section 15 (4), newly inserted in Article 97 EGAO, regulates the first-time application of interest on back tax claims and tax refunds in accordance with Section 233a AO and the associated changes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The interest applies for the first time to claims that arise after December 31, 1988"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The changes to \u00a7\u00a7 235 236 AO apply for the first time to interest accruing after December 31, 1988"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Law on the Exemption from Penalty Declaration of Income from Capital Assets and Capital Assets (Article 17 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) 1 Legislative intention The legal provision is intended for those who have not or not fully declared their income from capital assets and capital assets themselves and who must therefore expect the reproach To have intentionally or recklessly reduced the income tax applicable to this income and the wealth tax applicable to the corresponding assets, facilitate the road to tax honesty"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "2 Prerequisites for impunity Anyone who has not or not fully declared his income from capital assets should remain exempt from punishment for periods further back if he correctly and completely declares the capital income for the assessment periods 1986 and 1987 by December 31, 1990, or fails to do so for the assessment periods from 1986 onwards or catches up or corrects incorrect information"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The effects of the declarations exempting from punishment also extend to cases in which, under the impression of the public discussion about the tax liability of interest income, when the income from capital assets is disclosed, declarations have been made after October 13, 1987 that meet the requirements of a Exempting declarations are sufficient, in particular voluntary disclosures (\u00a7\u00a7 371 378 Paragraph 3 AO), tax returns for assessment periods from 1986, correction declarations (\u00a7 153 AO) or anticipated \"declarations exempting from punishment\""}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "It would appear unreasonable to withhold the benefit of \u00a7 1 and \u00a7 2 of the law from this group of people just because the declaration was made prematurely"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In order not to obstruct the path to tax honesty for those who have not indicated the wealth leading to the income in addition to the income from capital assets, the law grants exemption from punishment for the past, also with regard to wealth tax, if the capital assets from which the income flowed are explained"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In order to avoid tensions within the family, the impunity also extends to persons assessed together with the declaring person who have not themselves declared the capital income or capital assets exempt from punishment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The same applies in the case of a declaration of exemption from punishment by a child who is now of legal age in favor of former legal representatives"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The regulation does not apply to income from other types of income, even if it is income from assets, or to other types of assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In this respect, impunity can only be obtained under the conditions of Section 371 AO or Section 378 Paragraph 3 AO (voluntary disclosure)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Further prerequisites for exemption from punishment are that the reduced taxes on capital income or capital assets for the assessment periods from 1986 onwards are paid within a reasonable period set by the tax authorities"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "A declaration exempting from punishment is no longer possible if an official of the tax authorities has appeared to examine income or wealth tax, or in general to determine a tax offense or tax offense, if the perpetrator or his representative has initiated criminal or fine proceedings because of an income or tax offense Property tax evasion has been announced, or the offense has already been wholly or partly discovered at the time of the declaration exempting the offense and the perpetrator knew this or, given a reasonable assessment of the situation, had to expect it"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In the case of a frivolous reduction in taxes, the same conditions apply to failure to investigate as to exemption from punishment in the case of willful tax evasion"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "3 Consequences under tax law of a declaration exempting from penalties In order to make it easier for taxpayers who have not or not fully disclosed their income from capital assets and the corresponding capital assets in the past, the way to tax compliance, the law provides in addition to the exemption from penalties or fines, that there is no subsequent taxation for the period prior to 1986 if there is no impunity or a fine is not imposed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This also applies if the taxpayer has not acted at fault with regard to a tax reduction, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "found in an unavoidable error of prohibition"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The law ensures that tax assessment is not excluded in those cases in which an inheritance for tax debts of a testator who himself has not made a subsequent declaration exempting the penalty can be claimed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "In these cases, the tax situation is regularly reported by e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "discovered by credit institutions according to Section 33 of the Inheritance Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "If a declaration exempting the tax within the meaning of Section 1 of the Act has not yet been submitted when submitting a tax return, the taxpayer should still have the opportunity to be tax-compliant"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The tax authority must therefore set a reasonable deadline for any declaration exempting from punishment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Amendment of the Fifth Asset Creation Act (Article 18 of the Tax Reform Act) From 1990 the following applies: Funding is limited to asset participation as well as building society savings and investments similar to these"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Account and insurance savings as well as profit-sharing certificates and profit bonds issued outside the company are only paid with an employee savings allowance of 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "beneficiaries if the relevant contracts were concluded before January 1, 1989"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The annual maximum amount of capital-building benefits with additional benefits will be standardized to DM 936 and thus increased by DM 312 for building society savings and similar forms of investment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The supplement rate for building society savings and similar forms of investment is set at 10 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": ", for property investments to 20%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "lowered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The income limits are raised to DM 27,000 / 54,000 (single / married)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The child-related increase in the additional rates and the income limits does not apply"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The employee savings allowance is no longer paid out by the employer but annually in arrears by the tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The tax reduction for employers is abolished"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Amendment of the Housing Premium Act (Article 19 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) From 1990 (as in the SparPG), an annual minimum savings amount of DM 100 must be made (Section 2 (1) No. 1 WoPG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The requirement of \"one and a half times\" (\u00a7 2 Paragraph 1 No. 1 WoPG), like the borrowing ban (\u00a7 2 Paragraph 2 WoPG) for all contributions to building societies, expired at the end of 1987 (\u00a7 10 Paragraph 3 WoPG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "From 1990 the income limits for single / married persons are 27,000 / 54,000 DM (Section 2a (1) WoPG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "From 1990 the taxable income of the savings year is decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The child additives in Section 2a (1) sentences 2 and 3 and in Section 3 (1) WoPG do not apply"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "This already applies to the additional premium from 1989 (Section 10 (4) WoPG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "The increase in the income limit for children no longer applies from 1990 (Section 10 (1) WoPG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "From 1989 onwards, the premium rate according to Section 3 (1) WoPG is 10 percent for all contracts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "(\u00a7 10 Abs 4 WoPG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "Reduction of tax breaks and special regulations in housing (property tax) (Article 22 of the Tax Reform Act 1990) Under the previous requirements of \u00a7 82 II WoBauG, newly created apartments are only recognized as tax-privileged if they are ready for occupancy before January 1, 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "At the same time, the ten-year property tax relief according to \u00a7 92a II WoBauG - even if it is publicly subsidized apartments - is only granted for apartments that were ready for occupancy before January 1, 1990 (Art"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "22 Paragraph 1 No. 7 and 10 and Paragraph 2 No. 5)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0084252.xml"}, "text": "--- Other tax law Federal Republic of Bavaria North Rhine-Westphalia PDF"}]