[{"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion K\u00f6lnS-2230 - 55 - St 113S-2230 -EStG: 4 / 1EStG: 4 / 3EStG: 13aEStR: 127 For 1988 see OFD Cologne, same Az"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "28 12 1989 Income tax assessment of farmers and foresters for the assessment period 19871 General 2 Determination of profit from agriculture and forestry according to average rates (Section 13 a EStG) 21 Scope of application 211 Re Section 13 a Paragraph 1 No. 2 EStG (initial value limit) 212 Re Section 13 a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG (livestock limit) 22 Determination of profit221 Basic amount222 Value of work done223 Rent income received224 Profits according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 8 EStG2241 Sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals2242 Profit from pensioner animal husbandry2243 Vegetable growing (agricultural and horticultural ponds2246247 Vegetable farming2246247 Vegetable farming2246247 Vegetable farming for farming2246247 Forage farming2246 Vegetable farming , Debt interest, permanent burdens227 Other additions and reductions3 Determination of the profit on agriculture and forestry by comparing the operating income with the operating expenses (Section 4 (3) EStG) 31 Scope32 Determination of profits321 Cattle dur Average values322 Value in use of the apartment4 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry through bookkeeping (Section 4 (1) EStG) 41 Scope of application42 Opening balance sheets43 Bookkeeping44 Determination of profit441 Average livestock values442 Value in use of the apartment5 Estimate of the profit for farmers and foresters whose profit cannot be calculated using average rates51 General52 Estimate of the Profit according to standard rates521 Starting amount522 Lease income523 Surcharges for profits or profits not settled with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits5231 Sales of breeding cattle and other valuable animals5232 Above normal livestock farming5233 Field vegetable growing (agricultural use) 5234 Vegetable growing (horticultural use), fruit growing, asparagus and strawberry cultivation as well as trout pond farming524 Usage value of the apartment525 Wage expenses526 Lease expenses for building surcharges526 Lease expenses, debt interest527 Profit estimate5272 Increased deductions for residential buildings, as far as the value in use taxation according to \u00a7 52 Abs 15 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2 EStG is continued5273 Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV6 Other61 Partial retirement benefits62 Control notifications63 Unit value notifications64 Use of the assessment files when carrying out the assessment65 Review of Annex L1 General The assessment decisions for farmers and foresters are issued annually in full"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Changes to the previous text are indicated by vertical lines"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2 Determination of profit from agriculture and forestry according to average rates (Section 13 a EStG) 21 Scope of application Supplementary to Section 127 Paragraphs 3 - 10 EStR and No. 2 of the BMF's introductory letter of 27 March 1981 (Federal Tax Gazette 1981 I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "282), the following is pointed out: 211 Regarding Section 13 a Paragraph 1 No. 2 EStG (initial value limit) The initial value determined in accordance with Section 13 a Paragraph 4 EStG is decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Cattle surcharges can therefore not be taken into account as long as they have not been made the subject of a value update by the valuation body in accordance with \u00a7\u00a7 41 in conjunction with 22 para. 1 no. 1 BewG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Something different only applies if the requirements of Section 13 a Paragraph 4 No. 1 Sentence 4 EStG are met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "212 On Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG (animal population limit) According to Section 127 Paragraph 7 EStR and No. 22 of the BMF's introductory letter of 27 3 1981 a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": ", is to be applied accordingly when examining the VE limits of Section 13 a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG Section 124 a EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The prerequisite for the discontinuation of the determination of the average rate of profit is that the number of VE sustainably exceeds the limits of Section 13 a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "For the term sustainability, reference is made to Section 135 (4) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In the case of a gradual increase in the number of animals, it therefore depends on whether the number of animals converted into VE has been above the limits of Section 13 a (1) No. 3 EStG over the three preceding financial years"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "If this is the case, from the beginning of the fourth financial year onwards, the requirements of Section 13 a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG are no longer met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "If, on the other hand, the livestock are increased in one go well beyond the maximum permissible limits - e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "in connection with an expansion of the barn capacities - so that the livestock limits can also be expected in the following financial years, the requirements of Section 13 a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG do not apply from the time the maximum limits are exceeded for the first time"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The maximum number of animals that are permitted in accordance with Section 13 a Paragraph 1 No. 3 and Section 13 Paragraph 1 No. 1 EStG and converted into VE can be found in the overview attached as Annex 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "22 Determination of profit The scheme for determining profit according to \u00a7 13 a Paragraph 3 to 8 EStG results from the form Annex ESt 2 L / 3 L (86) - Profit determination according to \u00a7 13 a EStG -"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In detail, I would like to point out the following: 221 Basic amount When determining the basic amount according to Section 13 a Paragraph 4 EStG, Section 130 a Paragraph 3 EStR must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "222 Value of the work performance In the case of the basic amount according to Section 13 a Paragraph 4 EStG, it is assumed that the business is managed exclusively with paid workers (see Section 36 Paragraph 2 BewG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The value of the work performed by the business owner and his relatives who are not employed in the company on the basis of an employment relationship to be determined in accordance with Section 13 a Paragraph 5 EStG must therefore be added to the basic amount (Section 13 a Paragraph 3 No. 2 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Section 130 a Paragraph 4 to 6 EStR must be observed here"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In detail, the following is pointed out: When determining the value of the work performance for the physical cooperation of the business owner and the relatives who are not employed, only the work performance is to be taken into account in the result that is based on the initial value according to \u00a7 13 a para 4 EStG in the individual case No space required"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2 The paid workers are to be counted towards the appropriate number of full-time workers (VAK) according to the duration of their employment (\u00a7 13 a Abs 5 Nr 5 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to temporary workers employed on a short-term basis, as well as to workers who have been made available by contractors for certain ordering, maintenance or harvesting work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "For the crediting of the paid VAK"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "a breakdown of the wages is necessary, as far as it relates to the uses contained in the initial value (13 a para 4 EStG) and to the uses not contained therein"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Make Stpfl in the tax return (form \"Annex L\") to the extent / proportion of their employment or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "the activities of other people (relatives, third parties) in the company or no or obviously incorrect information on the part of the work attributable to special uses, the (physical) work or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "the proportion of the work performed by the business owner, the relatives employed in the business and / or the remunerated workers, if applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "with the assistance of the responsible official agricultural expert (ALS)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The table in the Felsmann comment in Section C 219 on the average labor requirement for special branches of business can also serve as a guide to determine the share that is attributable to special uses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "For the value of the work performed by the owner of a part-time business see Section 130 a Paragraph 4 Sentences 7 and 8 EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "For examples of calculating the value of the work, see Annex 2223 Collected lease interest. Reference is made to Section 13 a Paragraph 6 Sentence 2 EStG and Section 130 a Paragraph 7 EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The rent received also includes income from ground rent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Income from hunting leases is compensated by the basic amount as it relates to areas included in the initial value"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "224 Profits according to Section 13 a Paragraph 8 EStG Reference is made to Section 13 a Paragraph 8 EStG and Section 130 a Paragraph 9 EStR 1987"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In addition, please note the following: Profits from operations that were not taken into account when determining the initial value are, for example,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": ": Additional profits from sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals (cf. No. 2241), profits from renting rooms to holiday guests and from camping sites (ESt-Kartei NW \u00a7\u00a7 13 13 a EStG A No. 82), insofar as it relates to income Agriculture and forestry, interest income, insofar as the capital claim is attributable to the business assets, profits from riding schools and rental of own horses, insofar as it is income from agriculture and forestry, profits from secondary employment, insofar as it is income from agriculture and forestry trades, profits from investments that belong to the agricultural and forestry business assets, profits from the keeping and care of retired animals (see no.2242), profits from the rearing of animals in the wage system, profits from the rental of housing belonging to the agricultural business assets (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Rental residential property)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Profits from the inter-company use of machines, which are achieved in the context of agriculture and forestry, are not to be recorded in accordance with Section 13 a (8) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "You have already been paid for by applying the basic amount (ESt-Kartei NW \u00a7\u00a7 13 13 a EStG A Nr 103)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The profits (additional profits) according to \u00a7 13 a Paragraph 8 EStG are usually to be determined by comparing the operating income and operating expenses (\u00a7 4 Paragraph 3 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "If no records are available, the profits (additional profits) are to be estimated according to the principles of Section 4 Paragraph 1 EStG (Section 130 a Paragraph 9 Sentences 8 - 11 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "When estimating the profits (additional profits) from sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals, from growing vegetables and fruit, growing asparagus and strawberries and from trout pond farming, the following guidelines can serve as a guide"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Their application must not lead to an obviously incorrect taxation (see BFH judgment of 16 12 1965 BStBl 1966 III p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "193)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2241 Sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals From the sale of breeding cattle, only extraordinary income is to be recorded as a surcharge according to Section 13 a Paragraph 8 No. Judgment of 11/15/1984 BStBl 1985 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "156)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Extraordinary income is to be considered as exceeding the individual selling price including sales tax: breeding bulls 4200 DM breeding cows and cattle 3200 DM breeding boars 1,100 DM breeding sows 1000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "For breeding and riding horses, the additional profit is 60 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "the amount by which the selling price exceeds the value of 7500 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "If sales proceeds of more than 16,250 DM are achieved, the full amount of 11,000 DM (7,500 + 40%) is to be recognized as additional profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "of 8,750 DM)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Wages for paid workers as well as selling costs (auction fees, insurance contributions, transport costs, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": ") are taken into account in the amount of these values, so they cannot be deducted separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The additional profit must be calculated individually for each year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Offsetting with sales proceeds that are below these values \u200b\u200bis not permitted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The same procedure must be followed if above-average prices are achieved for breeding animals other than those specified or for other particularly valuable animals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The underlying value in these cases results from the tax production costs of the animal species in question plus 45%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2242 Profit from animal husbandry In the case of animal husbandry, income and profits are essentially dependent on the type of husbandry (barn or paddock husbandry), the type of livestock kept (e"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Horses or cattle) and the services (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "for horses also use of riding arenas)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In the case of pension horse keeping, the income includes payments for keeping and caring for the horses as well as remuneration for the use of riding arenas"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Depending on the location of the business and the type of services offered, income fluctuates between 250 DM and around 600 DM / month for each horse retired"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "When determining the profit, the judgment of the BFH of 14 4 1988 BStBl 1988 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "774 to be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The net profit for boarding horses is usually 60%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "of receipts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2243 Vegetable growing (agricultural and horticultural vegetable growing) For the delimitation of agricultural and horticultural vegetable growing see Sections 108, Paragraph 2 and 607, Paragraph 1, No. 1 BewRL 1964 Is vegetable growing in Wj"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "1987/1988 to be attributed to agricultural use, a surcharge according to Section 13a, Paragraph 8 of the Income Tax Act cannot be considered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Vegetables are only grown in the context of agricultural use if headed cabbage (white, red and savoy cabbage), picking peas and picking beans are grown exclusively using agricultural cultivation methods as part of agricultural crop rotation as the main crop"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "On the other hand, if the types of cabbage and / or peas or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Do not alternate beans with other agricultural crops such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Wheat, rye, barley, oats or beets, but one after the other or alternately with the same or different types of vegetables (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Endive, lettuce, lamb's lettuce, spinach, carrots, celery, beetroot, onions, radishes, leeks, tomatoes, kohlrabi, cucumbers, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": ") cultivated, the cultivation is no longer part of the agricultural crop rotation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Rather, it is a vegetable cultivation that is to be assessed according to horticultural principles (vegetable cultivation division of the horticultural use of vegetables, flowers and ornamental plants)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "If, in individual cases, an estimation method tailored to the company's circumstances is not preferable, or if accounting results from comparable farms or empirical values \u200b\u200bare not available, the profit can be estimated as follows: Outdoor vegetable growing Income between 40,000 DM and 80,000 DM / ha profit 40 to 65 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Vegetable growing with covered cultivation area Income between 80,000 DM and 135,000 DM / ha profit 30 to 65%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The profit is influenced by the type of marketing (auction in the wholesale market, sale on the farm, sale on the weekly market) and the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "A correct estimate in individual cases is i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "only possible in close cooperation with the ALS"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2244 Fruit growing The income fluctuates i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "between 15,000 and 35,000 DM per hectare"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "They depend on the type of fruit, the type of fruit, the age structure of the orchard and the quality of the soil and the climate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Special natural events such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Late frosts can lead to lower income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The profit can be as high as 30 to 50 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "of revenues are estimated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "It is influenced by the type of marketing (auction in the wholesale market, sale from the farm, sale at the weekly market) and the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "No. 2243 last paragraph applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2245 asparagus cultivation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "between 24,000 DM and 34,000 DM per hectare"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The profit can be 30 to 60 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "of revenues are estimated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "It is influenced by the type of marketing (auction in the wholesale market, sale from the farm, sale at the weekly market) and the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "No. 2243 last paragraph applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2246 Strawberry cultivation Revenues fluctuate i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "between 25,000 DM and 50,000 DM per hectare; the profits between 50 and 70 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "of receipts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The amount of income and profits are influenced by the type of marketing (sale on the farm, auction or by self-pickers) and by the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "No. 2243 last paragraph applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2247 Trout pond farming If no information is given on the income, the following framework rates can be used for the profits: Operating mode Framework rates Average rate Labor requirement DM / qmDM / qmVAK / ha Full operations (mainly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Edible fish production (principle: 35 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "of income) 10 - 402004 Farms (mostly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Brood fish production (principle: 40 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "of income) 4 - 401804 In individual cases, the profit can increase by up to 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "be increased or decreased"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "An increase in profit comes into consideration, in particular, if fish farming is carried out exclusively or predominantly or if table trout are largely refined into smoked trout"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "A reduction can be considered if it can be proven that losses had to be accepted due to low water inflow and poor water quality"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The above profit rates do not yet take into account wages, rent, lease and debt interest; the costs (shares) attributable to the pond management can therefore still be deducted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "225 Value in use of the apartment Reference to Section 130 a Paragraph 8 EStR 1987 In addition, it should be noted that the profit of the financial year in which the taxation of the value in use ceases to apply, including the value in use still to be assessed for part of the financial year, is to be divided proportionally in accordance with Section 4 a Paragraph 2 No. 1 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "With regard to the value in use of the apartment for the elderly, the BFH judgment of July 28, 1983 (BStBl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "1984 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "97) must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the value in use is to be attributed to the owner even in the case of real security and to be taken into account in the corresponding amount as a permanent burden in accordance with Section 10 (1) No. 1 a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "226 Lease interest paid, interest on debts, permanent encumbrances Reference is made to Section 13 a (3) sentence 2 EStG and Section 130 a (10) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Interest subsidies from public funds reduce the deductible debt interest"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Regarding the income tax treatment of the interest reduction subsidies according to the agricultural credit program see decree of FinMin NRW of 21 3 1985 S-2230 - 75 - VB 2 announced with order of 1 4 1985 S-2230 - 62 - St 113 a of the EStG are the principles of the BFH judgment of 23 June 1983 (BStBl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "1983 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "723) must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "227 Other additions and reductions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The following can be considered: additions and deductions according to \u00a7 6 c EStG, increased deductions for residential buildings according to \u00a7 7 b EStG i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "V with \u00a7 52 EStDV, insofar as the value in use taxation according to \u00a7 52 Paragraph 15 S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2 EStG will be continued Tax relief according to \u00a7 78 EStDV The increased deductions according to \u00a7 7 b EStG are to be taken into account before the tax relief of \u00a7 78 EStDV"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In the case of increased deductions according to \u00a7 7 b EStG it should be noted that the loss clause of \u00a7 7 a Paragraph 6 EStG a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "for fiscal years beginning after December 31, 1979, no longer applies"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "However, the tax relief according to \u00a7 78 EStDV may still not lead to a loss from agriculture and forestry (see \u00a7 78 Paragraph 3 EStDV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The other increased deductions according to \u00a7 7 d EStG, \u00a7\u00a7 82 a, 82 g, and 82 i EStDV and according to the Protective Building Act cannot be taken into account when determining profits according to \u00a7 13 a Paragraph 3 to 7 EStG, because with the average rates the AfA and so that the increased deductions that replace them are also generally compensated (see BFH judgment of 7 6 1984 BStBl 1984 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "663)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "However, if an asset is used in a part of the business, the full income of which is to be recorded in accordance with Section 13 a (8) EStG, increased deductions can also be taken into account when determining the profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "3 Determination of the profit on agriculture and forestry by comparing the operating income with the operating expenses (Section 4 (3) EStG) 31 Scope of application Reference is made to section 127 (3) EStR32 Determination of profitsOn section 17 EStR and reference is made to the following: 321 Average livestock values \u200b\u200bThe for accounting farmers and foresters Approved average valuation (Section 125 EStR) can also be used in accordance with Section 125 a EStR under certain conditions when determining profits according to Section 4 (3) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise reference is made to No. 441"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "322 Value in use of the apartment To determine the value in use of the apartment, reference is made to the ESt-Kartei NW \u00a7\u00a7 13 13 a EStG A No. 100"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the value in use is to be measured according to the circumstances of the individual case, even for farmers and foresters"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise, No. 225 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "4 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry through bookkeeping (Section 4 (1) EStG) 41 Scope of application On section 127 (1) EStR and on the BMF letter of 15 12 1981 BStBl 1981 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "878 (Appendix 5 to the income tax manual edition) is pointed out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Cattle surcharges are also to be taken into account when determining the economic value limit according to \u00a7 141 Paragraph 1 No. 3 AO if they are not or not yet the subject of a value update according to \u00a7\u00a7 41 i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "V with 22 para 1 no 1 BewG have been made"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "42 Opening balance sheets To review the opening balance sheets when transitioning to the comparison of business assets, reference is made to the order of 12 1 1984 S-2230 - 53 - St 113"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In the transition from the determination of profits according to \u00a7 13 a EStG to accounting, the BFH rulings of 17 3 1988 BStBl 1988 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "770 and from 14 4 1988 BStBl 1988 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "672 to be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "43 Bookkeeping On section 13 EStR and the BMF letter of 15 12 1981 a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "being point out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "44 Determination of profit 441 Average livestock values \u200b\u200bReference is made to section 125 EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The applicable average livestock values \u200b\u200bresult from the ESt-Kartei NW \u00a7\u00a7 13 13 a EStG A No. 20 For the evaluation of horses from the 1980/81 marketing year, the order of 17 7 1981 S-2132 a - 1 - St 111 ESt- Card index NRW, \u00a7\u00a7 13 13 a EStG, A No. 111)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "442 Value in use of apartment number 322 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "5 Estimate of the profit for farmers and foresters whose profit cannot be determined according to average rates51 General For farmers and foresters who are obliged to keep accounts but do not keep proper books, the profit is to be estimated in individual cases according to \u00a7 162 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to those farmers and foresters who are neither obliged to keep accounts nor meet the requirements of Section 13 a Paragraph 1 No. 2 and 3 EStG, if they do not keep books within the meaning of Section 4 Paragraph 1 EStG and also the operating income and - have not recorded expenditures within the meaning of Section 4 Paragraph 3 EStG (Section 127 Paragraph 2 - 4 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The estimate has - with the exception of the in Section 127 Paragraph 4 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "6, second half-sentence of the EStR - to be carried out in accordance with the principles of Section 4 (1) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "When making the estimate, all circumstances that are important for the estimate must be taken into account (Section 162 (1) sentence 2 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The aim of the estimate must be to determine the profit actually achieved"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The uncertainties inherent in an estimate are, however, at the expense of the taxpayer, who himself gave cause for the estimate by neglecting his tax cooperation obligations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "It must also be ensured that farmers who are required to keep accounts and whose profits are estimated are reported to the tax auditors if an examination appears to be suitable to encourage the farmer to keep accounts or if the examination promises success for other reasons"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "If a tax audit is planned in this sense, the assessment is to be carried out subject to the review (Section 164 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise, the procedure is in accordance with Section 14 (1) ALDA-FEST"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The following explanatory text must be included in the notification or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "to be attached as an attachment: \"The profit from agriculture and forestry for the financial year 19"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "/ 19th"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "was estimated according to \u00a7 162 AO because you did not declare your winnings or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "because you declared a profit that was not determined by bookkeeping, although you are obliged to keep the books"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "If you actually achieved a higher profit than the estimated, the tax would have been set too low"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In this case, there may be tax evasion or a frivolous tax reduction"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "However, you can then by declaring the actual profit under the further requirements of \u00a7\u00a7 371 378 Paragraph 3 AO criminal or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Obtain no fines"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Furthermore, I would like to point out that failure to comply with the accounting obligation can already result in a tax risk"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "\"52 Estimation of the profit according to standard rates Which estimation method is to be used in the individual case is left to the discretion of the tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "If, in individual cases, an estimation method tailored to the particular operational conditions is not to be preferred, or if there are no circumstances particularly influencing the operating result, such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Seed propagation or field vegetable cultivation exist or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "have been determined in the course of a previous tax audit and accounting results of comparable companies or empirical records are not available, the profit is to be estimated according to the principles of \u00a7 4 Paragraph 1 EStG as follows; starting amount (No. 521) + rental income (No. 522) + surcharges for winnings or winnings not paid for with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits (no.523) + value in use of the apartment (no.524)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Wage expenses (No. 525)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Lease expenses, interest on debt, permanent burdens (No. 526) +"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Other surcharges and reductions (No. 527) = profit for the financial year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The guideline rates listed below are intended as a guide for an accurate estimate of the profit (Section 127, Paragraph 2, p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "At the same time, a reduction in the estimated profit due to objections to individual points in the valuation process is generally out of the question because special circumstances in an individual branch of the business do not allow any conclusions to be drawn about the profit of the entire business"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The application of the standard rates must not lead to an obviously incorrect taxation (see BFH judgment of 16 12 1965 BStBl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "1966 III p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "193)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In detail, the following should be observed when estimating profits according to standard rates: 521 Starting amount The starting amount per hectare of usable agricultural area for the 1987/1988 financial year is: 1for pasture farming (71% of grassland)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "and more of the LN) 1400 DM2 for mixed farms (grassland share 31 to 70 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "der LN) with a root crop content of a) less than 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "the LN1400 DMb) 15 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "and more of the LN1500 DMc) If the root crop content is more than 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "the LN and is in it a sugar beet content of more than 20%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "the LN, the starting amount increases to 2000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "d) If the root crop content exceeds a total of 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "of the LN, are each started 5 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The additional amount of root crops should be added to the above starting amounts of 200 DM each"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "3In arable farms (proportion of grassland up to 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "der LN) with a root crop content of a) less than 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "the LN1400 DMb) 15 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "and more of LN1600 DMc) No. 2 c) and 2 d) apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "4In the case of dairy cow husbandry, the starting amounts (No. 1-3) are to be increased according to the average dairy cow herd of the farm as follows: a) less than 05 cows / ha LN200 DMb) 05 to less than 1 cows / ha LN300 DMc) 1 to less than 15 cows / ha LN400 DMd) 15 and more cows / ha LN600 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "With regard to the increase in the starting amounts to be made in cases of repeated profit estimates from the 1983/1984 financial year by a safety surcharge of up to a maximum of 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "reference is made to the order of 5 4 1983 S-2150 a - 2 - St 113"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The surcharge is not to be shown separately, but to be incorporated into the starting amounts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Only the pure agricultural production areas belong to the agricultural use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Areas for buildings, courtyards, paths, ditches, field borders, water, land, quarries, sand pits, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Areas are therefore not considered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Areas for house gardens are also not included"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise, Section 124 a Paragraph 3 EStR applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "For the calculation of the relevant root crop, grassland or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Sugar beet share depends on the size of these shares in the respective marketing year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The areas under cultivation of root crops do not include those areas on which root crops are only grown as catch crops or as catch crops"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Only the meadows and pastures listed in No. 5232 are to be regarded as grassland; the other crops mentioned there (fodder plants) belong to field forage cultivation, the areas of which belong to the field"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "522 Lease income Lease income, ground rent and hunting leases, reduced by proportionate operating expenses, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Property taxes are to be added to the starting amount if they are included in income from agriculture and forestry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "This is the case when the leased or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Hereditary assets belong to the lessor's agricultural and forestry business assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "523 Surcharges for winnings or winnings not settled with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "All profits from sustainable or one-off operating income that are not included in the starting amount are to be added to the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Such surcharges come z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Consideration for additional profits from sales of breeding cattle and other valuable animals, profits from abnormal animal husbandry, additional profits from special crops, profits from other special business branches (see \"Special operating income\" on p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "4 of Annex L), profits from the withdrawal and sale of land (see \"Sale / withdrawal of land\" on page 2 of Annex L), profits from the rental of living space belonging to the BV"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "5231 Sales of breeding cattle and other valuable animals As additional profit from the sale of breeding cattle and other valuable animals, the amounts by which the individual sales proceeds including sales tax exceed the following values: Breeding bulls DM 3400 Breeding cows and cattle DM 2600 Breeding oars DM 900 Breeding sows DM 800"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "For breeding and riding horses, the additional profit is 60 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "the amount by which the selling price exceeds the value of 6000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "If sales proceeds of more than DM 13,000 are achieved, the full amount of DM 8,800 (DM 6,000 plus 40 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "of 7000 DM)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Wages for paid workers as well as selling costs (auction fees, insurance contributions, transport costs, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": ") are taken into account in the amount of the above values, so they cannot be deducted separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The additional profit has to be calculated individually for each animal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "A netting with sales proceeds that are below the above values \u200b\u200bmay not be carried out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The same procedure is to be followed if above-average prices are achieved for breeding animals other than those specified or for other valuable animals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The value to be used in these cases results from the tax production costs of the animal species in question plus an assumed profit surcharge of 20% included in the initial value for the area with normal animal husbandry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "5232 Abnormal animal husbandry Profits from animal breeding and husbandry are settled with the starting amount (No. 521), provided that the average normal animal population is not exceeded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The animal husbandry paid for with the starting amount is to be set for the area of \u200b\u200bthe regional finance office in Cologne for forage production operations, other operations for the first 20 ha LN22 VE / ha14 VE / ha for the next 10 ha LN16 VE / ha08 VE / haf for the next 20 ha LN15 VE / ha07 VE / ha over 50 ha LN total maximum of 90 VE 50 VE The animal husbandry in VE that is covered by the starting amount can also be found in the overview attached as Annex 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Forage farms are farms where the forage area is 60 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "and more of the usable agricultural area without courtyard and building space, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "matters"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In this context, the forage area includes: Meadows (incl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Tree meadows, litter meadows), cattle pastures and arable meadows, as well as the cultivation areas for clover in pure seed and mixed cultivation, grass clover, alfalfa, seradella, sainfin, green corn, vetches, sweet lupins and all other forage plants"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Areas on which grain is grown for grain production are not included in the forage area even if the grain is fed to the livestock kept on the farm"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "When calculating the number of animals and converting them into livestock units, the procedure is in accordance with Section 124 a, Paragraph 2 of the Income Tax Regulation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The average herds (lines 79 to 85 of Appendix L) and the animals produced (lines 86 to 92 of Appendix L) are to be summarized"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Care must be taken that no animals are recorded twice"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "For the excess inventory remaining after the normal inventory has been taken into account, the profit for the 1987/1988 financial year is 300 DM / VE"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Wages are not taken into account here and can therefore still be deducted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "5233 Field vegetable cultivation (agricultural use) Field vegetable cultivation is understood to mean the cultivation of vegetables according to agricultural cultivation methods within the framework of agricultural crop rotation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "A distinction must be made between field vegetable cultivation in annual cultivation and field vegetable cultivation as a replica"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Additional profit not settled with the starting amount (No. 521) is to be set for the 1987/1988 marketing year: For field vegetable cultivation in annual cultivation: 7,000 DM per hectare minus the amount per hectare per hectare stated in the starting amount for this area, as a replica: 5,000 DM per hectare ( without reduction)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "It is up to the taxpayer to provide evidence of the actual proceeds from field vegetable growing"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In these cases, a discount of 25 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "be acknowledged"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The remaining amount is only to be reduced in the case of field vegetable cultivation in annual cultivation by the amount per hectare / UI set in the starting amount for this area"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The above standard rates do not take into account wages and can therefore be deducted separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "5234 Vegetable growing (horticultural use), fruit growing, asparagus and strawberry growing as well as trout pond farming Nos. 2243 to 2247 apply accordingly for the determination of the profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "As a surcharge on the starting amount, however, only the additional profit, i.e."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "the profit reduced by the pro-rata starting amount applied in the individual case"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "524 Value in use of apartment number 322 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "When estimating the profit, the gross value in use must always be applied, because the expenses associated with the apartment - with the exception of interest on debt (No. 526) and the increased deductions (No. 527) - are taken into account when determining the starting amounts (No. 521) and are thus compensated are"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "525 Wage expenses The starting amount (No. 521) is based on the assumption that the business is managed exclusively with unpaid workers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Wage expenses are therefore to be deducted from the starting amount insofar as they relate to the profits settled with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The treatment of wage expenses incurred with profits or income not paid for in the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits (see No. 523) are related to the respective surcharge regulations (see No. 5231 to 5235)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "For the distribution of wage expenses required in individual cases, No. 222 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2 and 3 apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The wage expenses to be deducted also include the expenses for short-term temporary workers as well as for the workers who are"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Contractors have been made available for certain ordering, maintenance or harvesting work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "If wage expenses in connection with machine expenses are invoiced in one sum by contractors, there are generally no concerns that the proportionate wage expenses to be taken into account at 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "appreciate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "If wage expenses cannot be proven, an estimate e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "possible according to documents from comparable companies"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Because of the need to notify the income tax office in such cases, reference is made to No. 62 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "c) pointed out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "526 Lease expenses, debt interest, permanent charges Such expenses can be deducted if they are operating expenses and have not already been taken into account when determining the surcharges according to No. 523"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The lease payments then attributable to the profit settled with the starting amount are not fully deductible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The lease also covers expenses that are already included in the starting amount as operating expenses (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Property tax, apportionment of the Chamber of Agriculture)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The lease payments are therefore to be reduced by the amount contained therein, which is allotted to such expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "There are no concerns about reducing this amount to 10 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "to estimate the rent payments"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In special individual cases, it may be justified to reduce the amount to 5 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "lower if excessive and no longer local rent is paid"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "527 Other surcharges and reductions 527 Allocation due to building depreciation in the case of profit estimation When calculating the starting amount, the deductions for wear and tear from the value of the business buildings are taken into account in accordance with \u00a7 7 EStG, because it is assumed that the business is managed by the owner himself"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In cases of leasing or free leasing of agricultural operations in whole or in part of a business with buildings, the depreciation for the business buildings is available to the lessor or the lessor"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "to the farmer leaving the property free of charge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In the case of the authorized user, the starting amount must therefore be increased by 100 DM / ha of leased LN"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "It is up to the tenant to prove the AfA in detail"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "5272 Increased deductions for residential buildings, insofar as the value in use taxation according to \u00a7 52 Paragraph 15 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2 EStG is continued"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "increased deductions for residential buildings according to \u00a7 7 b EStG and increased deductions according to \u00a7\u00a7 82 a, 82 g and 82 i EStDV into consideration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "These increased deductions are, however, by the depreciation already taken into account in the starting amount according to \u00a7 7 Abs 4 EStG in the amount of 2 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "to shorten"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "5273 Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV can be deducted from the starting amount if the register is kept according to \u00a7 7 a Paragraph 8 EStG (cf. order of 27 5 1981 S-2184 - 7 - St 111)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In these cases I ask you to request the directory and to attach a copy of the income tax file"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "After the beneficial period of three financial years has expired, the starting amount must be increased by a surcharge when claiming the preferential treatment in accordance with \u00a7 76 EStDV, since according to \u00a7 7 a (9) EStG the residual value is the assessment basis for further deductions for wear and tear and otherwise by applying the starting amount excessive depreciation amounts would be taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The surcharge for a financial year results from the sum of the special depreciation granted divided by the remaining useful life of the respective asset"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The initial amount must be increased for the remaining period of use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In order to ensure that this surcharge is also taken into account in future assessments, the control sheet for profit surcharges (Section 76 EStDV), form no. 724/49, must be kept and attached to the income tax file"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "6 Other 61 Retirement benefits 612 For cashless retirement benefits, the following values \u200b\u200bcan be used as a basis for Vz 1987 without individual proof: for meals with a retirement divider 3030 DM with a retired couple 5450 DM for heating and lighting 630 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "With regard to the value for heating and lighting, however, there are no concerns, requests from taxpayers to apply the pro rata, based on the energy bills or similar"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "the actual costs determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "613 If partial retirement benefits do not only consist of benefits in kind and in kind due to farm handover agreements between parents and children, it must be checked in each individual case whether the individual partial benefits are life annuities or permanent burdens (recurring payments)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Because of the transitional regulation in existing retirement contracts see ESt-Kartei NW, \u00a7 10 Abs 1 u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "2 EStG, A No. 147 If the value-in-use taxation ceases to apply on December 31, 1987, the pensioner obliged to deduct the value in use of the apartment up to that point in full in the 1987 calendar year as special expenses, even though he or she, in accordance with Section 4 a (2) No. 1 EStG only has to pay tax on part of the value in use in the calendar year 1988 (see No. 225)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "62 Control notifications Except in the usual cases (control notifications for the purposes of the Bp, the recording of taxable transactions with other taxpayers, inheritance tax), control notifications are to be prepared in the following cases in particular: The assessment body responsible in each individual case is to be informed of the taxpayer's or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "to disclose circumstances arising from the files that may affect the level of the fixed unit values \u200b\u200b(e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Change in areas for special use, changes in animal populations - see also order of 4 10 1977 S-3122 - 4 - St 241)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Information that may be of importance for an award according to \u00a7 41 BewG is summarized on page 4 of Annex L."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "I therefore ask in all cases in which the livestock declared in Annex L obviously exceeds or exceeds the animal population customary in the area"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "in which, for other reasons, a surcharge according to \u00a7 41 BewG may be considered, the assessment body can be informed by sending a copy of page 4 of Annex L."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Are access or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Leases known, so the lessor or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Inform the leaseholder of the competent assessment office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to the transfer of use free of charge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "This can be done in accordance with No. 3 of the order of 4 2 1981 S-2230 - 46 - St 111"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "For the rest, I ask you to ensure that the taxpayers on page 2 of Annex L the address of the lessee / lessor, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "specify exactly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "In particular, cases without signal \"A\", in which wage expenses are claimed, and cases with significant wage expenses are to be reported to the responsible wage tax office for examination by the wage tax field audit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "This also applies if wage expenses are set at an estimated amount when determining the profit (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "No. 525 section 4)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "63 Standard value notifications Unit value notifications for agricultural and forestry assets must always be evaluated promptly, particularly because of the possible effects on the way in which the taxpayer's profit is determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "64 Consultation of the valuation files when carrying out the assessment In particular when determining profits in accordance with Section 13 a of the Income Tax Act (EStG) and in valuation cases, I ask that you refer to the assessment files for the assessment and review of the values \u200b\u200bto be applied in the individual case when calculating profits"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "65 Review of the Annex L According to \u00a7 150 Para. 1 and 2 AO, book-keeping farmers are also obliged to fill out tax returns including the annexes and thus in particular also Annex L completely and truthfully"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "This applies in particular to the area data in lines 32 to 50 of Annex L, which are not only indispensable for the taxation of valuation farmers, but also"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "also serve to check the applicable profit determination method, to test profits and to be able to monitor value updates"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The section \"Sale / Withdrawal of Land\" contains the essential basic information required to examine profits from sales and withdrawals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "If the required information can be clearly found in the individual case from the balance sheet or similar documents, a reference in Annex L to the relevant documents is sufficient"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The information on p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "4 to the livestock is for the demarcation of the agricultural from the commercial animal breeding or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "Animal husbandry, for checking the accounting requirements and, if necessary,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "the applicable type of profit determination is important"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "I would therefore ask you to work towards ensuring that farmers and foresters who keep books also fill out Appendix L in full in future"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "If this does not happen, the system must be returned for the purpose of completion"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "It should be advisable to advise consultants who, to the knowledge of the tax office, look after farmers and foresters to a large extent, in good time before submitting their next tax returns, of the requirement to fill out Annex L in full"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "The plants were not included"}, {"meta": {"name": "0089052.xml"}, "text": "--- Income tax / wage tax / church tax Accounting North Rhine-Westphalia Agriculture Farmers Agriculture"}]