[{"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion Koblenz S-2230 A - St 34 2 S-2230 S-2230EStG: 13EStG: 13aEStG: 13/1 / 2EStG: 13/1 / 3EStG: 13/2 / 2EStG: 13a / 2 / 2EStG: 13a / 3 / 4EStG: 13a / 7EStG: 13a / 8EStG: 14aEStG: 14 / 4EStG: 14 / 5EStG: 4 / 1EStG: 4 / 3EStG: 7a / 8EStG: 7a / 9EStG: 7bEStG: 34bEStG: 52/15 / 4EStG: 52 / 17EStR: 127 / 4EStR: 124aEStR: 135 / 4EStR: 212 / 1EStDV: 76EStDV: 82aEStDV: 82gEStDV: 82iAO: 140AO: 141 / 1AO: 141/2 Income taxation of farmers and foresters for the calendar year 1987 1 Book-keeping farmers and foresters 11 Accounting obligation 12 Livestock for personal consumption and food 14 Assessment of plant stocks in tree nurseries 15 Treatment of rental and commercial buildings as arbitrary business assets 16 Value in use of the apartment 2 Determination of profit by comparing the operating income with the operating expenses 21 General 22 Average livestock values \u200b\u200b23 Value in use of the apartment 24 Maintaining the special directory according to \u00a7 7a para 8 EStG 3 Valuation farmers 31 General 32 Management of the special Verzeic 7a (8) EStG 33 Estimation of profits according to standard rates 34 Sales standard rates 35 Form 4 Determination of profits according to average rates (Section 13a EStG) 41 General 42 Profits from special uses 43 Profits from other operations 5 Other 51 Determination of capital gains - land gain taxation 52 Retirement benefits 53 Delimitation of the commercial enterprise in relation to agriculture and forestry 54 Simplification regulation for farm handovers to family members within a financial year 55 Lease of agricultural and forestry farms per parcel 56 Forestry 57 Control notifications 58 Changes to the Income Tax Act by the Tax Reform Act 1990 which were already applied to income tax assessment or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Determination of profits for calendar years before 1990 must be observed 1 Book-keeping farmers and foresters 11 Bookkeeping obligation The bookkeeping obligation is subject to farmers and foresters who manage an agricultural and forestry business as owners, tenants, usufructuary or other beneficial owners, as well as lessors who run a business as a whole have leased but not given up if the requirements of Section 140 AO are met or one of the accounting limits set out in Section 141 Paragraph 1 AO is exceeded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "When making the assessment, care must be taken to ensure that businesses that are required to keep accounts in accordance with Section 141 (1) AO are informed in good time of the start of the accounting obligation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "If the accounting obligation is no longer required, Section 141 (2) AO does not provide for a formal notification, but in these cases a corresponding note in the tax assessment or a special notification is considered appropriate for reasons of legal certainty"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "For the rest, reference is made to the following instructions regarding the accounting obligation in agricultural and forestry operations: Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "vom 18 12 80 - S-2230 / S-0311 A - St 34 2 / St 42 1 - No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "1 - Rdvfgen vom 27 4 and 26 5 81 - S-2230 A - St 34 2 - ESt-Kartei: Map 7 and \u00a7 13 - No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "5 - Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "vom 13 1 82 - S-0311 / S-2163 A - St 42 1 - Tz"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "1 and 2 - ESt-Kartei: Map 15 to \u00a7 13 Section 127 EStR 1987 12 Livestock assessment For the assessment of livestock - with the exception of horses - those with Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "of 26 5 67 - S-2132 a A - St 32 2 - established average values"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "For horses acquired by the taxpayer or born in the taxpayer's business after the beginning of the 1980/81 financial year, the horses listed in the Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "vom 24 3 81 - S-2132 a A - St 34 2 - ESt-Kartei: card 6 to \u00a7 13 - contained values \u200b\u200bare decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Incidentally also Section 125 EStR 1987 13 lump sums for personal consumption and meals The last with my Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "vom 8 3 82 - S-2132 a A - St 34 2 - ESt-Kartei: Map 1a to \u00a7 13 - fixed lump sums for own consumption and the meals at book-keeping farmers were checked within the scope of this year's surveys"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "It was found that generally applicable lump sums that can be used on a broad basis in practice can no longer be determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "This is primarily due to the fact that, due to the specialization of the farms in certain branches of production, the earlier, extensive self-sufficiency of the peasant family is almost no longer to be found today"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The ones with o"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The fixed lump sums are therefore to be applied for the last time for the 1986/87 marketing year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "I ask, o"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "and to attach a corresponding handwritten note to card 1a for section 13 of the income tax card"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "14 Evaluation of plant stocks in tree nurseries For the assessment of plant stocks in tree nurseries, the in the Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "vom 23 5 86 - S-2163 A - St 34 2 - ESt-Kartei: Map 2a to \u00a7 13 - approved simplification regulations essential"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "15 Treatment of rental and commercial buildings as voluntary business assets The decision as to whether a bookkeeping farmer and forestry manager can treat a property as voluntary business assets on which a residential and commercial building is to be built for the purpose of renting out to third parties is based on the information in Sect. 14 Paragraph 3 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "5-6 EStR 1987 to meet the principles laid down"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "16 Value in use of the apartment 161 General The income from agriculture and forestry includes until the last application of Section 13 Paragraph 2 No. 2 EStG (reference to Section 52 Paragraph 15 EStG and the Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "vom 21 11 86 - S-2236 A - St 31 1 - ESt-Kartei: card 3 to \u00a7 52 EStG) also the value in use of the taxpayer's apartment, if the apartment does not exceed the size usual for businesses of the same type"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The profit of the financial year in which the value-in-use taxation ceases to apply, including the value in use still to be assessed for part of the financial year, is to be divided proportionally in accordance with Section 4a (2) No. 1 of the Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The rental value is to be regularly estimated in analogous application of Section 8 (2) EStG, whereby the local average rent for apartments of a comparable type, location and equipment (market rent) is decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "If the rental value is determined according to the rent index drawn up by the tax office,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "still to take into account the rural conditions accordingly, as far as these have not yet been given special consideration in the rent index"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "In addition, agricultural holdings in the narrower sense (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "regularly not in the case of special uses) by the BFH jurisprudence (judgments of 30 1 74 - BStBl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "1974 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "608 of 30 1 74 - BStBl 1975 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "3 and from 28 3 74 - BStBl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "1975 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "9) to undertake approved deductions from the rental value, provided these have not yet been reflected in the rent index"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Deductions are regularly considered because of the general value-reducing factors resulting from membership in agriculture (20 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": ") and because of the special circumstances impairing the value of the individual case (up to 30 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The general discount of 20%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "of the rental value customary in the area is not to be made in the case of businesses with special uses, wine-growing or horticultural businesses in a normal location (see Section II No. 17 of the Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "vom 8 9 87 - S-2319 A - St 31 1)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "In addition, reference is made to Section 130 a Paragraph 8 EStR 1987"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "162 Fair measure for 1986 in the event of an application for the abolition of the value-in-use taxation in accordance with Section 52 (15) sentence 4 EStG The highest tax authorities have decided that farmers and foresters who, by the query in line 60 of Annex L to the 1986 income tax return, should be allowed before the end of the 1987 calendar year have made a decision on the continuation or discontinuation of the value-in-use taxation until the tax assessment for 1987 becomes final; the tax assessment for 1986 is possibly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "to change according to \u00a7 174 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "2 Determination of profits by comparing operating income with operating expenses 21 General Because of the scope of the determination of profits according to Section 4 Paragraph 3 EStG, I refer to Section 127 Paragraph 3 EStR 1987 (cf. a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Section 17 EStR 1987)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "22 Average livestock values \u200b\u200bThe average assessment permitted for bookkeeping farmers and foresters (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "12) can also be used in accordance with Section 125 a of the Income Tax Act 1987 under certain conditions when determining profits in accordance with Section 4 Paragraph 3 Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "23 Value in use of the apartment In the cases of Section 4 (3) EStG, the value in use of the apartment is to be determined in accordance with the principles applicable to accounting operations (see Sect"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "24 Maintaining the special register in accordance with Section 7a, Paragraph 8 of the Income Tax Act When determining profits in accordance with Section 4, Paragraph 3 of the Income Tax Act, special depreciation in accordance with Section 76 of the EStDV is permitted for the first time for the depreciable assets acquired or manufactured in accordance with Section 26 6 82; their use requires records in accordance with Section 7a (8) of the Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "These records in the special directory named in Section 7a (8) of the Income Tax Act must be made at the latest by the submission of the tax return for the financial year in which the beneficial asset was acquired or manufactured"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "It is not sufficient if the directory is only available at the time of a later application after submitting the tax return, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "a later tax audit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "3 Appraisal farmers 31 General In the case of farmers and foresters who are obliged to keep accounts but do not keep proper books, the profit must be estimated in individual cases in accordance with Section 162 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to those farmers and foresters who are not obliged to keep accounts nor meet the requirements of Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 2 and 3 EStG if they do not have any books in the sense of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 4 Abs 1 EStG and also the operating income and expenses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "of Section 4 Paragraph 3 EStG (Section 127 Paragraph 2 - 4 EStR 1987)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The estimate has - with the exception of the in Section 127 Paragraph 4 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "6 second half-sentence of the EStR 1987 - to be carried out according to the principles of Section 4 (1) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "When making the estimate, all circumstances must be taken into account that are important for the estimate in individual cases (Section 162 (1) sentence 2 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The aim of the estimate must be to determine the profit actually achieved"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Of several possible estimation methods (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Asset growth calculation, total monetary transaction calculation or estimate based on the results of similar accounting operations) is therefore the one that comes closest to the result that would have been shown in proper accounting"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "In doing so, preference should always be given to the method that best takes into account the particular operational conditions of the individual case"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The uncertainties inherent in an estimate are, however, at the expense of the taxpayer, who himself gave cause for the estimate by neglecting his tax cooperation obligations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "It is important to ensure that farmers who are required to keep accounts and whose profit is estimated are to be reported to the tax auditor if an audit appears suitable or promises success for other reasons"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "This applies in particular to all agricultural businesses that have fulfilled their accounting obligations for some time, then no longer keep books and allow themselves to be valued"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "If a tax audit is planned in these cases, the assessment must be carried out subject to the review (Section 164 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "32 Maintaining the special register in accordance with Section 7a (8) of the Income Tax Act (EStG) Insofar as agricultural operations that are required to keep accounts and do not keep books use special depreciation in accordance with Article 76 of the Income Tax Act (EStDV), the time at which the special register in accordance with Article 7a (8) of the EStG Tz"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "24 to be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "33 Estimation of the profit according to standard rates It is basically left to the discretion of the tax office which estimation method it uses in the individual case"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "As a rule, however, the profit will have to be estimated based on the results of similar accounting operations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The basis for this is a modified guideline rate estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "If, in individual cases, an estimate tailored to the particular operational conditions is not to be preferred or other empirical rates are not available, the profit can be estimated as follows: Initial estimate (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "331) Lease income (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "332) Surcharges for profits or profits not settled with the initial estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "333) Value in use of the apartment (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "334) Wage expenses (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "335) Lease expenses, interest on debts, permanent encumbrances (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "336) + - Other surcharges and reductions (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "337) ------------------------------------------------ - = Profit for the financial year However, the profit estimate using this method must not lead to an obviously incorrect taxation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Are there any doubts as to whether the type of operation, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "In the case of processing operations or operations with sugar beet cultivation, an accurate profit estimate in this form is even possible, I ask you to call in the agricultural audit or the responsible official agricultural expert (ALS)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "331 Starting estimate amount When determining the starting estimate amount, a distinction is made - as before - between the following areas: Area I: Rheinpfalz and Rheinhessen (both the Rhine plain), Koblenz-Neuwied basin, Maifeld and Grafschaft Area II: all other areas As the starting estimate amount per hectare of agricultural land ( LN) are to be set for the 1987/88 marketing year: Estimated starting amounts per hectare / LN area forage cultivation area in v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "the LN to 30 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "30-60 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "about 60 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "DMDMDMIa) 140010001300b) 1900c) 1400c) 1900d) 1800d) 2300II9009001100c) 1200c) 1700d) 1600d) 2100 Sales guide values \u200b\u200bper hectare / LN areaFodder cultivation area in v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "the LN to 30 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "30-60 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "about 60 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "DMDMDMIa) 350040004300b) 5000c) 4300c) 4700d) 4700d) 5000II370037004300c) 4100c) 4700d) 4500d) 5000 Comments: a) with predominantly cereal cultivation b) with predominantly root crop cultivation c) with fattening cattle d) with dairy farming over 40%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "of the cattle herd A surcharge to the operating income for the cultivation of new potatoes is for the Wj"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "1987/88 not required"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "For farms with poor soil conditions and / or in climatically unfavorable locations, a discount of up to 20% from the initial estimate can be made upon request"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "be made"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The relevant ALS must check the requirements for such a discount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The utilized agricultural area relevant for the estimate only includes the pure agricultural production areas including leases"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Areas for buildings, courtyards, house gardens, paths, ditches, field edges, forestry, tobacco-growing, horticultural, fruit-growing or viticultural areas, as well as areas used for mining, low-lying, unpaved land and similar areas are not taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "A quarter of hats and half of fruit-growing areas with regular agricultural underuse are to be considered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "If vegetables are grown as catch crops or catch crops, the corresponding areas are not to be excluded from the calculation of the relevant agricultural area because there is double use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "For the extent of the forage cultivation area, I refer to No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "3334 332 Lease income Lease income, ground rent and hunting leases, reduced by proportionate operating expenses, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Property taxes must be added to the initial estimate if they are included in income from agriculture and forestry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "This is the case when the leased or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Hereditary assets belong to the lessor's agricultural and forestry business assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "333 Surcharges for profits or profits not settled with the initial estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits All profits from sustainable or one-off operating income that are not included in the initial estimate are to be added to the initial estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Such surcharges come z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Consideration for profits from the extraction and sale of property areas Profits from viticulture Profits from fruit and vegetable production Profits from closure and severance distilleries Profits from tobacco production Profits from other special branches Profits from secondary operations Profits from abnormal animal husbandry Extra profits from breeding cattle sales I would also like to point out the following : 3331 Removal and sale of land cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "also note"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "51 u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "582 3332 Viticulture, fruit and vegetable growing as well as distilleries For the determination of the corresponding profits I refer to the information given in No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "42 circulars mentioned"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "3333 Tobacco growing According to the determinations made, the harvest yields in the Palatinate growing area have developed as follows (1 dt = 100 kg): Wj"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Cultivation area yield German"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Monetary value DM net harvest dt / haPreis DM / dt net taking DM / ha nettoGesamtanbau1985 / 8611603637828332224314778244241986/8712503295623934942264726191451987 / 8812202722720464338223175216769Geudertheimer (Zigarrengut) 1985/867812537418276760325720234011986/878392234814968186266669178321987 / 888071852812881154229769515956Burley (material to be cut) 1985/86357105369624585295913269601986/8736897188219742263845222761987 / 8836678126777439213386718504Virgin1985 / 8622468430879213921195851986/8742889747014213839178751987 / 88472388585805743187690917060Die harvest was through wetness and temperatures that are too low are very low"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "In contrast, the quality of the 1987 harvest was good"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Damage from hail led to partial total failures in the municipality of H\u00f6rdt"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The income from hail insurance compensation is not included in the income listed above"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "As in previous years, 9200 DM per hectare of cultivation area can be taken into account in the 1987/88 financial year to compensate for the actual construction costs"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "3334 Abnormal animal husbandry Profits from animal breeding and husbandry are settled with the estimated starting amount, provided that the average normal animal population is not exceeded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The normal livestock population in livestock units (VE) for other farms for the first 20 ha LN22 VE / ha14 VE / ha for the next 10 ha LN16 VE / ha08 VE / ha for the next 20 ha LN15 VE / ha07 VE / hamit more than 50 ha LN at most 90 VE50 VEF forage-growing operations are businesses where the forage area is 60%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "and more of the LN"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The forage area includes: Meadows, arable meadows, tree meadows, litter meadows, pastures, cultivation areas for grass clover, alfalfa, seradella, saspars, green corn, vetches, sweet lupins, silage corn, fodder beet, clover in pure seed and mixed cultivation and all other forage crops"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "When calculating the number of animals and converting them into VE, the procedure is in accordance with Section 124a EStR 1987"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "For the remaining after deduction of the normal inventory excess inventory is to be set for the 1987/88 marketing year as profit: beiDM / VERindviehhaltung1250Stallmast of Kaelbern690Stallmast of calves (payroll process) 195Mastschweineverkauf180Laeuferverkauf400Ferkelverkauf550Legehennen eggs sale Grosshandel0Legehennen eggs sale Einzelhandel1080Aufzucht of Junghennen830Junggefluegelmast280Entenmast750Putenmast1950Gaensemast2550Darauf attributable wages are not taken into account and therefore can be up or set down"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "When determining the abnormal animal husbandry and calculating the corresponding surcharge to the initial estimate, please contact the responsible ALS"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "3335 Sales of breeding cattle Regarding the determination of the additional profits from sales of breeding cattle, No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "43 accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "3336 payments for the abandonment of milk production or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "the shutdown and suspension of delivery of reference quantities the income tax treatment of payments for the abandonment of milk production or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The shutdown and suspension of delivery of reference quantities was most recently regulated by the Rdvfgen of 20 1 88 and 12 4 88 - S-2132 A - St 34 2 - ESt-Kartei: cards 18 c and d to \u00a7 13"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Corresponding fees are to be determined in individual cases on the basis of the relevant documents and added to the initial estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "334 Value in use of the apartment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "16 to determine the principles contained"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The (gross) rental value is always to be applied, because in the profit estimate the expenses associated with the apartment - with the exception of debt interest (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "336) and the increased deductions (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "3372) - when determining the estimated starting amounts (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "331) are taken into account and thus paid for"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "335 Wage expenses For the initial estimate (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "331) it is assumed that the company is managed exclusively with unpaid workers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Wage expenses are therefore to be deducted from the initial estimate insofar as they relate to the profit settled with the initial estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "If profits are recorded as a surcharge through individual calculation, care must be taken to ensure that any proportionate wage expenditure is not recorded twice (cf. in particular no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "3332 and 3333)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "336 Lease expenses, interest owed, permanent charges These expenses can be deducted insofar as they represent operating expenses and have not already been taken into account in a surcharge calculation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "337 other surcharges and reductions 3371 other surcharges"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Expert fees, breeding premiums, profits from the sale of fixed assets, profits from participation in cooperatives, stud fee income, feed money income, wages and remuneration for other services)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Insofar as such facts are determined in individual cases - especially in the context of company audits -"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "to make a profit surcharge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "3372 Increased deductions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "increased deductions for residential buildings according to \u00a7 7b EStG and increased deductions according to \u00a7\u00a7 82a, 82g and 82i EStDV"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "As far as increased deductions are used, the profit must be increased again by the depreciation already taken into account in the initial estimate according to Section 7 (4) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "3373 Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV can also be deducted from the initial estimate if the relevant requirements are met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "However, after the benefit period of three financial years has expired, the initial estimate must be increased by a surcharge, as, in accordance with Section 7a (9) of the Income Tax Act, the residual value is the assessment basis for further deductions for wear and tear and otherwise excessive depreciation amounts would otherwise be taken into account by applying the initial estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The surcharge for a financial year results from the total of the special depreciation granted divided by the remaining useful life of the respective asset"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The increase in the estimated amount must be carried out for the period of the remaining useful life"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "When using the preferential treatment for immovable assets with a useful life of more than 30 years as well as for conversions and extensions to these assets, a correction is not necessary in view of Section 76 (4) sentence 3 EStDV for reasons of simplification"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "In order to ensure that the surcharges are also taken into account in future assessments, the control sheet on form no. \"ESt 7\" must be kept and attached to the income tax files"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "34 Standard sales rates The standard sales rates applicable for the 1987/88 financial year are set out in paragraph"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "331 printed overview of the estimated starting amounts for the respective types of business"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "35 Form For the profit estimation according to the method described in paragraph"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "33 is available to the tax offices using the \"ESt 6\" form"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "4 Determination of profits according to average rates (\u00a7 13a EStG) 41 General A determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry according to the average rates of \u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 to 8 EStG n"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "is to be carried out for the first time for financial years beginning after 30 6 80"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "For further details, I refer to the following arrangements: Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "vom 18 12 80 - S-2230 / S-0311 A - St 34 2 / St 42 1 - No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "2 - Rdvfgen vom 27 4 and 26 5 81 - S-2230 A - St 34 2 - ESt-Kartei: Map 7 to \u00a7 13 - No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "2 - Sections 127 and 130 a of the 1987 EStR In the assessment, particular attention must be paid to the fact that the relevant taxpayers are informed in good time if the prerequisites for determining profits according to average rates cease to exist (Section 13a (1) sentence 2 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The scheme for the determination of the profit according to \u00a7 13a Abs 3 to 8 EStG results from the form \"Appendix ESt 2L / 3L (88) - Determination of profit according to \u00a7 13a EStG\""}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "42 Profits from special uses Pursuant to Section 13a (8) No. 1 EStG, profits from special uses must also be included in the average rate under the conditions specified there"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Any loss resulting from Section 13a (8) of the Income Tax Act (EStG) must be offset against the average rate profit in accordance with Section 13a (3) to (7) of the Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The exemption of max"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "3000 DM is only to be taken into account if the sum of the profits according to \u00a7 13a Abs 8 EStG is positive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The granting of the exemption cannot lead to a loss or change a loss"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "In addition, the profits to be recognized in accordance with Section 13a (8) of the Income Tax Act are generally to be determined by comparing the operating income and the operating expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "For the determination of the profit from viticulture, I refer to the Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "vom 25 7 88 - S-2233 A - St 34 2 - ESt-Kartei: Card 8 h to \u00a7 13 - and because of the determination of the profit from fruit and vegetable growing, the Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "vom 11 1 89 - S-2233 A - St 34 2 - ESt-Kartei: card 9 g to \u00a7 13 - to be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "As far as profits from closure and severance distilleries can be determined, I ask that the responsible agricultural BP agency be involved"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "This will inform the taxable district of the necessary reference rates and key figures"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "43 Profits from other business operations Profits from sales of breeding cattle that exceed normal profit are to be recorded within the framework of Section 13a (8) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The additional profits from the sale of breeding cattle must continue to be determined according to the previous procedure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The decisive starting values \u200b\u200bfor the 1987/88 financial year are: for breeding horses 9000 DM for riding horses 7000 DM for breeding bulls 5300 DM for breeding cows 2300 DM for breeding cattle 2200 DM for breeding sows1000 DM for breeding sows1000 DM for breeding sheep surcharge is DM1300"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "of the sales (auction) proceeds exceeding the initial values"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "5 Miscellaneous 51 Determination of capital gains - taxation of land gains I would like to draw your attention once again to the correct and timely recording of sales and land gains"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "In particular, I ask that the control material available, such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Notices of sale of the real estate transfer tax offices to be evaluated promptly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "52 Partial old-age benefits 521 General If partial old-age benefits exist due to farm handover contracts between parents and children not only consist of benefits in kind and in kind, it must be checked in each individual case whether the individual partial benefits are annuities or permanent expenses (recurring payments) (see BFH judgment of 28 7 83 BStBl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "1984 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "97)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Because of the transitional and adjustment regulations for existing old age contracts, reference is made to the Rdvfgen of 16 8 84 and 24 1 85 - S-2255 A - St 34 2 - ESt-Kartei: Karte 12 and 12a to \u00a7 13"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "522 Benefits in the case of business lease agreements On the application of the BFH case law on partial retirement benefits in agriculture and forestry (judgment of 28 7 83 a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": ") For so-called business leasing contracts, I refer to the Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "vom 20 5 86 - S-2255 A - St 34 2 - ESt-Kartei: card 20 to \u00a7 13 - towards"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "523 Retirement apartment after discontinuation of the value-in-use taxation If an apartment is left on the basis of a retirement contract, the value in use of the apartment - if Section 13 (2) No. 2 and Section 13a (3) No. 4 and Paragraph 7 EStG are no longer applied - is not a permanent burden for the retired person obliged to pay According to Section 10 (1) no.1a EStG, to be recorded as recurring remuneration within the meaning of Section 22 (1) sentence 1 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "This results from the abolition of the taxation of the value in use of the owner-occupied apartment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "On the other hand - according to the principles of the BFH judgment of 30 10 84 BStBl 1985 II S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "610 - in the case of the pensioner, such expenses associated with the provision of the apartment are deductible as a permanent burden, which accrue to the pensioner as recurring benefits in kind"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "In particular, expenses for electricity, heating, water and - provided it is not a conditional usufruct in rem - cosmetic repairs are to be recorded; however, deductions for wear and tear and interest are not to be applied"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "53 Demarcation of commercial operations from agriculture and forestry 531 Purchase of third-party products According to the BFH judgment of 27 11 80 - BStBl 1981 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "518 - the answer to the question of whether the trade in self-produced gardening products and with purchased goods is to be assessed as a whole as part of a single operation as agriculture and forestry or as a commercial activity depends on the ratio of the turnover of self-produced and purchased goods to the total turnover"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Section 135 (4) EStR, on the other hand, is based on the ratio of the purchase value of third-party products to total sales"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "After a decision by the highest tax authorities of the federal states, the regulation in Section 135 (4) EStR continues to apply for reasons of simplification"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "532 Horse keeping Because of the classification of horse keeping as an agricultural or commercial activity, I refer to the evaluation of the Rdvfgen from 26 11 1981 u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "24 9 1984 - S-3110 A - St 44 2 / St 45 2 - Bew- card index: \u00a7 33 BewG horse keeping card 1)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "In addition to Section 135 (11) of the EStR, the instructions contained therein are also to be applied mutatis mutandis to the income tax delimitation of these businesses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "54 Simplification regulation for farm handovers to family members within a financial year In the case of farm handovers to family members within a financial year, the with Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "vom 23 10 1980 - S-2239 A - St 34 2 - ESt-Kartei: Map 5 to \u00a7 13 - the regulation made to be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "55 Lease of an agricultural and forestry business per parcel The lessor can only choose to continue the business if and for as long as all essential operational bases are leased to one tenant or individually to several tenants"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "If the Stpfl does not clearly express his choice, the previous business assets must be continued as such as long as this is legally possible, i.e."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "how the assets are objectively suitable for resuming and continuing the discontinued operation (BFH judgment of 15 10 1987 BStBl 1988 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "260)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Furthermore, a continuation of the business is to be assumed in any case if the lessor declares that the business will not be given up but - by whoever - is to be continued at a later point in time and that there are objective circumstances in favor of the later continuation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "An objective fact speaks for the later continuation of the business if the business is not dissolved in its essential bases by the lease"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "This is the case as long as the essential economic goods are not finally used outside of the country or outside of the forest and the farmstead - in particular the farm buildings - are retained without any significant structural changes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "It also speaks in favor of maintaining the essential fundamentals of the business if the lease agreements with all tenants have a uniform duration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "If, according to the given circumstances, it is not clear whether the lessor has given up the business or continued it, the tax office (especially in the case of leasing the business in parcels) must clarify by requesting a written declaration of abandonment or continuation of the business, whether the taxpayer has given up the business or continues want to see (see Sect. 139 para 5 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "7 EStR 1987)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "56 Forestry 561 Acquisition of forest land In Section 212 (1) EStR 1987, for reasons of simplification, it is permitted that capitalized acquisition or production costs for standing wood are reduced by 3% annually"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "can be reduced"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "When acquiring forest land and when acquiring businesses and sub-businesses, the purchase price must therefore be properly divided between the land and the stocking (standing wood)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Whether this has happened in individual cases is checked by the forestry expert from the regional tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "I therefore ask you to report to the regional finance directorate in the relevant cases before carrying out the assessment, enclosing the files"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "562 Selling of forest land Even with the sale of forest land and the sale of businesses and sub-businesses, appropriate taxation is usually only guaranteed if the proceeds from the sale relate to the land (loss clause under Section 55 (6) EStG) and to the Tillering as well as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "on other assets (buildings, inventory, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": ") is divided"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The distribution of the sales proceeds and, if applicable,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "In such cases, the corresponding book value is determined by the forestry expert from the regional finance directorate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "I therefore ask that in each individual case, immediately after a sale becomes known (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "by means of a notification of sale from the real estate acquisition tax office) and before carrying out the corresponding assessment, enclosing the tax files and the standard value files of the regional finance office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "563 Tariff reduction according to \u00a7 34b EStG Applications for the application of the reduced tax rates according to \u00a7 34b EStG for extraordinary income from forestry (extraordinary use of wood and wood use as a result of force majeure - calamity use -) must be forwarded immediately to the regional tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "After a review by the forestry expert, the tax offices receive a notification about the amount of tax-privileged wood use, which must be taken into account in the assessment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "57 Control reports Except in the usual cases (control reports for the purposes of Bp, inheritance tax, wage tax, unit valuation, etc.)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "), particularly in the case of lease / usage relationships, control notifications must be prepared using the \"ESt 34 d\" form"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The cases in which the individual lease / use ratio comprises agricultural areas of more than 2 ha or in which areas with special uses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "of Section 13a Paragraph 4 No. 4 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "I ask that incoming control reports as well as unit value reports always be evaluated promptly because of possible effects on the way in which the taxpayer's profit is determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "When evaluating them, it can be useful to consult the standard value files"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The same also applies to the assessment of farmers and foresters, particularly when determining profits in accordance with Section 13a of the Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "58 Amendments to the Income Tax Act by the Tax Reform Act 1990 that were already applied to the income tax assessment or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Determination of profits for calendar years prior to 1990 must be observed 581 transitional regulations for owner-occupied apartments in the business assets of a farmer and forestry manager (Section 52 (15) EStG) According to Section 52 (15) sentence 3 EStG, a farmer and forestry worker who is working on an agricultural and forestry business can Property belonging to business assets, built an apartment for their own residential purposes or an apartment for the elderly that will only be completed after December 31, 1986, continue to record the value in use of the apartment as part of the profit determination up to and including the assessment period 1998"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The prerequisite for this is that the building application was submitted before 1 1 1987 and that the apartment is used for the taxpayer's own residential purposes or for the residential purposes of the senior citizen in the year of completion"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "This now also covers the cases in which the building application was submitted between 28 2 1986 and 1 1 1987"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "582 Tax-free withdrawal of land from agricultural and forestry business assets According to the newly inserted sentence 10 of Section 52 (15) EStG, a farmer and forester can after 31 12 1986 land his agricultural and forestry business assets by building with a Take out an apartment for your own residential purposes or an apartment that is shared between the elderly and tax-free"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "This regulation applies accordingly to real estate that in the assessment period 1986 still belonged to commercial assets or business assets used for self-employed work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "583 Benefit in the case of severance payments to heirs and the repayment of debts in agriculture and forestry (Section 14a EStG) The benefits contained in Section 14a (4) and (5) EStG for the sale or removal of agricultural and forestry land to compensate for replacement heirs or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "for debt repayment in agriculture and forestry are dependent on compliance with certain income limits"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Here sliding rules have now been introduced which, if the relevant income limits are exceeded, lead to a step-by-step reduction in the tax exemptions in the event of compensation for heirs who have given way and in the event of debt repayment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "The new regulations are already to be applied to sales and withdrawals made after December 31, 1985 (Section 52 (17) EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "In addition, the exemption for debt repayment under paragraph 5 will be extended by four years until the end of 1992"}, {"meta": {"name": "0090691.xml"}, "text": "Income tax / wage tax / church tax Invoicing Procedural law / tax code Commercial law Corporate law Rhineland-Palatinate Agriculture Income tax Farmer"}]