[{"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion M\u00fcnster S-1300 - 119 - St 11 - 34S-1300S-2293O-2252S-1300 - 124 / St 21S-1300 A - St 32 1 / S-2293 A - St 31 1O-2252 A - St 16 1S-1300S- 2293O-2252 Bibliography of the corresponding administrative instructions: BayernOFD N\u00fcrnberg S-1300 - 124 / St 21 from 01081990EStK Annex DBA advance card for card 11 Baden-W\u00fcrttembergOFD Freiburg S-1300 A - St 32 1 / S-2293 A - St 31 1/1042 / O -2252 A - St 16 1 vom 13061990 Taxation of foreign income for persons with unlimited tax liability Reference: My ruling from 4 7 1986 S-1301 - 119 - St 11 - 341 Annex1 General information11 Important provisions of the tax code12 Unrestricted tax liability13 Income from the GDR or Berlin (East ) 14 Approval of foreign income15 Determination of foreign income and foreign taxes2 Avoidance of double taxation (basic rules) 21 Credit method22 Exemption method3 Foreign income from a country with which a double taxation agreement exists31 General information on double taxation agreements311 Be Standing DBA312 Structure of the DBA313 Taxation rules of the DBA32 Residence 33 Crediting of foreign taxes (crediting method) 331 General332 Implementation of the crediting333 Additional information on individual types of income34 Exemption from foreign income (exemption method) 341 General342 Progression reservation343 Additional information on individual types of income with no DBA exists41 Determination of income42 Offsetting of foreign taxes43 Flat rate waiver5 Negative foreign income 51 Negative foreign income according to Section 2a Paragraphs 1 and 2 EStG511 General512 Negative progression proviso513 Monitoring514 Productivity clause and other exceptions515 Overview516 Constitutionality52 Foreign investment law (from 1990: Section 2a Paragraphs 3523 Additional Tax Law) 521 General Application524 Additional Tax Act 521 Monitoring6 Incorrect taxation of foreign income by the source country7 Evaluation of the notification According to \u00a7 18 Foreign Tax Act8 Special procedural features for the uniform and separate determination of foreign income Appendix 1: Income from dividends and interest (additional information) 1 General11 Request and check of the documents12 Determination of the income13 Determination of the tax credit14 Processing instructions2 Tax credit according to the DBA France3 Crediting of fictitious taxes Appendix 2: Income from private property (additional information) 11 Taxation rules according to the double taxation agreements12 Tax bases121 General122 Taxation of owner-occupied apartments from the assessment period 1987123 Double taxation agreement Switzerland Appendix 3 Income from employment or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "dependent work according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "DTA law (additional information) 1 Work for a private employer in a DTA country 11 Principle of the place of work 111 General112 Managing directors and board members of corporations113 Processing instructions114 No deduction of special expenses12 Amount of exempt wages13 183-day rule 131 General132 Determination of the 183-day deadline133 Payment by an employer based in the country of activity134 payment of wages at the expense of a permanent establishment of the employer in the country of activity14 double taxation agreements in Italy15 cross-border commuters16 special regulations2 work for a public employer in a double taxation agreement country3 foreign activity decree the request for information and attention"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The summary is intended to help the audit offices determined z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "to avoid serious errors when recording foreign income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The elaboration does not claim to be complete; in particular, earnings are only dealt with in part"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Special features of the taxation of foreign profit income (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Issues related to currency conversion, BFH decision of 9 August 1989 BStBl 90 II 175) must be taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If there are any doubts, it is therefore not possible to dispense with studying the relevant regulations, the administrative regulations and case law"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The HSGebl / HSachB \"External Tax Law\" should regularly be involved in solving the corresponding questions of doubt"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "I ask that the main content of the guide be the subject of service briefings"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The guideline should be revised after a certain testing period (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Preparation of an index, inclusion of examples)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "I would ask you to report to me about your experiences with the guide, suggestions for changes and additions by October 31, 1992"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Guideline for the taxation of foreign income for natural persons with unlimited tax liability Status: May 19901 General information11 Important provisions of the tax code In matters with foreign relevance, the provisions of the AO must be observed, including the following special provisions: \u00a7 2 AO on the priority of international agreements (DTA and other intergovernmental agreements), Section 90 (2) AO on the increased duty of the parties to cooperate, Section 117 AO on intergovernmental legal and administrative assistance in tax matters, Section 138 (2) AO on the obligation to notify when setting up and acquiring foreign companies and permanent establishments and when acquiring foreign holdings, Section 162 (2) AO on the estimation of tax bases in the event of a breach of the duty to cooperate according to \u00a7 90 Paragraph 2 AO, \u00a7 180 Paragraph 5 AO on the separate determination of foreign income that is excluded from taxation according to a DTA but is important for the tax assessment d (see no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "12 Unrestricted tax liability In the case of unrestricted taxpayers, all domestic and foreign income is subject to income tax (global income principle, see Section 1 (4) EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The existing methods of avoiding double taxation for foreign income must be observed (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "13 Income from the GDR or Berlin (East) Income from the GDR or Berlin (East) is not foreign income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Income of the type described in \u00a7 49 EStG, insofar as it is obtained in the GDR or in Berlin (East) and - from 1989 - is actually used there for a tax corresponding to the domestic income tax, is acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 3 No. 63 EStG tax-free"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The income is not subject to the progression proviso according to \u00a7 32b EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "14 Approval of foreign income The foreign income must be income that, according to Section 2, Paragraph 1, No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "1 - 7 EStG are subject to income tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "A DTA cannot justify a domestic tax liability, but only leave a tax claim of the Federal Republic of Germany based on domestic tax law or withdraw it in whole or in part"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Appendix 115 Determination of foreign income and foreign taxes The type and amount of foreign income must always be determined in accordance with German law"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Operating expenses and advertising expenses (also possibly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Lump sums) are to be taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The foreign income as well as any"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Foreign tax to be taken into account (s"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "21) are to be converted according to the officially set exchange rate in the Federal Gazette (see also Section 212 b EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "For reasons of simplicity, conversion at the sales tax conversion rates that are published monthly in the Federal Tax Gazette Part I is permitted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The taxpayer must provide evidence of the amount of foreign income and the determination and payment of foreign taxes by means of appropriate documents (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Tax assessment, payment receipt), if necessary"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "in German translation (\u00a7 68b EStDV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "References to foreign income can also be obtained from documents in the files, in particular from control material and from confirmations of domestic residence (so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Certificates of residence) that have been submitted in connection with applications for exemption or reimbursement of foreign withholding taxes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "2 Avoidance of double taxation (basic rules) Foreign income is usually also subject to taxation abroad"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "To compensate, they are not taxed or only taxed at a reduced rate in the Federal Republic of Germany (avoidance of double taxation)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The following methods are particularly suitable: offsetting the foreign tax against the German tax that is attributable to the foreign income; u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "also the deduction when determining the total amount of income (\u00a7 34c Paragraph 1 - 3 EStG) - credit method; the exemption, d"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "the removal of foreign income from the German tax base with progression reservation (Section 32b (1) No. 2 EStG) - exemption method"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The credit method (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "21) is to be used if a DBA does not exist (see no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "41), exists for the income for which the DTA provides for crediting (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "331)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The exemption method (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "22) is only to be used insofar as this is provided for in a DTA (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "341)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "There is no offsetting of foreign taxes or a deduction from the total amount of income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "An overview of the tax exemption and tax reductions for foreign income is contained in Annex 221 Credit method. With the credit method, the Federal Republic of Germany has the full right to tax foreign income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "This applies to both positive and negative income, i.e."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "the latter are to be allowed to compensate for other income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The restrictions of Section 2a (1) and (2) EStG (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "511 and 514) must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The tax levied in the foreign country can either be offset or, upon request, deducted when determining the total amount of income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If no double taxation agreement is applicable, this follows for all foreign income i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 34d EStG from \u00a7 34c Paragraph 1 and 2 EStG, otherwise from the relevant regulations of the respective DBA in conjunction with \u00a7 34c Paragraph 6 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "A deduction from the total amount of income in accordance with Section 34c (2) EStG is also permitted if the DTA expressly only mentions the crediting (see section 212e EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "22 Exemption method With the exemption method, the foreign income is treated as tax-free, but in the assessment of the tax rate within the framework of the progression proviso in accordance with"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Section 32b (1) no.2 EStG is taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "According to this, both the positive and the negative progression proviso is possible, the latter to the effect that losses may increase the tax rate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "reduce to 0 (if necessary"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Consideration of unused losses in accordance with \u00a7 10d EStG, see Section 185 (2) sentence 3 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The restrictions of Section 2a (1) and (2) EStG (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "512) must be observed, however"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "3 Foreign income from a country with which a DTA exists31 General information on DTAs311 Existing DTAs An overview of the current status of DTAs and DTA negotiations is published in BStBl Part I at the beginning of each year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The overview of the DTAs as of 1 1 1990 contains the Annex 4312 Structure of the DTA Most DTAs are structured as follows: The introductory provisions delimit the scope of the agreement and contain the definitions that are important for its application (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Residence, permanent establishment)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The following articles set the framework within which the source state may tax income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Another article determines how the state of residence avoids double taxation of income that is left to the source state for taxation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The final articles regulate the protection against tax discrimination, the implementation of mutual agreement procedures, the exchange of information between the contracting states as well as the entry into force and expiry of the agreement"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "It should be noted that individual DBA provisions in additional agreements (final protocol, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": ") can be modified or explained"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "313 Taxation rules of the DBA The rules on taxation in the source country generally do not allow any conclusions to be drawn about taxation in the country of residence; this can be found regularly in the article on avoiding double taxation in the country of residence (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "also No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Insofar as \"can\" and / or \"may\" are mentioned in the regulation of taxation law in a DTA, the respective regulation only refers to the specifically addressed contracting state"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If the latter does not make use of the permit, i.e. does not exercise his right to tax, the other contracting state generally has no right to tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The other contracting state is therefore also limited in this case to the right to tax that the DTA expressly leaves it (prohibition of virtual double taxation)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "32 Residency Unlimited Stpfl are also i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "of the respective double taxation agreement resident in the Federal Republic of Germany"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Does the here unrestricted Stpfl also have a place of residence or habitual abode in the foreign country"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Dual residence), it should be noted that the DTA determines one of the two states, which is i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "of the agreement applies"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "As a rule, this is the state with which the Stpfl has closer personal and economic relationships (center of life interests)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Special feature: According to the DBA USA 1966 (Art"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "XV Paragraph 1 No. 2) American citizenship already leads to dual residence"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If the Federal Republic of Germany is not the country of residence in the case of dual residence, there is usually no right to tax foreign income in Germany"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "These are also not subject to the progression proviso"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The personal unlimited tax liability in Germany remains unaffected"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Residency abroad is only assumed for the application of the DBA (cf. AO application decree on \u00a7 8 No. 2 AO card index, \u00a7 8 card 1)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If the Federal Republic of Germany is the state of residence or if it is considered as such in the case of dual residence, it must first be determined in accordance with the articles on taxation in the source state whether the foreign state has a right to tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If the foreign state has no right to tax, the income must be recorded in the Federal Republic of Germany"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "It must be ensured that the foreign income is also included in the respective annexes to the income tax return and is transferred to the designated Kz"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "14 must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Crediting or deduction of foreign taxes is ruled out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If, on the other hand, the foreign state has a right to tax under the articles on withholding taxation, i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "No statement has yet been made on how double taxation will be avoided in the Federal Republic of Germany (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "313)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The avoidance of double taxation in the country of residence is regulated in a separate article of the agreement"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The DTAs use two methods: the credit method and the exemption method (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "21 and 22)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "33 Crediting of foreign taxes (crediting method) 331 General The crediting method (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "21) applies according to the DBA i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "In the case of income from dividends, interest and license fees (if there is a withholding tax right), from artists and professional athletes, from supervisory boards, from immovable property in exceptional cases (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Switzerland, Spain)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Income is included in Germany when determining the total amount of income; Section 2a (1) and (2) EStG must be observed (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "21 511 and 514)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "332 Implementation of the crediting The pro rata German income tax applicable to the foreign income is to be determined in total for the income originating from one state"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The calculation of the maximum amount in accordance with Section 34c (1) EStG is based on the foreign income that is taken into account when determining the taxable income, i.e."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "after application of \u00a7 2a Abs 1 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The foreign taxes to be offset are also to be included in the foreign taxes that have been paid on income within the meaning of Section 2a (1) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "As a result, in cases in which, on the basis of Section 2a (1) EStG, total income from a state is not to be taken into account when determining the total amount of income (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Losses from silent participation), which may be applied to foreign income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "foreign taxes levied within the framework of the maximum amount according to \u00a7 34c paragraph 1 EStG or deducted at the request of the Stpfl according to \u00a7 34c paragraph 2 EStG when determining the total amount of income (cf. section 212c sentence 4 and 212d paragraph 2 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The right to choose must be exercised uniformly for all income from a foreign country and for all taxes that can be offset under the respective double taxation agreement (cf. section 212 e sentence 4 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "In the case of a deduction according to Section 34c (2) EStG, the number of the state for which the deduction was requested must be entered in the ESt / LSt 1 A cover sheet at Kz 1884"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The application of Section 34c (3) EStG is out of the question here"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "333 Additional information on individual types of income Details on foreign income from dividends and interest are shown in Appendix 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "For foreign income from private property, if the credit method is used as an exception (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Switzerland, Spain), see Appendix 234 Exemption from foreign income (exemption method) 341 General The exemption method (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "22) applies according to the DBA i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "In the case of income from commercial operations (corporate profits from permanent establishments), employment (unless the so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "183-day rule applies), self-employed work within the framework of a permanent establishment, immovable property (incl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Agriculture and Forestry)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The income is treated as tax-free, but when calculating the tax rate within the framework of the progression proviso in accordance with"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Section 32b (1) no.2 EStG is taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Individual agreements grant tax exemption for permanent establishment profits only if the income of the permanent establishment comes from certain (active) activities"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "342 Progression reservation The progression reservation according to \u00a7 32b EStG does not apply to income from Italy as long as the DBA Italy 1925 is still applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The type and amount of foreign income must also be determined for the purpose of the progression proviso under German tax law (see Section 185, Paragraph 1 of the Income Tax Law)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Operating expenses and advertising expenses (also possibly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Lump sums) must therefore be deducted when calculating the income to be taken into account in the progression proviso"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "This BA or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "WKs may not reduce domestic income (Section 3c EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "For the assessment basis for loss deduction see the BFH judgment of 11 10 1989 BStBl 1990 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "For tax-free foreign income i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7\u00a7 34 Abs 2 34b EStG, Section 185 Paragraph 3 Sentence 2 EStR must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "In the cases of Section 2a Paragraph 1 EStG (cf. in detail no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "512 and Appendix 3), the negative progression proviso is excluded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The entire income subject to the progression proviso must be entered in the ESt / LSt 1 A cover sheet under Kz 1840/41"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If, however, wages are available, the income is to be entered in Appendix N to Kz 2739 or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "2839 and the advertising expenses for Kz 2779 and"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Kz 2879 (variable information from VZ 1984 see subject 10 part 27 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "3 DA-ADV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "343 Additional information on individual types of income Details on foreign income from private property are shown in Appendix 2 and on foreign income from employment in Appendix 3"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "4 Foreign income from a country with which there is no double taxation agreement41 Determination of income When determining the total amount of domestic income, all foreign positive and negative income is generally recorded (so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "World income principle)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "However, Section 2a (1) and (2) EStG must be observed (cf. in detail no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "511 and 514 and Appendix 3)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "42 Crediting of foreign taxes (The fixed, paid foreign tax that is no longer subject to a reduction claim (see also Section 212 c EStR) is credited in accordance with Section 34 c, Paragraph 1 EStG, if"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "34d EStG are present, the source country is also the taxing country and the foreign tax corresponds to German income tax (Section 212 a EStR, Annex 10 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The remarks on No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "332 apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The maximum amount limit according to \u00a7 34c Paragraph 1 Sentences 1 and 2 EStG (maximum crediting up to the amount of the proportionate German income tax applicable to income from a foreign country) makes it necessary to calculate the maximum amounts separately for each country (see \u00a7 68a sentence 2 EStDV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The income and the resulting foreign taxes are to be transferred separately to the ESt / LSt 1A cover sheet for Kz 1842/43 and 44/45"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If, instead of offsetting, the deduction of foreign tax is applied for when determining the total amount of income (Section 34c (2) EStG), the number of the country to which the application relates must be entered under code 1884"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The application can only be made uniformly for all income from a certain country"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Are the o"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Requirements for crediting or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "a deduction in accordance with \u00a7 34c Paragraph 1 or 2 EStG is not available, the foreign tax under Kz"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "1846 to be entered so that it is deducted in accordance with Section 34c (3) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "43 Flat rate waiver on the so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Lump-sum decree and the special regulations contained therein for foreign income from commercial operations and self-employed work are pointed out (Appendix 14 of the EStR, BStBl 1984 I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "252)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "According to this, under certain conditions, the foreign income is only reduced to 25% upon request"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "taxed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "5 Negative foreign income 51 Negative foreign income according to \u00a7 2a Paragraph 1 and 2 EStG511 General From the assessment period 1983, the in \u00a7 2a Paragraph 1 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "1 to 4 EStG conclusively listed negative foreign income can only be compensated with foreign income of the same type from the same country"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Affected are losses from a foreign agricultural and forestry establishment, a foreign commercial establishment (unless it is a productively active establishment according to Section 2a Paragraph 2 EStG), a silent participation in a commercial enterprise / a participation loan if the debtor is domiciled, domiciled or has management abroad, renting and leasing immovable property or property located abroad"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "These losses may not be deducted according to Section 10d EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "As far as the above"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If compensation is not possible, the losses reduce the positive foreign income of the same type that the Stpfl earns from the same country in the following seven assessment periods"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The legal consequences of Section 2a (1) EStG are not taken into account in a program-controlled manner in the automatic income tax assessment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Insofar as negative income is not to be taken into account or positive income to be reduced, the relevant values \u200b\u200bmust be determined and instructed personally"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "512 Negative progression proviso In the cases of Section 2a (1) EStG, the negative progression proviso is also excluded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "513 Monitoring To ensure the correct application of the loss deduction restriction, a monitoring overview for each type of income i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "of Section 2a Paragraph 1 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "1 - 4 EStG, create every state and every year of loss and attach them to the tax files (see Annex 6)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to negative progression reservations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "514 Productivity clause and other exceptions In the event of losses from foreign commercial establishments that fall under the productivity clause of Section 2a (2) EStG, or for losses that are not mentioned in Section 2a (1) EStG, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If you are self-employed abroad, loss compensation is possible with all income (even if the negative progression clause is applied)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "515 Overview The tax treatment of losses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 2a Paragraph 1 and 2 EStG is compiled in the overview in Appendix 3"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "516 Constitutionality Due to the proceedings pending at the BFH regarding the constitutionality of Section 2a Paragraph 1 EStG, the legal remedy procedure pursuant to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "To let \u00a7 363 Abs 2 AO rest and to grant suspension of execution upon request, see order of 6 1 1987 S-2118a - 20 - St 11 - 31"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "52 Foreign Investment Act (from 1990: Section 2a (3) and (4) EStG) 521 General"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "2 Paragraph 1 Clause 1 AIG (from 1990: Paragraph 2a Paragraph 3 EStG) apply for the losses from foreign commercial and productive establishments i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "to be deducted from Section 5 AIG (from 1990: Section 2a Paragraph 2 EStG) when determining the total amount of income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If the Stpfl has several commercial establishments in the foreign country concerned (participation in a co-entrepreneurship also counts as a permanent establishment), a loss can only be deducted if a loss still remains after offsetting with profits from the same country"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "522 Application The application must be submitted to the local tax office (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "by entering the loss in the GSE attachment to code 2138)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "A notification from the permanent establishment tax office that a foreign loss can be taken into account according to \u00a7 2 AIG does not in itself contain an application (cf. in detail no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The application can be limited to a certain amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "523 Addition The loss deducted in accordance with Section 2 AIG must be added back in the following assessment periods (unlimited in time), provided that the total amount of the business premises located in the country concerned is positive (Section 2 Paragraph 1 Sentence 3 AIG, from 1990: Section 2a Para 3 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "In the event of a sale, neither the tax exemption according to \u00a7 16 (4) EStG nor the reduced tax rate according to \u00a7 34 EStG is to be granted for the addition (see BFH rulings of 8 3 1989 BStBl 1989 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "541, and from 2 3 1989 BStBl 1989 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "543)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "An addition takes place under the conditions of \u00a7 2 Paragraph 2 AIG (from 1990: \u00a7 2a Paragraph 4 EStG) if the foreign permanent establishment is converted into a corporation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "No addition is made if the Stpfl proves that it is generally not possible to carry forward or carry back losses in the foreign country (Section 2 Paragraph 1 Sentence 4 Paragraph 2 No. 2 AIG, from 1990: Section 2a Paragraph 3 Sentence 4 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "524 Monitoring To monitor the subsequent taxation, a monitoring overview (see Annex 7) is to be kept, separated by country"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Since the obligation to add relates to all permanent establishments in the country in question, overviews must also be set up for losses from permanent establishments that were already sold or abandoned in previous years if the deducted losses have not been fully taxed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Monitoring is also necessary with regard to any future permanent establishments if income is not currently being generated in the country in which the losses were incurred"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "6 Incorrect taxation of foreign income by the source country Taxation in the source country that contradicts the rules of a DTA cannot be taken into account for domestic taxation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "However, the taxpayer generally has the option of opposing taxation contrary to the treaty within the framework of an appeal procedure abroad"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Irrespective of this, the Stpfl can request the initiation of a mutual agreement procedure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The application can be submitted to the tax authority responsible for taxation, which forwards the application via official channels to the Federal Minister of Finance, or to the Federal Minister of Finance as the competent authority"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The Federal Office of Finance, Friedhofstrasse 1 5300 Bonn, has 3 applications ready for reimbursement of foreign withholding tax levied too much on dividends and interest (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "13 Appendix 1)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "7 Evaluation of the notification according to \u00a7 18 Foreign Tax Act The tax bases for \u00a7\u00a7 7 - 14 AStG are separately and if necessary"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "consistently determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The additional amount is to be applied to income from capital assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If the shares in the foreign company belong to business assets, the additional amount increases the profit (Section 10 (2) AStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "8 Special features of procedural law for the uniform and separate determination of foreign income Foreign income - even if it is only subject to the progression proviso or is of importance for Section 2 AIG (from 1990; Section 2a Paragraph 3 EStG) - may be"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "to be determined separately and uniformly (Section 180 (5) AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "That applies u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "if a domestic partnership generates such income or if several tax residents are involved in foreign partnerships"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "In the latter case, the participation must be reported to the Federal Office of Finance using form BfF 2"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "With regard to the local responsibility for the separate and uniform determination of the profits of foreign partnerships in which domestic shareholders are involved, see BMF letter dated 11 12 1989 BStBl 1989 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "470, AO card index, \u00a7 25 card 2 If foreign income is to be determined separately and uniformly, a decision must be made in the determination procedure whether this income is within the meaning of \u00a7 2a Paragraph 1 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "1 to 4 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Since legal consequences from \u00a7 2a EStG arise exclusively in the case of the income tax assessment of the parties involved in the assessment, in addition to the amount of income, it is also necessary to determine which type within the meaning of \u00a7 2a Paragraph 1 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "1 to 4 EStG this income is to be allocated and from which country this income originates (see column 14 of the forms Annex ESt 1 2 3 B and notification ESt 4 B)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "From this it becomes clear that the determination of negative / positive income within the meaning of Section 2a Paragraph 1 EStG cannot be dispensed with"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The application of Section 2 Paragraph 1 AIG (from 1990: Section 2a Paragraph 3 EStG) is only to be decided when assessing the income tax of the individual participants (see BFH of 28 4 1983 BStBl 1983 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "566, and from 20 9 1989 BStBl 1990 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "112)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "In the determination procedure it is only necessary to decide whether and to what extent the permanent establishment income meets the requirements of Section 2 Paragraph 1 and Section 5 AIG (from 1990: Section 2a Paragraph 3 in conjunction with"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Paragraphs 1 and 2 of the Income Tax Act) and from which country this income comes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "A summary of the permanent establishment income from several countries is therefore not possible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "For these reasons, the taxation criteria for the case of application of Section 2 Paragraph 1 AIG (from 1990: Section 2a Paragraph 3 EStG) (see column 11 of the forms Annex ESt 1 2 3 B, notification ESt 4 B) as well as for the cases of Consideration in accordance with the progression reservation (see columns 12 and 15 of the forms Annex ESt 1 2 3 B, notification ESt 4 B) alternatively determined side by side"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "However, the application according to \u00a7 2 AIG (from 1990: \u00a7 2a Paragraph 3 EStG) can only be made in the income tax declaration of the Stpfl at the tax office of his residence (s"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "522)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If the income to be exempt is not from commercial establishments, a distinction must only be made between current and extraordinary income (cf. column 10 of the forms Annex ESt 1 2 3 B, communication ESt 4 B); Furthermore, the regulations of \u00a7 2a Paragraph 1 and 2 EStG must be observed (column 15 forms Annex 1 2 3 B, notification ESt 4 B)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Due to the regulations of \u00a7 34c EStG on the offsetting of foreign taxes on the ESt, it is necessary to determine the foreign income and the foreign taxes due on it separately for each country (see column 20 of the forms Annex ESt 1 2 3 B, message ESt 4 B)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The state from which the income originates and from which the foreign taxes were set must be specified"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Insofar as notifications are received at the tax offices of the domicile about the results of a determination which do not meet the requirements set out above, the respective tax office must be asked to provide additional information"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Appendix 1: Income from dividends and interest (additional information) 1 General 11 Requirement and verification of documents In the case of dividends and interest, the documents from domestic and foreign banks regarding the amount of the income and the withholding tax withheld (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "15 of the guideline) and to check it finally, even if the assessment is made subject to review (Section 164 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "In particular, the type (dividends or interest) and the amount of income per country as well as the amount of foreign taxes per type of income must be evident from the bank receipts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Receipts that do not meet these requirements must be objected to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Regarding the conversion, see also no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "15 of the guide"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "A summary of the foreign income and the foreign taxes from several countries for the purpose of crediting is in accordance with"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Section 34c (1) of the Income Tax Act is not permitted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The only exception is for unit certificates from investment companies (see Subject 10, Part 18, p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "2 DA-ADV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "12 Determination of income When determining income, accrued interest paid must be deducted from the income as well as the - proportionate - income-related expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "At least the amounts that are shown in the dividend certificates or other certificates from the banks should be taken into account as income-related expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If the Stpfl does not provide evidence of the income to which expenses are attributable in individual cases, a division must be made in relation to domestic and foreign income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "This is especially true if interest on debt for any refinancing is claimed as income-related expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Does the taxpayer earn in addition to foreign income from capital assets (i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Dividends or interest) for which he seeks tax credit, no or only little domestic income from capital assets, the foreign income may be"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "To determine the income that is decisive for the calculation of the maximum tax creditable by reducing the income-related expenses lump sum and the saver's allowance"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "There are no concerns if these amounts are initially deducted from income that is not eligible for tax credit (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "domestic income) and only the excess amount is deducted from the income from the state for which the tax credit is claimed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "13 Determination of creditable taxes It should be noted in particular that crediting / deduction of foreign taxes is only possible if it is no longer subject to any reduction claim"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Many DTAs provide for withholding tax restrictions abroad for dividends and interest"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Only insofar as foreign tax remains after this reduction claim has been taken into account, this is to be offset or ex officio"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "deductible upon request"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "It does not matter whether the taxpayer's claim to a reduction is actually asserted with the competent foreign tax authority (see section 212 c EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The amount of withholding tax and a possible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The right to a reduction can be found in Annex 5 for the most frequently used double taxation agreements, see OFD M\u00fcnster from 2 4 1990 S-2293-61 - St 11-31"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Applications for the reimbursement of foreign withholding tax can be obtained from the bank holding the account or from the Federal Office of Finance, Friedhofstrasse 1 5300 Bonn 3"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "14 Processing instructions The income (gross income, i.e."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Income before deduction of foreign taxes, reduced by the income-related expenses) must be entered in the case of machine processing in the ESt / LSt 1A cover sheet for Kz 1842/44/56 and the income must always be entered in the KSO appendix to Kz 2632/33"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The foreign taxes that are no longer subject to a reduction claim in the source country must be entered under Kz 1843/45/57"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "2 Tax credit according to the double taxation agreement France In relation to France, there is the special feature that France grants residents of the Federal Republic of Germany a tax credit on dividends distributed (so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "avoir fiscal)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the shareholders of French corporations domiciled in the Federal Republic of Germany will not be charged with French capital gains tax or will be refunded in full"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "When assessing German income tax, an amount of 50 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "the distribution of the French corporation as a \"tax credit\" such as withheld German capital gains tax offset against or refunded to the German tax of the shareholder"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "This amount must also be added to the shareholder's income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The French tax authorities grant the German tax authorities the amount of the tax credit minus the French capital gains tax of 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "on the dividend plus credit by way of a fiscal equalization in a special procedure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "For this purpose, the tax office enters the total amount included in the tax assessment base and the DM amount to be reclaimed by the French tax authorities in copies 4 and 5 of the form RF 1A intended for fiscal equalization and forwards copy 5 to the Federal Office of Finance without delay"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The forwarding to the Federal Office of Finance is to be specially noted on the copy 4, section 5, no.3 intended for the files of the tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Forms for asserting the tax credit can be obtained from the Federal Office of Finance, Friedhofstr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "1 5300 Bonn 3 (see also ESt-Kartei NRW, Appendix DBA France, A No. 8)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "3 Crediting of fictitious taxes According to some DTAs (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Brazil, India, Greece) a crediting of notional foreign withholding taxes on dividends / interest is permitted up to a certain maximum amount; d"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Even if no withholding tax or a lower withholding tax is withheld abroad, foreign taxes or foreign taxes are offset in the income tax assessment within the framework of \u00a7 34c EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "upon request, a deduction when determining the total amount of income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Appendix 2: Income from private property (additional information) 11 Taxation rules according to the DTAs In most DTAs, the right to tax income from immovable property (private renting and leasing of land and buildings, including personal use) is exclusively assigned to the state where the property is located"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "In the Federal Republic of Germany as the country of residence, this income is only taken into account for the progression proviso (exception DBA Italy 1925)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "According to some DBAs (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Spain and Switzerland) the right to tax income from immovable property is available to both the country of domicile and the country of residence"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "In the Federal Republic of Germany as the country of residence, double taxation is eliminated by the credit method (cf. in detail no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "21 and 33 of the guide)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "In the case of negative income, Section 2a EStG (cf. in detail no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "51 of the guideline), if necessary"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "also for the negative progression reservation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "12 Tax bases 121 General The income must always be determined in accordance with the provisions of the Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "It should be noted that the degressive depreciation according to Section 7 (5) EStG is excluded for buildings located abroad that were built after December 31, 1982"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "122 Taxation of owner-occupied apartments from the assessment period 1987 For apartments that were owner-used before 1987, the use of value in accordance with Section 21 (2) EStG is only possible within the framework of the transitional regulation of Section 52 (21) sentence 2 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "This means that in the case of apartments for which in VZ 1986 the value in use was taken as the surplus of income over income-related expenses, the income must be taken into account for both taxation and the progression proviso, unless the taxpayer provides an irrevocable declaration pursuant to Section 52 (21) sentence 3 EStG or has already given it in a previous assessment period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The deduction amount according to \u00a7 10e EStG is only granted for apartments located in Germany"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The owner already uses an apartment for his own residential purposes if the apartment is available to him at any time"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "According to this, personal use within the meaning of Section 21, Paragraph 2 of the Income Tax Act (EStG) is to be assumed over the whole year, even if the apartment is actually only occupied by the Stpfl for a relatively short period of time, but is otherwise available to him at any time"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "According to the BFH judgment of 24 September 1985 (BStBl 1986 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "287) by comparing the gross rental value to be estimated and the proven income-related expenses (cf. also Section 161 a, Paragraph 2 of the Income Tax Act 1987)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Apartments abroad that are first used in 1987 or later are always disregarded because of the repeal of Section 21 Paragraph 2 Sentence 1 EStG (see Section 52 Paragraph 21 Sentence 1 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "123 DBA Switzerland An exception arises from the mutual agreement on the DBA Switzerland for the taxation of the value in use of an owner-occupied single-family house (condominium) in Switzerland."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "After that, the value in use was 1 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "of the Swiss defense tax value"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "This average taxation, which corresponded to \u00a7 21a EStG, is retroactively abolished from 1 1 1987, ESt-Kartei NRW, appendix DBA Switzerland, A No. 19 Such apartments in Switzerland, to which \u00a7 52 paragraph 21 sentence 2 EStG does not apply, are therefore from 1987 no longer to be taken into account for tax purposes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "A credit or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "a deduction of Swiss income tax according to \u00a7 34c paragraph 1 and 2 EStG is not permitted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Appendix 3 Income from employment or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "dependent work according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "DTA law (additional information) 1 Activity for a private employer in a DTA country 11 Principle of the place of work 111 General If a domestic employee works for a private employer in a DTA country, the country of activity regularly has the right to tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "In this case, the income is to be exempted subject to progression reserve (for the DBA Italy cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The DBAs leave i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "the Federal Republic of Germany the right to tax if the employee is no longer than 183 days in the tax or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Calendar year in the other country (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "What matters is where the activity is actually carried out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "It is irrelevant where from or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "where the payment of wages will be made"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "112 Managing directors and board members of corporations Managing directors and board members of corporations carry out their managerial activities associated with issuing instructions at the company's headquarters (BFH of 15 11 1971 BStBl II 1972 68)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The domestically resident managing director of a GmbH who undertakes a business trip abroad, however, carries out his activity abroad because a definable specific business transaction is given (BFH of 21 5 1986 BStBl II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "739)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The 183-day rule is i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "to be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "113 Processing instructions In the assessment period, it must be checked whether the requirements for exemption from wages are met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "This also applies if the relevant exemption certificates for the purposes of wage tax deduction in accordance with Section 39b (6) EStG have been issued by the business premises tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "For the progression proviso, the income is to be determined according to German law"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Advertising expenses (or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "unused lump sums and tax exemptions), which are related to the foreign activity, are to be taken into account for the income to be recognized in the case of progression proviso"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "On the other hand, they may not reduce domestic income (Section 3c EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The foreign wages are listed in Appendix N to Kz 2739 or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Kz 2839 advertising costs are to Kz 2779 or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Kz 2879 (see subject 10 part 27 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "3 DA-ADV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "114 Prohibition of deduction of special expenses Special expenses (pension expenses) are not deductible if they are directly related to tax-free income (Section 10 (2) No. 1 EStG 1990; previously Section 10 (2) No. 2 Section 52 LStR 1990)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The reduction in the advance deduction, on the other hand, is not affected, even if there is tax-free wages"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "12 Amount of the wages to be exempted If the wages in the Federal Republic of Germany are to be exempted under a DTA, it must first be checked to what extent the remuneration can be allocated to foreign activity or domestic activity"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If an allocation is not possible, the wages are to be divided according to the ratio of the agreed working days abroad to the other agreed working days (see BFH of 29 1 1986 BStBl II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "479 and 513 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "ESt-Kartei NRW, \u00a7 19 EStG, A Nr 102)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "13 183-day rule 131 General Taxation remains in the country of residence (- Federal Republic of Germany), provided that all of the following requirements are met (so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "183-day rule): the employee does not stay in the country of employment for more than 183 days in total during the respective tax year (tax year in the country of employment does not need to be identical to the calendar year), and the remuneration is paid by or for an employer who does not is resident in the country of work, and the remuneration is not borne by a permanent establishment or permanent establishment that the employer has in the country of work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Deviations in the individual DTAs must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "the residence of the employer in a third country according to the DBA France, Austria is detrimental to the taxation law of the Federal Republic of Germany, see ESt-Kartei NRW, appendix DBA general, A No. 16132 Determination of the 183-day period, requirement for the 183-day rule (see no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "131) is u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "that the employee does not stay in the country of employment for more than 183 days in total during the respective tax year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The length of stay is decisive for the 183-day period, not the length of the worker's activity in the foreign contracting state"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Several stays in the same contracting state within a tax year for one or more employers must be added together"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The 183-day period is for every tax year or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Check calendar year separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If the tax year deviates from the calendar year, the tax year of the country of activity is decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "A different tax year have z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": ": Australia1 7 to 30 6 Great Britain6 4 to 5 4 Ireland6 4 to 5 4 When determining the 183-day period, the usual work breaks, such as trips home on weekends and public holidays as well as vacation leave, are to be added to the days spent in the country of employment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "This also applies if the employee spends his vacation in the country concerned after his work, but not if he spends his vacation in Germany or in a third country after finishing his work abroad"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If your work abroad is interrupted due to illness, the circumstances of the individual case must be taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If the Stpfl returns to Germany because of the illness, then in the case of a short-term illness (up to 14 days) it can be assumed that the connection with the foreign activity will continue"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Days on which the employee is on the way to or from his foreign place of work (travel days) are also counted towards the days of stay in the country of employment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to days of arrival or departure on which the employee does not or no longer travels to the country of employment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "133 Payment by an employer based in the country of activity Prerequisite for the 183-day rule (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "131) is u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "that the remuneration is paid by or for an employer who is not resident in the country of activity"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Employer i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "of the DBA is the entrepreneur to whom the employee owes his employee performance economically"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "As a rule, this is the person under whose direction the employee works and whose instructions he is subject to (see BFH of 21 8 1985 BStBl II 1986 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "4 in the case of an employee who was released from work at the foreign subsidiary)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "If a domestic company has a permanent establishment abroad, the employer is i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "of the DBA the domestic company and not the foreign permanent establishment (see also BFH of 29 1 1986 BStBl II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "442)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "134 Payment of wages at the expense of a permanent establishment of the employer in the country of employment Prerequisite for the 183-day rule (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "131) is u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "that the remuneration is not borne by a permanent establishment or permanent establishment that the employer has in the country of activity"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The definition in the respective agreement is decisive for the term \"permanent establishment\""}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "After numerous DBAs z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "a construction or assembly site (unlike in accordance with \u00a7 12 AO) only becomes a permanent establishment after a period of 12 months"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "The wages are borne by a foreign permanent establishment to the extent that the activity can be assigned to the permanent establishment (BFH of 24 2 1988 BStBl II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "819)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "These are those wages, salaries, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "which are to be taken into account as remuneration for employment when determining the profit attributable to the permanent establishment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "For details see BMF letter of 21 4 1981 BStBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "It is not decisive who pays the remuneration or who accounts for the remuneration in his bookkeeping, or whether the remuneration is initially paid by the parent company and later passed on to the foreign permanent establishment in the form of a cost allocation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "A subsidiary (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "GmbH) is not a permanent establishment of the parent company, but may"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "even employer i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "of the DBA"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "14 DBA Italy The DBA Italy 1925 contains neither the term temporary residence nor the progression proviso"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "As a result, wages for hourly work in Italy must also be exempted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "According to the signed draft of the new double taxation agreement (cf. No. 22 b of the final protocol), the crediting method should take the place of the exemption until the time of general application of the new double taxation agreement, cf. my rulings of 25 1 1989 and 15 1 1990 - S-1301 - 69 - St 11 - 34"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "15 Cross-border commuters According to the DBA, special features also apply to cross-border commuters"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "These are employees who work in the border area of \u200b\u200bone country and return daily to their place of residence in the border area of \u200b\u200bthe other country (see ESt-Kartei NRW, appendix DBA Belgium, A No. 3; appendix DBA France, A No. 6)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Deviations apply according to the implementation law for cross-border commuters in the Netherlands (BStBl 1986 I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "115, ESt-Kartei NRW, appendix DBA Netherlands, A No. 5)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "16 Special regulations For artists, athletes, flight and ship personnel, university teachers, students, schoolchildren, apprentices and other trainees, the DTAs contain special, different regulations in some cases"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "2 Work for a public employer in a DBA state If the employee works for a public employer, i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": ", regardless of the place of activity, the state of the treasury has the right to tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "This usually does not apply if the employee has the nationality of the country of employment (so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "Local staff)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to the DBA Italy 1925"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "German teachers in public schools who spend days with the school classes in Italy are not exempt from tax according to the DBA Italy 1925 with their proportional wages"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "3 Foreign employment decree Under the requirements of the foreign work decree (Annex 26 XI of the LStR 1990), foreign income from employment is exempted under the progression proviso (entry of wages in Appendix N to Kz 2736 or 2836 or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "advertising expenses at code 2779 or 2879; see subject 10 part 27 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "3 DA-ADV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "In detail, the following requirements must be met: the Stpfl is an employee of a domestic employer, the foreign activity is for a domestic supplier, manufacturer or contractor, the foreign activity is related to one of the activities listed in Section I No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "1 - 4 of the foreign activity decree, the foreign activity is carried out in a non-DBA state and not in the GDR or Berlin (East), there is no wages from a domestic public fund, the duration of the foreign activity is at least three uninterrupted months from Annexes 1 - 7 were not included"}, {"meta": {"name": "0097588.xml"}, "text": "--- Other tax law Bavaria Baden-W\u00fcrttemberg North Rhine-Westphalia Administrative instructions 19900828"}]