[{"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion K\u00f6ln S-2230 - 55 - St 121bek"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "OFD M\u00fcnster S-2230 - 116 - St 12 - 31 from 03/02 / 92S-2230 -EStG: 13EStG: 13aEStG: 4 / 1EStG: 4 / 3Income tax assessment of farmers and foresters for the assessment period 19901 General2 Determination of profit from agriculture and forestry according to average rates (Section 13a EStG) 3 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry by comparing the operating income with the operating expenses (Section 4 (3) EStG) 4 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry through bookkeeping (Section 4 (1) EStG) 5 Estimate of the profit for farmers and foresters whose profit cannot be determined according to average rates [dot] 6 Miscellaneous1 GeneralThe assessment orders for farmers and foresters will in future be published in full in the event of significant changes (changes compared to the previous text are - with the exception of purely editorial changes - indicated by vertical lines)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2 Determination of profit from agriculture and forestry according to average rates (Section 13a EStG) 21 Scope of application Supplementary to Section 127 Paragraphs 5 - 10 EStR and No. 2 of the BMF's introductory letter of 27 March 1981 (Federal Tax Gazette 1981 I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "282), the following is pointed out: 211 Areas to be considered The self-cultivated, own, leased and set-aside areas due to public funding programs must be taken into account (Section 124 Paragraph 3 S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2 and 3 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "212 Regarding Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 2 EStG (initial value limit) The initial value determined in accordance with Section 13a Paragraph 4 EStG is decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Cattle surcharges can therefore not be taken into account as long as they are not the subject of a value update according to \u00a7\u00a7 41 i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "V with \u00a7 22 Paragraph 1 No. 1 BewG have been made"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Something else only applies if the requirements of Section 13a Paragraph 4 No. 1 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "4 EStG are fulfilled"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "213 On \u00a7 13a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG (animal population limit) According to Section 127 Paragraph 7 EStR and No. 22 of the introductory letter of the Federal Ministry of Finance of 27 3 1981 a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": ", is to be applied accordingly when examining the VE limits of Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG Section 124 a EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The prerequisite for the elimination of the determination of the average rate of profit is that the number of VE sustainably exceeds the limits of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "For the term sustainability, reference is made to Section 135 (4) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In the case of a gradual increase in the number of animals, it therefore depends on whether the number of animals converted into VE has been above the limits of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG over the three preceding financial years"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If this is the case, the requirements of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG are no longer met from the beginning of the fourth financial year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If, on the other hand, the animal population is increased significantly above the maximum permissible limits in one go - e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "in connection with an expansion of the barn capacities - so that the limits can be expected to be exceeded in the following financial years as well, the requirements of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG do not apply from the time the maximum limits are exceeded for the first time"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The maximum number of animals permitted in accordance with Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 3 13 Paragraph 1 No. 1 EStG and converted into VE can be found in the overview attached as Annex 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "When determining animal populations, foreign animals must also be taken into account (BFH judgment of 23 September 1988 BStBl 1989 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "111)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "22 Determination of profit The scheme for determining profit according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 to 8 EStG results from the form \"Annex ESt 2 L / 3 L - Determination of profit according to \u00a7 13a EStG -\""}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In detail, I would like to point out the following: 221 Basic amount When determining the basic amount according to Section 13a Paragraph 4 EStG, Sections 124 a Paragraph 3 and 130 a Paragraph 2 EStR must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "222 Value of the work performance In the case of the basic amount according to Section 13a (4) EStG, it is assumed that the business is managed exclusively with paid workers (see Section 36 (2) BewG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The value of the work performed by the business owner and his relatives who are not employed in the company on the basis of an employment relationship to be determined in accordance with Section 13a (5) EStG must therefore be added to the basic amount (Section 13a (3) No. 2 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Section 130 a Paragraph 3 to 5 EStR must be observed here"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In detail, the following is pointed out: When determining the value of the work performance for the physical cooperation of the business owner and the relatives who are not employed, only the work performance is to be taken into account in the result, which is based on the area recorded in the initial value according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 4 EStG in the individual case not applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The paid workers are to be counted towards the appropriate number of full-time workers (VAK) according to the duration of their employment (\u00a7 13a Abs 5 Nr 5 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to temporary workers employed on a short-term basis as well as to workers who have been made available by contractors for ordering, maintenance or harvesting work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "For the crediting of the paid VAK is gg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "a breakdown of the wages is necessary, insofar as what) is applicable to the uses contained in the initial value (Section 13a (4) EStG) and b) to the uses not contained therein (BFH judgment of 14 4 1988 BStBl 1988 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "774)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Make Stpfl in the tax return (form \"Annex L\") to the extent / proportion of their employment or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "the activities of other people (relatives, third parties) in the company or no or obviously incorrect information on the part of the work attributable to special uses, the (physical) work or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "the proportion of the work performed by the business owner, the relatives employed in the business and / or the remunerated workers, if applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "with the assistance of the responsible official agricultural expert (ALS)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The tables printed in Felsmann's comment in Section C 219 219 a about the average labor requirement for special branches of business can also serve as a guide to determine the proportion that is attributable to special uses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "For the value of the work done by the owner of a part-time business, see Section 130 a Paragraph 3 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "7 and 8 EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Deviating from this, the value of the work is to be set at 02 VAK for an initial value of up to DM 15,000 and 03 VAK for an initial value of over DM 15,000 to 32,000 (decree of FinMin NRW dated 8 7 1991 S-2149 - 3 - VB 2 announced with ruling dated 6 8 1991 S-2149 - 12 - St 121)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "For examples of calculating the value of the work, see Annex 2223 Collected Lease Interest Reference is made to Section 13a (6) No. 2 EStG and Section 130a (6) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The rent received also includes income from ground rent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Income from hunting leases, on the other hand, is compensated by applying the basic amount insofar as it is attributable to areas included in the initial value"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "224 Profits according to Section 13a (8) EStG Reference is made to Section 13a (8) EStG and Section 130a (8) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In addition, please note the following: Profits from operations that were not taken into account when determining the initial value are, in particular,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": ": Additional profits from the sale of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals (cf. No. 2241), profits from renting rooms to holiday guests, insofar as it is income from agriculture and forestry (reference to Section 103, Paragraph 7 of the BewRL), interest income insofar as the capital claim is attributable to the business assets, profits from the rental of own horses, insofar as it is income from agriculture and forestry (for delimitation reference to Section 135 Paragraph 11 EStR), profits from pensioner animal husbandry and wage rearing (see No. 2242), Profits from investments that belong to the agricultural and forestry business assets, profits from the rental of buildings and parts of buildings belonging to the agricultural business assets, profits from the sale of milk quotas and sugar beet quotas, compensation for economic difficulties (BFH judgment of 17 5 1990 BStBl 1990 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "891)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Profits from the cross-company use of machines, which are achieved in the context of agriculture and forestry, are in part to be recorded in accordance with Section 13a (8) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In this respect, reference is made to the ESt-Kartei NRW, \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, A No. 103"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The Stpfl can determine the profits (additional profits) according to \u00a7 13a Abs 8 EStG either by comparing assets according to \u00a7 4 Abs 1 EStG or by comparing the operating income and operating expenses (\u00a7 4 Abs 3 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If no records are available, the profits (additional profits) are to be estimated (Section 130 a Paragraph 8 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "9 to 12 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "When estimating the profits (additional profits) from sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals, from animal husbandry, from vegetable and fruit growing, from asparagus and strawberry cultivation and from trout pond farming, the following guidelines can serve as a guide"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Their application must not lead to an obviously incorrect taxation (see BFH judgment of 16 12 1965 BStBl 1966 III p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "193)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "For the determination of the profit, see BFH judgment of 14 4 1988 BStBl 1988 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "7742241 Sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals From the sale of breeding cattle, only extraordinary income is to be recorded as a surcharge according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 8 No. NRW, \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, A No. 118)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Extraordinary income is to be regarded as exceeding the individual selling prices including sales tax: Breeding bulls 4200 DMBreeding cows and cattle 3200 DMBreeding boars1100 DMBreeding sows1000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "the amount by which the selling price exceeds the value of 7500 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If sales proceeds of more than DM 16,250 are achieved, the full amount of DM 11,000 (DM 7500 + 40%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "of 8,750 DM)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Wages for paid workers as well as selling costs (auction fees, insurance contributions, transport costs, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": ") are taken into account in the amount of these values \u200b\u200band cannot be deducted separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The additional profit must be calculated individually for each year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Offsetting with sales proceeds that are below these values \u200b\u200bis not permitted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The same procedure must be followed if above-average prices are achieved for breeding animals other than those specified or for other particularly valuable animals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The underlying value in these cases results from the tax production costs of the animal species in question plus 45%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2242 Profits from animal husbandry In pension animal husbandry, income and profits are essentially dependent on the type of husbandry (stable or paddock husbandry), the type of animal kept (e"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Horses or cattle) and the services (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "for horses also use of riding arenas)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In the case of pension horse keeping, the income includes payments for keeping and caring for the horses as well as remuneration for the use of riding arenas"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The income fluctuates depending on the location of the business and the type of services offered between 250 DM and about 600 DM / month per retired horse"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "When determining the profit, the BFH judgment of 14 4 1988 BStBl 1988 II S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "774 to be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The net profit for boarding horses is usually 60%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "of receipts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2243 Vegetable growing (agricultural and horticultural vegetable growing) For the delimitation of agricultural and horticultural vegetable growing, see Sect. 108 Paragraph 2 and 607 Paragraph 1 No. 1 BewRL"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If vegetable growing is then to be assigned to agricultural use, a surcharge according to Section 13a (8) EStG is not possible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Vegetable cultivation in the context of agricultural use only occurs if headed cabbage (white, red and savoy cabbage), picking peas and picking beans are grown exclusively according to agricultural cultivation methods as part of the agricultural crop rotation as the main crop"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "On the other hand, if the types of cabbage and / or peas or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Do not alternate beans with other agricultural crops such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Wheat, rye, barley, oats or beets, but one after the other or alternately with the same or different types of vegetables (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Endive, lettuce, lamb's lettuce, spinach, carrots, celery, beetroot, onions, radishes, leeks, tomatoes, kohlrabi, cucumbers, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": ") cultivated, the cultivation is no longer part of the agricultural crop rotation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Rather, it is a vegetable cultivation that is to be assessed according to horticultural principles (vegetable cultivation division of the horticultural use of vegetables, flowers and ornamental plants), which is to be recorded as a surcharge under the conditions of Section 13a (8) No. 1 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If, in individual cases, an estimation method tailored to the company's circumstances is not preferable, or if the accounting results of comparable farms or empirical values \u200b\u200bare not available, the profit can be estimated as follows: field vegetable growing income between 40,000 and 80,000 DM / ha, profit 40 to 65 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Income Vegetable growing with covered cultivation area Income between 80,000 and 135,000 DM / ha, profit 30 to 65 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "of receipts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The profit is influenced by the type of marketing (auction in the wholesale market, sale on the farm, sale on the weekly market) and the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "An accurate estimate in individual cases is usually only possible in close cooperation with the ALS"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2244 Fruit growing The income usually fluctuates between 15,000 and 35,000 DM / ha"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "They depend on the type of fruit, the types of fruit, the age structure of the orchard, the quality of the soil and the climate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Special natural events such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Late frosts can lead to lower income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The profit can be as high as 30 to 50 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "of revenues are estimated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "It is influenced by the type of marketing (auction in the wholesale market, sale from the farm, sale at the weekly market) and the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "No. 2243 last paragraph applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2245 Asparagus cultivation The income generally fluctuates between 24,000 and 34,000 DM / ha"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The profit can be 30 to 60 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "of revenues are estimated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "It is influenced by the type of marketing (auction in the wholesale market, sale from the farm, sale at the weekly market) and the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "No. 2243 last paragraph applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2246 Strawberry cultivation The income usually fluctuates between 25,000 and 50,000 DM / ha, the profits between 50 and 70 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "of receipts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The amount of income and profits are influenced by the type of marketing (sale on the farm, auction or by self-pickers) and by the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "No. 2243 last paragraph applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2247 Trout pond farming The profits are usually 35% for full operations (mainly food fish production)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "of income, breeding farms (mainly fish farming) 40 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "of receipts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If no information is given on the income, the following framework rates can be used for the profits: operating mode framework rates, DM / sqm average rate, DM / sqm labor requirement, VAK / ha full operations10 - 402004 breeding operations4 - 401804 In individual cases, the profit can be increased by up to 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "be increased or decreased"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "An increase in profit comes into consideration, in particular, if fish farming is carried out exclusively or predominantly or if table trout are largely refined into smoked trout"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "A reduction can be considered if it can be proven that losses had to be accepted due to low water inflow and poor water quality"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The above profit rates do not yet take into account wages, rent, lease and debt interest; the costs (shares) attributable to the pond management can therefore still be deducted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "225 Value in use of the apartment 2251 Approach of the value in use Reference to Section 130 a Paragraph 7 EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "With regard to the value in use of the apartment for the elderly, insofar as Section 52 Paragraph 15 S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "4 EStG is not applicable, the BFH judgment of 28 7 1983 (BStBl 1984 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "97) must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the value in use is to be attributed to the owner even in the case of real security and to be taken into account in the corresponding amount as a permanent burden in accordance with Section 10 (1) No. 1 a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2252 Loss of value-in-use taxation In cases of deselection of value-in-use taxation, form no 724/74 (questionnaire on the withdrawal of an apartment from business assets) must be sent to determine the facts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If the value-in-use taxation does not apply to the fiscal year deviating from the calendar year, particular attention must be paid to the fact that the value in use still to be assessed up to 31 December is included in the profit for the fiscal year and is to be allocated to the different calendar years on a pro-rata basis according to Section 4a (2) No. 1 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "As far as the value in use taxation according to \u00a7 52 Abs 15 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "4 EStG is retrospectively deselected, the application also regularly affects the amount of income from the previous year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If the assessment of the previous year has already been finalized, it must be changed in accordance with Section 175 (1) No. 2 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "226 Lease interest paid, interest on debts, permanent encumbrances On \u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2 EStG as well as Section 130 a Paragraph 9 EStR is referred to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Interest subsidies from public funds reduce the deductible debt interest"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Regarding the income tax treatment of the interest reduction subsidies according to the agricultural credit program, see ESt-Kartei NRW, \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG A No. 114. For the tax treatment of the current account interest, the principles of the BFH decision of July 4, 1990 (BStBl 1990 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "817) must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "227 Other additions and reductions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The following can be considered: additions and deductions according to \u00a7 6c EStG, increased deductions for residential buildings according to \u00a7 7b EStG i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "V with \u00a7 52 EStDV, insofar as the value in use taxation according to \u00a7 52 Paragraph 15 S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2 EStG is continued"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "This reduction does not apply from the 1994/1995 financial year onwards. Profit deductions according to \u00a7 78 EStDV The increased deductions according to \u00a7 7b EStG must be taken into account before the profit deduction according to \u00a7 78 EStDV (BFH judgment of 26 10 1989 BStBl 1990 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "292)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The profit deduction according to \u00a7 78 EStDV cannot lead to a loss from agriculture and forestry (see \u00a7 78 Abs 3 EStDV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The other increased deductions according to \u00a7\u00a7 7c, d, h, i and k EStG, 82a, g and i EStDV and according to the Protection Building Act cannot be taken into account when determining profits according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 to 7 EStG, because with the average rates the Depreciation and thus also the increased deductions that replace them are in principle compensated (see BFH judgment of 7 6 1984 BStBl 1984 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "663)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "However, if an asset is used in a part of the business whose full income is to be recorded in accordance with Section 13a (8) EStG, increased deductions can also be taken into account when determining the profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "23 Voluntary business assets When determining profits according to \u00a7 13a EStG, arbitrary business assets cannot be formed (BFH judgment of 23 5 1991 BStBl 1991 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "798)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In the event of a change in use, however, voluntary business assets can be retained (Section 13 a Paragraph 3 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "4 EStR, ESt-Kartei NRW, \u00a7 4 Abs 1 EStG, A 54)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "3 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry by comparing the operating income with the operating expenses (Section 4 Paragraph 3 EStG) 31 Scope of application Reference is made to Section 127 Paragraph 3 EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "32 Profit determination Refer to section 17 EStR and the following: 321 Average livestock values \u200b\u200bThe average rating (section 125 EStR) permitted for bookkeeping farmers and foresters can also be used under certain conditions when determining profits in accordance with Section 4 (3) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise reference is made to No. 441"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "322 Value in use of the apartment To determine the value in use of the apartment, reference is made to the ESt-Kartei NRW, \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, A No. 100"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the value in use is to be measured according to the circumstances of the individual case, even for farmers and foresters"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise, No. 225 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "4 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry through bookkeeping (Section 4 (1) EStG) 41 Scope of application On section 127 (1) EStR and on the BMF letter of 15 December 1981 (BStBl 1981 I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "878 Annex 6 to the income tax manual) is pointed out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Cattle surcharges are also to be taken into account when determining the economic value limit according to \u00a7 141 Paragraph 1 No. 3 AO if they are not or not yet the subject of a value update according to \u00a7\u00a7 41 i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "V with 22 para 1 no 1 BewG have been made"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "42 Opening balance sheets To review the opening balance sheets when transitioning to the comparison of business assets, reference is made to the order of 12 1 1984 S-2230 - 53 - St 113"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "This instruction is z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "particularly with regard to the BFH rulings of 17 3 1988 (BStBl 1988 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "770), 14 4 1988 (BStBl 1988 II 672) and from 17 5 1990 (BStBl 1990 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "891) revised"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "43 Bookkeeping On section 12 EStR and the BMF letter of 15 12 1981 a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": ", being point out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "44 Determination of profit 441 Average livestock values \u200b\u200bReference is made to section 125 of the Income Tax Regulation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The applicable average livestock values \u200b\u200bresult from the ESt-Kartei NRW, \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, A No. 20 For the evaluation of horses, reference is additionally made to the ESt-Kartei NRW, \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, A No. 111"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "442 Value in use of apartment number 322 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "5 Estimate of the profit for farmers and foresters whose profit cannot be determined using average rates"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "51 General In the case of farmers and foresters who are obliged to keep accounts but do not keep proper books, the profit is to be estimated in individual cases in accordance with \u00a7 162 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to those farmers and foresters who are neither obliged to keep accounts nor meet the requirements of Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 2 and 3 EStG if they do not keep books within the meaning of Section 4 Paragraph 1 EStG and also not the operating income and - have recorded expenditures within the meaning of Section 4 Paragraph 3 EStG (Section 127 Paragraph 2 to 4 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The estimate has - with the exception of the in Section 127 Paragraph 4 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "7 second half-sentence of the EStR - to be carried out according to the principles of Section 4 (1) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "When making the estimate, all circumstances that are significant for the estimate must be taken into account (Section 162 (1) p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The aim of the estimate must be to determine the profit actually achieved"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "However, the uncertainties inherent in an estimate are at the expense of the Stpfl, who himself gave cause for the estimate by neglecting his tax cooperation obligations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "It must also be ensured that farmers who are required to keep accounts and whose profits are estimated are reported to the tax auditors if an examination appears to be suitable to encourage the farmer to set up accounts or if the examination promises success for other reasons"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If a tax audit is planned in this sense, the assessment is to be carried out subject to a follow-up audit (Section 164 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "According to the principles of the FinMin NRW decree of 31 7 1989 S-0337 - 1 - VC 2, it is announced by order of 9 8 1989 S-0337 - 10 - St 312 whether an estimate is to be carried out in other cases subject to review to decide"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The following explanatory text must be included in the notification or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "to be attached as an attachment: \"The profit from agriculture and forestry for the financial year 19"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "/ 19th"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "was estimated according to \u00a7 162 AO because you did not declare your winnings or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "because you declared a profit that was not determined by bookkeeping, although you are obliged to keep the books"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If you actually achieved a higher profit than the estimated, the tax would have been set too low"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In this case, there may be tax evasion or a frivolous tax reduction"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "However, you can then by declaring the actual profit under the further requirements of \u00a7\u00a7 371 378 Paragraph 3 AO criminal or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Obtain no fines"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Furthermore, I would like to point out that failure to comply with the accounting obligation can already result in a tax risk"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "\"52 Estimation of the profit according to standard rates Which estimation method is to be used in the individual case is left to the discretion of the tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If, in individual cases, an estimation method tailored to the particular operational conditions is not to be preferred, or if there are no circumstances particularly influencing the operating result, such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Seed propagation or field vegetable cultivation, exist or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "have been determined in the course of a previous tax audit and accounting results of comparable companies or empirical records are not available, the profit is to be estimated according to the principles of \u00a7 4 Paragraph 1 EStG as follows: starting amount (No. 521) + lease income (No. 522) + surcharges for Profits not paid for with the starting amount or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits (no.523) + value in use of the apartment (no.524)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Wage expenses (No. 525)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Lease expenses, debt interest (No. 526) +"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Other surcharges and reductions (No. 527) = profit for the financial year The guide rates listed below are intended as a guide for an accurate estimate of the profit (Section 127, Paragraph 2, S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "At the same time, a reduction in the estimated profit due to objections to individual points in the valuation process is generally out of the question because special circumstances in an individual branch of the business do not allow any conclusions to be drawn about the profit of the entire business"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The application of the standard rates must not lead to an obviously incorrect taxation (see BFH judgment of 16 12 1965 BStBl 1966 III p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "193)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "521 Starting amount The starting amount per hectare of usable agricultural area (UAA) for the 1990/1991 financial year is as follows:"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "and more of the LN) 1400 DM2 For mixed farming (grassland share 31 to 70%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "der LN) with a root crop content of a) less than 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "the LN1400 DMb) 15 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "and more of the LN1500 DMc) If the root crop content is more than 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "the LN and is in it a sugar beet content of more than 20%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "of the LN, the starting amount increases to 2000 DMd) If the root crop portion exceeds 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "of the LN, are each started 5 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Additional portion of root crops to be added to the above starting amounts for each 200 DM3"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "der LN) with a root crop content of a) less than 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "the LN1400 DMb) 15 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "and more of LN1600 DMc) No. 2 c) and 2 d) apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "4In the case of dairy cow husbandry, the starting amounts (No. 1 - 3) are to be increased according to the average dairy cow herd of the farm as follows: a) less than 05 cows / ha LN by 250 DMb) 05 to less than 1 cows / ha LN by 400 DMc) 1 to less than 15 cows / ha LN by 550 DMd) 15 and more cows / ha LN by 800 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "reference is made to the order of 5 4 1983 S-2150 a - 2 - St 113"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The surcharge is not to be shown separately, but to be incorporated into the starting amounts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Only the pure agricultural production areas belong to the agricultural use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Areas for buildings, courtyards, paths, ditches, field borders, water, land, quarries, sand pits, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Areas are therefore not considered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Areas for house gardens are also not included"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise, Section 124 a Paragraph 3 EStR applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "According to this, areas set aside due to public funding programs are still considered to be used for agriculture"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "For the calculation of the relevant root crop, grassland or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Sugar beet share depends on the size of these shares in the respective marketing year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The areas under cultivation of root crops do not include those areas on which root crops are only grown as catch crops or as catch crops"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Only the meadows and pastures listed in No. 5232 are to be regarded as grassland; the other crops mentioned there (fodder plants) belong to field forage cultivation, the areas of which belong to the field"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "522 Lease income Lease income, ground rent and hunting leases, reduced by proportionate operating expenses, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Property taxes are to be added to the starting amount if they are included in income from agriculture and forestry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "This is the case when the leased or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Hereditary assets belong to the lessor's agricultural and forestry business assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "523 Surcharges for winnings or winnings not settled with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "All profits from sustainable or one-off operating income that are not included in the starting amount are to be added to the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Such surcharges come z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Consideration for additional profits from sales of breeding cattle and other valuable animals as well as whole animal herds Profits from above normal animal husbandry Additional profits from special crops Profits from other special business branches (see \"Special operating income\" on page 4 of Annex L) Profits from the removal and sale of land (see \"Sale / withdrawal of Land \"on page 2 of Annex L) Profits from the rental of buildings and parts of buildings belonging to the business assets Profits from the sale of milk quotas and sugar beet quotas Compensation for economic difficulties"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "5231 Sales of breeding cattle and other valuable animals As additional profit from the sale of breeding cattle and other valuable animals, the amounts by which the individual selling price including sales tax exceeds the following values: - Breeding bulls DM 3400 - Breeding cows and cattle DM 2600 - Breeding boars DM 900 - Breeding sows .800 DM - and riding horses is the extra profit with 60%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "the amount by which the selling price exceeds the value of 6000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If sales proceeds of more than DM 13,000 are achieved, the full amount must be recognized as additional profit, which is DM 8,800 (DM 6,000 + 40%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "of 7000 DM)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Wages for paid workers as well as selling costs (auction fees, insurance contributions, transport costs, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": ") are taken into account in the amount of the above values, so they cannot be deducted separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The additional profit has to be calculated individually for each animal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "A netting with sales proceeds that are below the above values \u200b\u200bmay not be carried out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The same procedure is to be followed if above-average prices are achieved for breeding animals other than those specified or for other valuable animals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The value to be used in these cases results from the tax production costs of the animal species in question plus an assumed profit surcharge of 20% included in the initial value for the area with normal animal husbandry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "5232 Abnormal animal husbandry Profits from animal breeding and husbandry are settled with the starting amount, provided that the average normal animal population is not exceeded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "As animal husbandry paid for with the starting amount, other farms for the first 20 ha LN22 VE / ha14 VE / ha for the next 10 ha LN16 VE / ha08 VE / ha for the next 20 ha LN15 VE / ha07 VE / ha over 50 ha LN a maximum of 90 VE50 VEDie Animal husbandry in VE, which is settled with the starting amount, can also be found in the overview attached as Annex 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Forage farms are farms where the forage area is 60 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "and more of the usable agricultural area without courtyard and building space, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "matters"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In this context, the forage area includes: Meadows (including tree meadows, litter meadows), cattle pastures and arable meadows, as well as the areas under cultivation for clover in pure seed and mixed cultivation, grass clover, alfalfa, seradella, sasparsette, green maize, vetches, sweet lupins and all other forage plants"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Areas on which grain is grown for grain production are not included in the forage area even if the grain is fed to the livestock kept on the farm"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "When calculating the number of animals and converting them into VE, the procedure is in accordance with Section 124 a (2) EStR"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The average herds (lines 80 to 86 of Appendix L) and the animals produced (lines 87 to 93 of Appendix L) are to be summarized"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Care must be taken that no animals are recorded twice"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "For the excess inventory remaining after the normal inventory has been taken into account, the profit for the 1990/1991 financial year is 300 DM / VE"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Wages are not taken into account here, so they can still be deducted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "5233 Field vegetable cultivation (agricultural use) Field vegetable cultivation is understood to mean the cultivation of vegetables according to agricultural cultivation methods within the framework of agricultural crop rotation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "A distinction must be made between field vegetable cultivation in annual cultivation and field vegetable cultivation as a replica"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Additional profit not settled with the starting amount (No. 521) is to be set for the 1990/1991 financial year: Annual crop: 7,000 DM less the amount per hectare / UAA set in the starting amount for this area"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "It is up to the Stpfl to provide evidence of the actual proceeds from vegetable growing in the fields"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In these cases, a discount of 25 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "be acknowledged"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The remaining amount is only to be reduced in the case of field vegetable cultivation in annual cultivation by the amount per hectare / UI set in the starting amount for this area"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The above standard rates do not take into account wages and can therefore be deducted separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "5234 Vegetable growing (horticultural use), fruit growing, asparagus and strawberry growing as well as trout pond farming Nos. 2243 to 2247 apply accordingly for the determination of the profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "As a surcharge on the starting amount, however, only the additional profit, i.e."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "the profit reduced by the pro-rata starting amount applied in the individual case"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "524 Value in use of apartment number 322 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "When estimating the profit, the gross value in use must always be applied, because the expenses associated with the apartment - with the exception of interest on debt (No. 526) and the increased deductions (No. 527) - are taken into account when determining the starting amounts (No. 521) and are thus compensated are"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "525 Wage expenses The starting amount (No. 521) is based on the assumption that the business is managed exclusively with unpaid workers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Wage expenses are therefore to be deducted from the starting amount insofar as they relate to the profits settled with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The treatment of wage expenses incurred with profits or income not paid for in the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits (see No. 523) are related to the respective surcharge regulations (see No. 5231 to 5234)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "For the distribution of wage expenses required in individual cases, No. 222 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2 and 3 apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The wage expenses to be deducted also include the expenses for temporary workers employed on a short-term basis as well as for the workers who have been made available by contractors for ordering, maintenance or harvesting work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If wage expenses in connection with machine expenses are invoiced in one sum by contractors, there are generally no concerns that the proportionate wage expenses to be taken into account at 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "to estimate the gross expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "526 Lease expenses, debt interest Such expenses can be deducted if they are operating expenses and have not already been taken into account when determining the surcharges according to No. 523"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The lease payments then attributable to the profit settled with the starting amount are not fully deductible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The lease compensates for expenses that are already included in the starting amount as operating expenses (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Property tax, apportionment of the Chamber of Agriculture)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The lease payments are therefore to be reduced by the amount contained therein, which is allotted to such expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "There are no concerns about reducing this amount to 10 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "to estimate the rent payments"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In special individual cases, it may be justified to reduce the amount to 5 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "lower if excessive and no longer local rent is paid"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "527 Other surcharges and reductions 5271 Increase in the starting amount due to the use of third-party buildings (AfA) When calculating the starting amount, the deductions for wear and tear from the value of the company buildings are taken into account in accordance with \u00a7 7 EStG, because it is assumed that the owner manages the business himself becomes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In cases of leasing or free leasing of agricultural operations in whole or in part of a business with buildings, the depreciation for the business buildings is available to the lessor or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "to the farmer leaving the property free of charge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In the case of the authorized user, the starting amount must therefore be increased by 100 DM / ha of leased LN"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "It is left to the authorized user to prove the depreciation in detail"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "5272 Reduction of the starting amounts due to increased deductions for residential buildings As such come - as far as the value in use taxation according to \u00a7 52 Abs 15 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "2 EStG is continued - e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "increased deductions for residential buildings according to \u00a7 7b EStG and in other cases increased deductions according to \u00a7\u00a7 7c, d, h, i, k EStG, 82a, g and i EStDV"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "These increased deductions are, however, by the depreciation already taken into account in the starting amount according to \u00a7 7 Abs 4 EStG in the amount of 2 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "to shorten"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "5273 Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV can be deducted from the starting amount if the list is kept according to \u00a7 7a, paragraph 8 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In these cases, I ask you to request the directory and to attach a copy of the income tax file"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "After the expiry of the preferential period of three financial years, the starting amount is to be increased by a surcharge when claiming the preferential treatment according to \u00a7 76 EStDV, since according to \u00a7 7a Abs high depreciation amounts would be taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The surcharge for a financial year results from the total of the special depreciation granted divided by the remaining useful life of the respective asset"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The initial amount must be increased for the remaining period of use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In order to ensure that it is also taken into account in future assessments, the control sheet for profit surcharges (\u00a7 76 EStDV), form no. 724/49 must be kept and attached to the income tax file"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "6 Other 61 Partial old-age benefits The values \u200b\u200bof the non-cash partial old-age benefits are to be estimated in accordance with Section 1 Paragraph 1 SachBezV in the version applicable to the respective VZ (Section 87 Paragraph 4 S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "7 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The values \u200b\u200bare published annually in BStBl I."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "611 For the VZ 1990 and 1991 the following values \u200b\u200bcan be used as a basis without individual proof: 19901991 for meals with an elderly divider 3499 DM 3564 DM with an elderly married couple 6298 DM6415 DM for heating and lighting with an elderly divisor777 DM792 DM with an elderly married couple1399 DM1426 DM With regard to the value of heating and lighting, however, there are no concerns from Stpfl to the pro rata, based on the energy bills or similar"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "the actual costs determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "612 If partial retirement benefits exist based on farm handover agreements between parents and children not only consist of benefits in kind and in kind, it must be checked in each individual case whether the individual partial benefits are life annuities or permanent burdens (recurring payments) (Section 167, Paragraph 1, No. 2 b EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If the value-in-use taxation ceases to apply on December 31, 1990, the pensionable person obliged to deduct the value in use of the apartment up to this point in time as special expenses in full in the 1990 calendar year, although according to Section 4a (2) no The value in use is only taxable in the 1991 calendar year (cf. No. 225)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "62 Control notifications Except in the usual cases (control notifications for the purposes of the Bp, the recording of taxable transactions with other taxpayers, inheritance tax), control notifications are to be prepared in the following cases in particular:"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "to disclose circumstances arising from the files that may affect the level of the fixed unit values \u200b\u200b(e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Change of the areas for special uses, changes in the animal population - see also order of 4 10 1977 S-3122 - 4 - St 241)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Information that may be of importance for an award according to \u00a7 41 BewG is summarized on page 4 of Annex L."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "I therefore ask in all cases in which the animal population declared in Appendix L obviously exceeds or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "in which, for other reasons, a surcharge according to \u00a7 41 BewG may be considered, the assessment body can be informed by sending a copy of page 4 of Annex L."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "b) Are access or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Leases known, so the lessor or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Inform the leaseholder of the competent assessment office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to the transfer of use free of charge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "In addition, I ask you to ensure that the Stpfl on page 2 of Annex L the address of the lessee / lessor, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "specify exactly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "c) In particular, cases without signal \"A\", in which wage expenses are claimed, and cases with significant wage expenses are to be reported to the responsible wage tax office for examination by the wage tax field audit (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "No. 525)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "63 Standard value notifications Unit value notifications for agricultural and forestry assets must always be evaluated promptly, particularly because of the possible effects on the way in which the Stpfl's profit is determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "64 Consultation of the valuation files when carrying out the assessment In particular when determining profits in accordance with Section 13a of the Income Tax Act (EStG) and in valuation cases, I ask that you refer to the assessment files for the assessment and review of the values \u200b\u200bto be applied in the individual case when calculating profits"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "65 Review of the Annex L According to \u00a7 150 Para. 1 and 2 AO, book-keeping farmers are also obliged to fill out tax returns including the annexes and thus in particular also Annex L completely and truthfully"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "This applies in particular to the area data in lines 32 to 49 of Annex L, which are not only indispensable for the taxation of appraisal farmers, but also"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "also serve to check the applicable profit determination method, to test profits and to be able to monitor value updates"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The section \"Sale / Withdrawal of Land\" contains the essential basic information required to examine profits from sales and withdrawals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If the required information can be clearly found in the individual case from the balance sheet or similar documents, a reference in Annex L to the relevant documents is sufficient"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The information on page 4 of Annex L on the livestock population is used to distinguish between agricultural and commercial animal breeding or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Animal husbandry, for checking the accounting requirements and, if necessary,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "the applicable type of profit determination is important"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "I would therefore ask you to ensure that farmers and foresters who keep books also fill out Appendix L in full"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If this does not happen, the system must be returned for the purpose of completion"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "If this has not yet been done, it should be advisable to advise consultants who, to the knowledge of the tax office, look after farmers and foresters to a large extent, in good time before submitting the next tax return, of the requirement to fill out Annex L in full"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "The plants were not included"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105421.xml"}, "text": "Income tax / wage tax / church tax Accounting North Rhine-Westphalia Agriculture"}]