[{"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The Federal Minister of Finance IV B 1 - S-2532 - 81/91 S-2532 S-2532 -S-2532 | SAre for tax items that were realized after 31122004, by BdF IV C 6 - O-1000/07/0018 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "29 3 2007 (coordinated state decree - \"Letter to contain the flood of standards\") FinMin RP S-2121 A - 442 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "2 8 1991 BdF IV B 7 - S-1900 - 97/91 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "6 5 1991 Processing of the 1990 annual returns in the acceding area 1 General 2 General legal basis for the assessment 3 Overview of forms (annual returns, attachments and instructions) without VAT return for the 2nd half of 1990 4 Review of the accounting part in the annual returns 5 Assessment procedure 6 Entry and account assignment in the IABV 7 Basic information in In the context of the annual return 8 Information on income taxation 9 Tax-free accumulation reserve according to \u00a7 3 Paragraph 2 St\u00c4G 10 Tax exemption for re-privatized companies 11 Tax withholding amount according to \u00a7 9 Paragraph 1 DB to the St\u00c4G 12 Limited tax liability 13 Foreign income / importance of double taxation agreements 14 Calculation of the tax when 15 trade tax is combined 16 Property tax 17 Corporate income tax 18 Procedural law 19 Compensation payments for wage policy measures 20 Social security issues 1 General The assessment must begin immediately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In the cases in which the declaration is not deviated from, the forms Disposal (income tax assessment), disposition (determination), disposition (corporation tax assessment) must be used"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In all other cases, the relevant calculation sheet must be used and a tax assessment must always be issued"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "All tax assessments are subject to review (Section 164 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "2 General legal bases of the assessment 21 Procedural law AO 1970 - GDR -, GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 681; AO 1990 - GDR - and the introductory law issued for it, GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 1428; AO 1977 22 Income tax legal bases for natural and legal persons EStG in the version v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "18 9 1970 GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 670; K\u00f6StG in the version v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "18 9 1970 GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 671; Order on the taxation of tradespeople, self-employed and other taxable citizens - Taxation guidelines - v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "24 8 1979 GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 1016; Tax Amendment Act - St\u00c4G - v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "6 3 1990 Journal of Laws I No. 17 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "136; Implementation regulation - DB - v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "16 3 1990 to the St\u00c4G, GBl I No. 21 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "195; Tax Adjustment Act - StAnpG - v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "22 6 1990 GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 1427; DB v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "22 6 1990 to the StAnpG, GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 1427 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "127; Law on the opening balance sheet in German marks and the capital redefinition in the manner specified in Art"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "4 of the law on the removal of barriers to the privatization of companies and the promotion of investments, amended version (D-Markbilanzgesetz - DMBilG -), BStBl I 1991 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "713; Tax Amendment Act 1991 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "24 6 1991 BStBl I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "665; Order on the tax exemption of income from the rental of rooms to the FDGB holiday service and the facilities of the spa and bathing sector of 1 4 1974 GBl I No. 20 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "195; Depreciation tables, published by the Ministry of Finance in 1990 only valid for the second half of 1990, distribution: Verlag Die Wirtschaft Berlin GmbH"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "23 Additional special income tax regulations 231 Craftsmen / flat-rate craftsmen Law on the taxation of craftsmen - HdwStG - v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "16 3 1966 GBl I No. 8 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "71; Order on the tax assessment of the craftsmen v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "16 3 1966 - assessment guidelines - v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "17 3 1966 GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 537; 1 DB to the law on the taxation of craftsmen v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "17 3 1966 Journal of Laws II No. 32 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "183; 3 DB to the law v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "16 5 1968 GBl II No. 54 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "287; 4 DB to the law v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "9 4 1976 Journal of Laws I No. 16 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1221; 5 DB to the law v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "11 2 1986 Journal of Laws I No. 13 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "181 232 Tax-privileged freelance regulation - VO - on the taxation of labor income v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "22 12 1952 GBl I No. 182 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1413 233 Commission dealer (KH) VO on the taxation of KH - KHStVO - v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "24 12 1959 GBl I 1960 No. 2 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "19 in the version of the correction v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "27 2 1960 GBl I No. 12 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "126; 4 DB to VO v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "13 2 1980 GBl 1980 SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 1033 234 Part-time employees VO v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "22 12 1952 on the taxation of labor income (for tax-privileged professional income), GBl No. 182 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1413; VO v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "12 1 1984 on the taxation of sales and profits from the sale of plant and animal products, GBl I No. 3 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "20; Taxation guidelines v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "24 8 1979 at Zimmervermietung, GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 1016; Order on the tax exemption of income from renting rooms to the FDGB holiday service and the facilities of the spa and bathing sector v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1 4 1974 GBl I No. 20 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "195 235 Corporations Order to simplify the collection of taxes for the economic activity of social organizations v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "4 7 1967 GBl II No. 66 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "445; Party Law v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "21 2 1990 Journal of Laws I No. 9 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "66; VO on the taxation of credit unions v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "7 4 1966 GBl II No. 45 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "290; VO for the introduction of the law on the implementation of legal provisions of the Federal Republic of Germany for housing cooperatives of the GDR v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "15 8 1990 GBl I No. 53 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1072 236 Crafts Production Cooperatives Law on Taxation of Crafts Production Cooperatives and their Members - PGH Tax Act - v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "30 11 1962 GBl I No. 13 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "119; 1 DB to the PGH Tax Act v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "4 12 1962 GBl II No. 92 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "777; 5 DB to the PGH Tax Act v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "23 12 1969 GBl II No. 105 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "731; VO on the establishment, activity and transformation of production cooperatives of the craft v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "8 3 1990 Journal of Laws I No. 18 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "164 237 Fiduciary managed property 4 DB for the regulation on self-calculation and on the due dates of taxes and social security contributions - taxation of the income and assets of taxpayers not resident in the German Democratic Republic - v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "27 1 1955 GBl I No. 10 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "97; Order on the repeal of financial regulations v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "10 9 1990 Journal of Laws I No. 62 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1560 24 Sales tax law 241 Sales tax law for the first half of 1990 Legal regulations for sales tax v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1 1 to 30 6 1990 Sales Tax Act (UStG) i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "18 9 1970 GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 673; 1 DB to the Value Added Tax Act v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "20 10 1981 GBl I No. 37 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "436 VAT benefits are regulated in the following legal provisions: Order v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "23 7 1957 on the exemption of sales of various foods in the private retail trade from VAT, GBl I No. 50 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "406 i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "the arrangement v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "24 9 1962 Journal of Laws II No. 74 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "667 - amendment \u00a7 12 -; Arrangement v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "22 3 1958 on the exemption of sales of industrially packaged flour in private retail from VAT, GBl I No. 25 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "337; Arrangement v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "23 7 1958 on the exemption of sales from the delivery of various foodstuffs in cooperative and private production companies from VAT, GBl I No. 53 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "621; Arrangement v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "8 8 1958 on the exemption of sales from freelance work from VAT, GBl I No. 55 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "642; Arrangement v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "9 4 1959 on the exemption of sales from freelance tax-privileged activities of doctors from VAT, GBl I No. 24 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "327; Arrangement v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "26 9 1958 on tax benefits for sales from the delivery of meat, meat and sausage products and animal fats from the USt, GBl I No. 63 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "779; Arrangement v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "16 10 1958 on the exemption of sales from the delivery of leather footwear from VAT, GBl I No. 65 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "798; Arrangement v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1 7 1959 on the application of sales tax exemption for cooperative, semi-public and private production companies, GBl I No. 43 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "620; Arrangement v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "11 9 1959 on the exemption of sales in the orthopedic shoemaker's trade from VAT, GBl I No. 53 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "686; Arrangement v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "21 11 1959 on tax benefits for sales from the delivery of fish and fish products as well as roasted coffee at the USt, GBl I No. 68 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "884; Arrangement v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "5 8 1960 on VAT exemptions, Journal of Laws I No. 48 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "486; Order No. 2 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "29 12 1960 on sales tax exemptions, GBl II 1961 No. 1 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "2 - change -; Arrangement v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "10 2 1966 GBl II No. 19 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "99 - Trade in movable property -; Arrangement v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "24 9 1962 on tax breaks for the sales of late-night potatoes in semi-public and private retail, GBl II No. 74 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "667; Order No. 3 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "10 12 1962 on sales tax exemptions, GBl II No. 99 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "852; Order No. 5 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "25 5 1964 on VAT exemption, Journal of Laws of II No. 54 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "477; Order No. 8 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "18 8 1965 on VAT exemption, Journal of Laws II No. 87 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "643; Internal regulations on VAT relief Instruction No. 7/1975 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "10 6 1975 on the taxation of the optician trade; Instruction No. 9/1978 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "31 7 1978 on the taxation of craftsmen and tradespeople when buying tire casings and selling retreaded tires; Contribution D 1/1 in I-Letter No. 2/80 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "23 10 1980 on the sale of new tires; Instruction No. 5/1987 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "29 6 1987 on tax regulations due to price changes for precious metals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "242 Sales tax law for the 2nd half of 1990 cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "attachment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "25 Trade tax law Trade tax law in the version v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "18 9 1970 GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 672 26 Wealth Tax Law Valuation Act in the version v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "18 9 1970 GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 674; Wealth Tax Act in the version v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "18 9 1970 GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 675; Ordinance on wealth and inheritance tax v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "2 12 1987 Journal of Laws I No. 29 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "282; Law amending the legislation on income, corporation and wealth tax - St\u00c4G - v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "6 3 1990 Journal of Laws I No. 17 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "136; Wealth tax and valuation guidelines - VSt - and BewR 1955 - v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "15 1 1955 GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 70 amended by regulation of 19 January 1961 GBl II No. 9 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "35 arrangement v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "14 5 1974 GBl I No. 26 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "268 and order v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "10 9 1990 Journal of Laws I No. 62 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1560; Tax Amendment Act 1991 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "24 6 1991 BStBl I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "3 Form overview (annual returns, attachments and instructions) without sales tax return for the 2nd half of 1990 Annual return for tradespeople (AV 24/30) Official instructions for AV 24/30 Appendix Production fund tax (AV 24/41) Appendix Wage income (AV 24 / L) Appendix R - Accumulation reserve - (AV 24 / R) Annual declaration for partnerships (AV 24/31) Official instructions for AV 24/31 Annual declaration for freelance workers (AV 8/10) Official instructions for AV 8/10 annual declaration for part-time workers (AV 24/23) Official Instructions for AV 24/23 annual declaration for commission dealers (AV 24/10) Official instructions for AV 24/10 annual declaration for owners of property managed in trust (AV 24/30) Annual declaration for craftsmen (AV 11/30) Official instructions for AV 11/30 annual declaration for craftsmen and small businesses with flat-rate tax (AV 11/22) Official instructions for AV 11/22 Application for reimbursement of fee tax withheld (AV 8/17) Annual declaration for corporations (AV 24 / 32) Official instructions for AV 24/32 Annual Declaration for PGH and AGP (AV 24/1) Official instructions for AV 24/1 Tax certificate of the distributing corporation (Section 11 (3) DB to the St\u00c4G) (VE 8-0 (1990)) Declaration for separate determination of tax bases (\u00a7 47 KStG) for 1 1 1991 (KSt 1 G GDR) For the sales tax return for the 2nd half of 1990 see appendix"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If tax returns were not submitted on the forms from the acceding countries or if incorrect forms from the acceding area were used, the declarations (possibly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "after photocopy) with a special cover letter enclosing the correct forms"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The taxpayer should be asked to re-submit the return using the correct forms"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "4 Review of the accounting section in the annual returns without VAT return for the 2nd half of 1990 41 Processing of the annual returns in the assessment offices The receipt of the annual return is shown in the V-list and in the tally sheet (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "12) and signed in the processing note of the annual declaration (green print) under point 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This is followed by a review of the summary and accounting for 1990 part of the annual declaration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In particular, the amount determined in column 7 must be checked according to the sample on page 3"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "When examining the annual return, the taxpayer must check the correctness of the balance stated by the taxpayer as of 30 6 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "As a result of the monetary union, all balances and outstanding arrears as of 30 6 1990 were reduced by 50%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "reduced"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This resulted in a change in the cumulative target amount in each relevant year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Table 33 and the account statement as of 20 6 1990, on which all changes due to payments, debit changes, transfers and reimbursements were to be entered from 21 to 30 6 1990 serve as the basis for the check in the assessment offices"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Formerly state-owned combines, companies and institutions are generally subject to tax liability from 1 7 1990 (BMF letter v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "3 5 1991 - IV B 7 - S-1900 - 59/91 -, BStBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "506)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Accordingly, a tax rate is only set for the second half of 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "It is therefore important to ensure that the tax rate only includes prepayments that actually represent prepayments on the tax rate for the second half of 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Payments made for the first half of 1990 by corporations that arose from former state-owned enterprises on the basis of the trust ordinance of 1 3 1990 are not tax payments, but payments due to special relationships with the state budget"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This also applies if the payments were made under EAA 153 to 155 or 101"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "These payments are not part of the statements in the context of the AV 24/32 annual returns"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "To make checking easier, the corporations are requested in line 100 of the annual declaration (AV 24/32) to report the payments made under EAA 153 to 155 or 101 for the first half of 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1 half year 19902 half year 1990 Amount, M paid before 1 7 1990, M backpayment + / overpayment - (column 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Column 2), M50 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "from column 3 DM amount, DM paid after 30 6 1990, DM1234561 tax rate acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "row"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "(in Sp"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "5 to be entered) 100006000+ 4000+ 20007000700021000012000- 2000- 1000700070003100006000+ 4000+ 20007000800041000012000- 2000- 10007000600051000015000- 5000- 25007000061000022000- 12000- 600070000 Tax number Amount acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Column 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Column 4 + column 5 M / DM for the year 1990 total arrears / overpayment amount according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Column 7"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Column 12 DMYearEAABA paid (Column 2 + Column 6), M / DM789101112131Tax rate15000901012513000 + 2000218000901012519000- 1000315000901012514000+ 10004180009010125180000519500901012515000, this column is confirmed immediately with a subsequent payment, the subsequent payment is confirmed with an overpayment in the column of the first annual return of 13+ 100042 to forward the treasury to the debit position of the back payment (final payment)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "At the same time as the debit position, the due date for monitoring must be entered in project 713"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "All additional payments are due within 7 days of submitting the annual return"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "For this reason, the date of receipt must be noted on every annual declaration (even if handed over in person)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The date of receipt plus"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Enter 7 days"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "For the purpose of data collection, the treasury creates a block sum from the data of the annual declaration, whereby only annual declarations with the same due date are to be combined in one block"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The data collection office must always confirm this data collection under point 2 of the order printed on the declaration forms"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The cash register checks the debit position"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The annual declaration is then handed over to the assessment office for further processing"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "43 Annual declarations with overpayments If an overpayment (credit) is calculated in column 13, the assessment must be carried out before the annual declaration for debit position is forwarded to the treasury"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Overpayments can be offset against arrears and prepayments that are due soon"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "5 Assessment procedure 51 Assessment without deviation from the annual return If the assessment by the tax assessment agency does not reveal any deviations from the annual return, the posting part of the annual return is entered in a blank line in procedure 713 with posting type 27 with the amount \"0\" on the lowest EAA so that an account statement can be printed out and this account is considered to be billed for 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This annual declaration processed in this way is forwarded to the tax office with a special processing order (separated into income tax, corporation tax and determinations)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The block sum must be entered in an empty account assignment field from the treasury"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The annual declaration must then be forwarded to the data collection office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Then the debit position is checked by the cash supervisor"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The respective processing must be noted in the processing order"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "A copy of the account statement, printed out twice, will be sent to the taxpayer by the tax office as a statement for 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The printed account statement, the annual declaration and the processing order are returned to the tax office after confirmation by the finance office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In the event of reimbursement, the tax office must issue a payment order"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Attention must be paid to attachments and assignments"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The payment order and the account statement will be sent to the treasury for reimbursement"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The finance office may have"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "to offset against other claims"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "52 Assessment with deviations from the annual declaration If the examination of the annual declaration leads to a different determination, this must be made with the calculation sheet for natural persons AV 9/22, the annex to the co-operating spouse AV 9/23, the calculation sheet for partnerships AV 9/25, the Calculation sheet for managed properties AV 9/29, the calculation sheet for corporations AV 9/52, the calculation sheet for PGH AV 9/51"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "A different determination is only to be carried out if the tax rate (column 7 of the accounting section of the annual return) changes by more than 20-- M / DM (analogous application of the Small Amount Ordinance)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the notices of tax and compensation payments AV 9/24, notice for the partnership AV 9/27, notice for the managed properties AV 9/30, notice for corporations AV 9/54, notice for PGH AV 9/53 are to be created"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The calculation sheet and the notification will be sent to the treasury for debit entry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The treasury forms the block sum; then the data must be recorded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The corresponding completion notes are to be attached to the disposal of the calculation sheet"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The finance office enters the date and due date and sends the notification together with a copy of the account statement"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The calculation sheet and a copy of the account statement are returned to the assessment office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "6 Entry and account assignment in the IABV After the introduction of the IABV, postings in project 713 are no longer possible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The posting of the annual declaration is to be made with an unchanged transfer of the final payment / the reimbursement amount calculated by the taxpayer with a special form from the finance office from the data collection point"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In the event of a deviation from the annual declaration, the accounting section \"Initial or changed assessment in the IABV\" contained in all calculation sheets must then be used"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to cases that were processed during the initial data acquisition in project 713, i.e."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Correction postings can then only be entered in the IABV"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Example: 1 half year 19902 half year 1990 amount paid before 1 7 1990 arrears / overpayments (column 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Column 2) 50 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "From column 3 Amount paid after 30 6 1990 MMMMDMM123456100006000 + 4000+ 200070007000 Tax number Tax type Period Posting text Amount acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Column 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Column 4 + Column 5 M / DM192021221110900315000114090031160900311119013 Due date"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "15000 The subsequent payment or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Overpaid amounts are shown in the annual declaration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The multi-item sum (MPS = sum of the individual amounts from column 22) must be entered by the assessment office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If the assessment does not deviate from the annual declaration, the part to be recorded in the IABV (see last section in the statement of the respective calculation sheet) must be attached to the annual declaration in a suitable form and the data to be recorded must be entered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "7 Basic information in the context of the annual return When processing the annual return, the stored basic information for the tax case must be checked and if necessary"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "to update"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In addition to the address data, the following must be carefully checked: a) the account details of the Stpfl; b) Basic and interest code letters for tax cases; c) religious affiliation and timing of the initial assessment of church taxes of a parish with the right to levy; d) as far as possible, storage of the sending characteristics for sending the forms for the 1991 tax return (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "for income from renting and leasing: number of rental residential properties for the applicable number of annexes V); e) if tax advice is available, the attribute \"St\" is to be set in the account (this means that in future no tax return forms will be sent to the Stpfl); f) as far as the Stpfl has appointed an authorized representative / representative for his tax affairs, the scope of the power of attorney is to be determined according to period and the responsibility for determination and collection and to be entered in the account; g) In cases of doubt, the business code must be determined in agreement with the State Statistical Office and stored in the account; after the introduction of the IABV, this also applies to the trade name; h) as far as the spouses and their forms of ownership / activities are still listed under different tax numbers (possibly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "even at different tax offices), from 1991 the accounts are to be merged for income and wealth tax purposes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "8 Notes on income taxation Please refer to the notes in the explanations of the annual returns"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The following must also be observed: 81 Determination of the business tax deductible as business expenses from the tax rate for income / surplus calculation Only the portion of business tax that is included in the tax rate may be used as business expense"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Even if the Stpfl's calculations result in a higher trade tax than is included in the tax rate paid, the trade tax is only deemed to have been paid first in the amount actually paid"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "When the trade tax liability began in the 2nd half of 1990, withholding tax payments were not increased because other parts of the tax rate were no longer applicable in the 2nd half of 1990 (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Production fund tax, payroll tax), the trade tax in the amount of these omitted taxes is deemed to have been paid"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If the trade tax component in the tax rate was higher than the calculated trade tax, this trade tax component remains the business expense"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The overpayment is to be booked as operating income at the time of receipt / offsetting"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If the trade tax liability only occurred in the course of the 1990 calendar year and the tax rate was therefore not increased by a trade tax component, then in this case too, the trade tax for 1990 can only be recognized as a business expense in the amount in which other taxes from the first half of 1990 the were taken into account when determining the advance tax payments, ceased to exist in the second half of 1990 (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Production fund tax, payroll tax)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Example: For tax rates set in 1990, 6000 M / DM, included trade tax portion 1000 M / DM, based on the annual declarations of the taxpayer, calculated trade tax 3000 M / DM, paid trade tax to be assessed in 1990, 1000 M / DM for the VZ 1991 or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Trade tax to be applied to the DC in which the additional payment is made as a business expense2000 DM82 Calculation of the flat rate for business expenses The flat rate for business expenses is based on the gross income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If the flat fee is used, all operating expenses are covered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "83 No offsetting of current losses against capital gains of the first half of 1990 (only for private craftsmen and small businesses as well as shops and restaurants of the commission and private retail trade) Loss compensation of current losses of the calendar year 1990 with capital gains of the first half of 1990 is not possible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This means that capital gains in the first half of 1990 - in contrast to capital gains in the second half of 1990 - are always subject to separate taxation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This also applies if losses from ongoing business operations occurred in the first half of 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If the separate taxation of capital gains for the first half of 1990 results in a tax, this will always be set at the calculated amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Capital gains from the 2nd half of 1990 can be offset against negative current profits from both half-years"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "84 Offsetting of ongoing losses as well as loss carry-back from 1991/1992 to the second half of 1990 According to \u00a7 4 of the DB to the St\u00c4G, both loss compensation within one type of income and loss compensation between several types of income are possible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This applies both to income and corporation tax purposes and to business tax purposes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Accordingly, losses from one half-year can also be offset against profits from the other half-year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Losses in the first half of 1990 can also be offset for the purposes of trade tax if no trade tax is payable for the first half of 1990 due to special forms of taxation (profit tax) (e"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Craftsmen and PGH)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If offsetting is not possible, losses in 1990 can be recognized under the conditions of Section 10d EStG, Section 8 (4) KStG (Section 57 (4) EStG and"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Section 36 (5a) of the Trade Tax Act 1991)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The loss that can be carried forward is to be determined separately as part of the assessment; A notification of this must always be given"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Even if the declaration values \u200b\u200bare accepted, a notification is required to determine the loss that can be carried forward, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "with form AV 9/24 to be issued"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Based on the Tax Amendment Act 1991 of 24 6 1991 (BStBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "665), losses from 1991/1992 can be carried back to the second half of 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This does not apply to trade tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The calculation sheet 1990 contains a corresponding calculation line"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "85 Donation deduction 851 Donation deduction in the first half of 1990 According to \u00a7 2 DB to the St\u00c4G, donations from sponsors up to the amount of 2 per thousand of the turnover of the company or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "deducted from self-employed or freelance work as business expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "852 Donation deduction in the 2nd half of 1990 With \u00a7 10a EStG the StAnpG introduced a limited donation deduction for the 2nd half of 1990 as special expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "When calculating the maximum amounts of donations that can be deducted as special expenses, only the types of income falling within the scope of the EStG may be taken into account, but not the income taxable according to the provisions of the Coreper"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Beneficiary donations may be deducted if they can be shown to have been made in the second half of 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "To limit the donation deduction, the total amount of income for the entire calendar year or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "the sum of the total sales of the second half of 1990 and the wages and salaries expended in the calendar year are decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This rule applies accordingly to corporations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "853 donations to political parties are not deductible in 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "854 Annual declaration AV 24/34 for owners of property administered in trust"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Annual declaration included calculation of income tax at a flat rate of 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "for the 2nd half of 1990 is outdated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "By \u00a7 1 No. 5 of the order on the repeal of financial law provisions v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "10 9 1990 (Journal of Laws I No. 62 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1560) the fourth implementation regulation of 27 1 1955 (Journal of Laws I No. 10 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "97) repealed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "As a result, from 1 7 1990 onwards, the regulation on the flat-rate assessment of income tax at the rate of 25% no longer applies"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "From this point in time the regulations of \u00a7\u00a7 49 and 50 EStG i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "18 9 1970 (GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 670)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The income tax is to be determined on the surplus of the 2nd half year 1990 according to the basic tax rate A."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "It should be noted that the tax should be at least 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": ", at most 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "of the excess"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The calculation sheet AV 9/29 already takes the new legal situation into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "A modified tax assessment is only to be carried out by the tax office if the tax effect is more than 20 M / DM (analogous application of the Small Amount Ordinance)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "9 Tax-free accumulation reserve in accordance with Section 3 (2) St\u00c4G The tax-free reserve must always be calculated in accordance with Appendix R (AV 24 / R)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In the income declared by the Stpfl, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "from business operations, the reserve may not yet be deducted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "A deduction is only possible when determining the total amount of income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If the taxpayer has already deducted the reserve from the income, the deducted amount must be added back to the income so that the profit from business operations is correctly included in the calculation of business tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "When calculating the accumulation reserve, a comparable assessment basis must be assumed for income taxpayers and corporation taxpayers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Accordingly, in the case of corporation taxpayers, the amounts in lines 1 to 3 and 5 of form AV 24/32 are only included in to take over the form AV 24 / R"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In the case of entities that are required to keep accounts, i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "the amounts in line 11 must be adopted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Proceed accordingly at PGH"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Appendix R is to be attached as a monitoring sheet to the income tax file"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "10 Tax exemption for re-privatized companies A separate BMF letter is issued on this"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "11 Tax deduction amount according to \u00a7 9 Abs 1 DB to the St\u00c4G"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "22 7 1991 (BStBl I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "737)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "12 Limited tax liability Persons who are not subject to unlimited tax liability in the accession area in 1990 are subject to limited tax liability with their income from the accession area within the meaning of Section 49 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "For details see BMF letter v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "10 7 1991 (BStBl I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "739)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In each individual case, it must be checked to what extent the limited tax liability can be restricted by a double taxation agreement"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In the case of persons with limited tax liability who are resident in the former Federal Republic of Germany, the BMF letters v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "10 7 1990 (BStBl I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "314) and v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "22 8 1990 (BStBl I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "417) must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Further information, in particular on the taxation of labor income, can be found in the working instructions of the Ministry of Finance of the former GDR v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "22 8 1990 (BStBl I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "546 ff"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "/ 555)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "For the tax deduction of tax-privileged professional income see BMF letter of 19 7 1991 - IV B 4 - S-2500 - 101/91 - (Annex 1)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "13 Foreign income / Significance of double taxation agreements In accordance with the provisions of the Unification Treaty, the double taxation agreements concluded by the former GDR remain in force until December 31, 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The double taxation agreements also include the agreements to avoid double taxation on the income and assets of natural and legal persons between the member states of the Comecon"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "An overview of the DTAs valid until December 31, 1990 is attached as Appendix 2"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The double taxation agreements of the Federal Republic of Germany apply in the accession area from 1 1 1991"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 2 AO 1977)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "For taxpayers with unlimited tax liability who receive income from the respective contracting state, the DTAs regulate how double taxation is to be avoided (usually by exempting income from the other state or by offsetting the foreign tax paid on the income against the domestic tax liability), regulate the extent to which persons who are subject to limited tax liability with income within the meaning of Section 49 EStG may actually be taxed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Insofar as foreign income is to be exempted within the scope of unlimited tax liability on the basis of a double taxation agreement, the income is to be excluded from the tax base"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If, on the other hand, double taxation is avoided by offsetting the foreign tax against the domestic tax liability, the offsetting is based on Section 34 of the Taxation Guidelines v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "24 8 1979 (GBl SDr"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 1016), unless the respective double taxation agreement contains a different regulation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The avoidance of double taxation on foreign income from countries with which there is no agreement on the avoidance of double taxation takes place in accordance with Section 34 of the Taxation Guidelines of 24 August 1979 (a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": ") by offsetting the foreign tax with unlimited tax liability"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In 1990, income from the former Federal Republic of Germany also counts as income from abroad"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "14 Calculation of the tax when several activities come together for income tax 141 Different full-time activities that are subject to the same legal regulation 1411 Required annual declaration Were different full-time activities carried out at the same time, but which comply with the provisions - e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "of the Income Tax Act (EStG), submission of an annual declaration is sufficient"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This means that z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Several full-time income from commercial operations for income tax purposes can be summarized in the line \"Income from commercial operations\""}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "When determining the total income, according to \u00a7 4 DB for the St\u00c4G, loss compensation within the income type and also the offsetting of losses against income from another income type can be made"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1412 Determination of taxable income When determining the total taxable income, it should be noted that, even if several annual returns have been completed, special expenses 50 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "the contributions to the FZR tax class allowances and tax reductions due to extraordinary burdens can only be claimed once"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Tax-privileged freelancers can pay special expenses and 50 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "of the contributions to the FZR are not deducted if they equal the lump sum of the work-related expenses with 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "have used"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1413 Determination of income tax When determining income tax, the total income must be used as the starting point"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "To this end, the respective taxable income must be added from the relevant annual returns"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The income tax according to the basic tax rate A (St\u00c4G) must be calculated on the total taxable income determined in this way"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1414 Determination of the trade tax With regard to the trade tax, it should be noted that the trade tax must be determined separately for each business enterprise"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "142 Various full-time activities that are subject to different legal provisions 1421 Required annual return If a taxpayer has carried out various full-time activities at the same time, the corresponding different annual returns must generally be submitted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If craftsmen or commission dealers earned other full-time income subject to income tax in the second half of 1990, this can be declared in the annual declaration for craftsmen or commission dealers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The statements made under No. 1411 apply accordingly to compensation for losses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1422 Determination of taxable income When determining the total taxable income, it should be noted that even with different annual declarations, special expenses 50 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "the contributions to the FZR tax class allowances and tax reductions due to extraordinary burdens may only be deducted once"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "For reasons of simplification, the highest possible amounts of one of the relevant legal provisions can be used for activities carried out simultaneously"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Tax-privileged freelancers can pay special expenses and 50 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "of the contributions to the FZR are not deducted if they equal the lump sum of the work-related expenses with 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "take advantage of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If the full-time income was earned consecutively or if a full-time activity was given up, the amounts can only be taken into account pro rata temporis (twelfth) according to the period in which the income of the respective type of income was earned"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1423 Determination of income tax See No. 1413 143 Income from full-time activity and wage income 1431 Required annual return"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "AV 8/10)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In addition, there is the wage income annex (AV 24 / L), on which the employer must enter the wages received"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "To determine the wage income, see instructions for the annual declaration AV 24/23 no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "23 In the case of craftsmen and commission dealers, wages are not included, as special taxation rules applied to both groups"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If their co-operating spouses only started their work in the business of the spouse after June 30, 1990, so that at no point in 1990 the special legal provisions applied to them, their wage income must be included in their taxation with the annex wage income (AV 24 / L)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1432 Determination of the taxable income When determining the total taxable income, it should be noted that the taxable income determined in the annual return (AV 24/30 line 60) is transferred to the annex wage income (AV 24 / L) line 9"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1433 Determination of income tax The tax rate is to be determined according to tax rate table C."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The basis is the total income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "There are two calculation steps to consider when determining the tax rate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Determination of the tax rate according to the tax rate table C on the taxable income from the main occupation The taxable income (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Line 60 of form AV 24/30) is transferred to line 9 of the annex wage income (AV 24 / L)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The tax rate according to tax rate table C is determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Tax rate = (tax acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Basic tax rate A) / (total income) The tax rate determined in this way is applied to the taxable income from full-time employment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "After calculating the income tax, this is transferred from Appendix L to the corresponding annual return and the calculation is continued"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Determination of the tax rate according to the tax rate table C on the taxable income from the part-time activity In the form AV 24/23 in line 64 the wage income from Appendix L and the total taxable income from the full-time annual return are to be taken over"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The tax rate on the total taxable income is determined according to the tax rate table C as shown above"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The tax rate is then applied to the taxable income from the secondary occupation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The income tax determined in this way is included in the annual return for the main occupation and then the calculation is continued"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The calculated tax rate is only to be applied to the total taxable income from the main occupation (s)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Income tax is calculated in the wage income annex (AV 24 / L) and then included in the annual return for the further calculation steps"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "144 Income from several part-time activities A separate annual declaration for part-time activity (AV 24/23) must be submitted for each part-time activity"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In the second and every subsequent annual return for part-time workers, income tax is only calculated up to line 45 of the annual return (subtotal)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The result of this line 45 in the second and each subsequent annual declaration must be transferred to line 45 of the first annual summary declaration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The additional income must be added up to the previous subtotal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "According to \u00a7 4 of the DB zum St\u00c4G, a loss that has arisen in a secondary activity, here in line 45 broken down by half-year, can be offset against the positive income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The totalization ensures that the special expenses and pension expenses are only deducted once"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "According to \u00a7 12 St\u00c4G, the tax exemption of 3000 M / DM can only be applied to the total part-time income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "It should be noted that the tax exemption must always be taken into account in the income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "145 Income from full-time and part-time activities as well as wage income 1451 Required annual declaration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "AV 24/30, AV 8/10)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Form AV 24/23 must be submitted for part-time work and the annex wage income (AV 24 / L) for wage income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1452 Determination of taxable income The taxable income must be determined separately in the individual annual returns"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "It should be noted that the special editions 50 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "the contributions to the FZR tax class allowances and tax reductions due to extraordinary burdens may only reduce the income once"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Tax-privileged freelancers can pay special expenses and 50 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "of the contributions of the FZR are not deducted if they include the lump sum of the work-related expenses with 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "take advantage of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1453 Determination of income tax cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "No. 1433 1454 Determination of trade tax With regard to trade tax, it should be noted that"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "A trade tax must also be determined for part-time work and the trade tax section must be completed in the respective declaration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "146 Notes on the distinction between full-time and part-time activity A part-time activity within the meaning of Section 12 St\u00c4G is an activity that is self-contained and is not economically related to a full-time activity"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "A tax exemption of 3000 M / DM is granted annually for income from a part-time activity, such as from craft, trade and business operations as well as other independent activities, from freelance work and renting and leasing"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "A part-time job excludes the employment of workers (\u00a7 13 DB to the St\u00c4G)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In order to distinguish between full-time and part-time work, a time component must also be taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Based on the time required in each case, an activity is always full-time if the taxpayer uses more than a third of his working time for this activity"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If housewives, pensioners and students have earned taxable income, this is considered full-time income for tax purposes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Compared to the previous year 1989, a change has occurred here (in the context of the submission of the annual declarations in 1989, this group of people received benefits as for part-time workers)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "From 1990 onwards, any other activity of housewives, pensioners or students will no longer be treated as a part-time activity"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The other activities of a recipient of unemployment benefit, unemployment assistance, early retirement benefit or waiting allowance are also full-time"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This leads in 1990 to the fact that z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Pensioners, housewives or recipients of unemployment benefits for their rental and leasing income do not receive this tax-free allowance (3000 M / DM)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "However, if they only started this activity in the 1990 calendar year, they can receive a tax deduction of 10,000 M / DM for new openings in accordance with Section 9 (1) DB to the St\u00c4G"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The taxable income of this group of people is included in the annual return for full-time income (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "for traders AV 24/30)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "147 Organizational connection of cases with full-time and part-time activity In cases in which income from full-time and part-time activity come together, the taxes on the income from the part-time activity together with the taxes on the income from the full-time activity are in the annual return for to settle the full-time activity"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Cases in which a separate tax number has been assigned for the secondary occupation and in which postings have been made for this tax number, debit and credit amounts must be transferred to the personal account with the tax number for the main occupation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The tax number for the secondary occupation must then be deleted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "15 Trade tax If the tax liability begins in the course of 1990, the assessment of a tax base for the trade capital does not apply"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to corporations that emerged from formerly state-owned companies and based on the Treuhandgesetz v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "17 6 1990 from 1 7 1990 are taxable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If the trade tax liability already existed on 1 1 1990, the most recently determined unit value for the business assets is decisive for the calculation of the trade capital"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If the tax office has not yet determined a unit value for the business assets and the business was already subject to trade tax on 1 1 1990, the unit value must be determined for the business assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "When calculating the trade income, for reasons of simplification, the calculation of an annual amount (Section 10 (2) GewStG) and the pro-rata determination of trade tax (Section 22 (1) GewStG) can be dispensed with if the taxpayer agrees"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Profits from the sale of a commercial operation (partial operation) or from the sale of assets used for self-employment are not subject to trade tax (Section 13 (7) of the Taxation Guidelines v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "24 8 1979 a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "To differentiate the income from self-employed work from the income from commercial operations, see \u00a7 14 of the taxation guidelines v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "24 8 1979 a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "For commission dealers and craftsmen who are subject to taxation according to the KHStVO v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "24 12 1959 (op"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": ") or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "the HdwStG v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "16 3 1966 (A"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "), the trade tax liability begins on 1 7 1990 The same applies to production cooperatives of the craft and their working groups"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "16 Wealth tax Natural and legal persons who became taxable in 1990 are not liable for wealth tax in 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This applies because of \u00a7 135 BewG i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "of the Tax Amendment Act 1991 (a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": ") contrary to the regulation on the payment of taxes of the state-owned combines, businesses and institutions converted into corporations in the second half of 1990 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "27 6 1990 (Journal of Laws I No. 41 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "618) also for corporations that emerged from formerly state-owned companies and that are based on the Treuhandgesetz v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "17 6 1990 are considered to be converted into an AG or GmbH"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If wealth tax was paid by the former VEB with the combined tax rate for the 2nd half of 1990, this can only be offset against other taxes in the 1990 annual return (Art"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "97 a \u00a7 3 EGAO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "With regard to the wealth tax liability for commission dealers, in addition to the explanations in the annual declaration, it should be noted that according to \u00a7 3 Paragraph 2 KHStVO v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "24 12 1959 (op"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": ") the exemption of business assets is given if the commission dealer has no other taxable assets and his business assets do not include any land"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "17 Corporate income tax At the beginning of the tax liability see the explanations for the annual return"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The following deviations must be observed: Social organizations: The order simplifying the collection of taxes for the economic activity of social organizations v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "4 7 1967 GBl II No. 66 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "445 was effective v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1 7 repealed in 1990 (No. 4 of the order on the repeal of financial law provisions of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "10 9 1990 Journal of Laws I No. 62 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1560)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Accordingly, the in \u00a7 1 para 1 of the order v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "4 7 1967 named social organizations from 1 7 1990 the general tax regulations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The tax liability will i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "to the sales and profits from economic activity (\u00a7 4 K\u00f6StG, \u00a7\u00a7 52 64 AO-GDR or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "AO 1977)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Credit unions: Credit unions are not subject to general taxation until July 1, 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "For the first half of 1990 the ordinance v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "7 4 1966 GBl II No. 45 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "290 with the proviso that the profit tax is measured according to the basic tax tariff B of the St\u00c4G"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The tax liability of companies of a commercial nature of legal persons, which are themselves exempt from corporation tax, begins when the legal person starts a sustainable economic activity that is not sovereign"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The tax liability of existing businesses of a commercial nature begins at the latest on 1 7 1990. For details, see the working instructions of the Ministry of Finance of the GDR v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "22 8 1990 (BStBl I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "546/549)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "For corporations that emerged from formerly state-owned combines, companies and institutions, tax liability begins on 1 7 1990, even if the conversion into a corporation took place in the first half of 1990 (see BMF letter of 3 May 1991 BStBl 1991 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "506), the taxation according to the K\u00f6StG, GewStG and UStG does not begin until 1 7 1990 wealth tax and trade capital tax are not levied contrary to the self-calculation regulation - VEB (St\u00c4ndG 1991)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Insofar as the corporation tax liability begins in the course of 1990, the taxable income is only converted to an annual amount for corporations that are based on the Treuhandgesetz v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "17 6 in 1990 emerged from a former state-owned combine, company or facility (Section 2 (3) of the Ordinance v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "27 6 1990 Journal of Laws I No. 41 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "618)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "171 Taxation of distributions Corporate income tax rate According to the basic tax rate B of the St\u00c4G of March 6, 1990 (a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": ") to tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Distributions from corporations other than corporations are not subject to the reduced distribution rate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The reduced corporate tax rate is also out of the question for those with limited corporation tax liability"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "For distributed profits from corporations with unlimited tax liability, the corporation tax is 36 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The assessment basis for corporation tax on distributions is the portion of the income used for the distribution, i.e. 100/64 of the distribution amount before deduction of capital gains tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Example: The X-GmbH resolves to pay a dividend of 100"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Capital gains tax in accordance with Section 44 (1) EStG in the amount of 15"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The shareholder receives a cash dividend of 85%. The portion of the income used for the distribution, which corresponds to the reduced tax rate of 36%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "is calculated as follows: Cash dividend100 The income amount used for this is 100/64 = 156 corporation tax 36 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "= 56 The corporation tax on distributions from corporations with unlimited tax liability in the amount of 36 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "according to \u00a7 5 Abs 2 St\u00c4G (a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": ") is also to be levied on distributions for the year 1990 that are not made until 1991 or later (Section 54a No. 2 KStG-BRD)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Shareholders who were subject to unlimited tax liability in the accession area in 1990 and who received profit distributions in 1990 can levy the corporation tax of 225% on the profit distributions of corporations with unlimited tax liability"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "credit the distributed dividend (\u00a7 6 St\u00c4G, a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The basis of the corporate income tax credit and the crediting of the withheld capital gains tax is that according to \u00a7 11 Paragraph 3 of the DB zum St\u00c4G (a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": ") Tax certificate VE 8-0 (1990) to be issued"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "172 Production cooperatives of the craft and AGP The taxation of the production cooperatives of the craft is based for the first half of 1990 - as before - according to the PGH Tax Act v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "30 11 1962 (op"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "For taxation in the second half of 1990, the general tax regulations are decisive, in particular the corporation tax law and the trade tax law"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If the PGH is converted into a corporation or partnership in 1990, the successor company must issue the annual declaration for corporations or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "to submit the declaration for the uniform and separate determination of the income of the partnership for the period from the conversion to December 31, 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This also applies in the case of the conversion of a PGH into a registered cooperative"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Insofar as the conversion of a PGH into a registered cooperative took place in the first half of 1990, the taxation is already based on general tax law and not the PGH tax law from the time of conversion"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The assessment basis for the profit tax rate of the PGH is the annual profit per member and not only the profit of the first half of 1990 PGH can use the special depreciation according to \u00a7 12 i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Use \u00a7 7 DB for the St\u00c4G"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "It is also permissible to offset the loss of one half year with the profit of the other half year if the PGH continued to exist as PGH in 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "A remaining loss can be carried forward according to \u00a7 10d EStG-BRD"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Regarding the taxation of PGH members see the BMF letter of 6 5 1991 - IV B 7 - S-1900 - 97/91 - (Annex 3)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "PGH cannot make use of the accumulation reserve for the first half of 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "PGH can receive compensation for a decrease in net income that is due to the elimination of previous tax breaks (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "for minor and minor repairs) and taking into account the new regulations introduced by the Tax Amendment Act (Section 9 (4) DB to the St\u00c4G, a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This compensation could be granted by the tax office until December 31, 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If a PGH is entitled to compensation in individual cases, it is to be brought about via the tax rate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Claims from the first half of 1990 are devalued in a ratio of 2: 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "18 Procedural law 181 Delay surcharge The assessment basis for a delay surcharge is the tax rate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The late surcharge may be 10%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "do not exceed the tax rate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Since a late surcharge is levied uniformly in DM, the portion of the tax rate for the first half of the year must be halved"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Thereafter, the percentage is to be applied to the halved tax rate for the first half of 1990 and the tax rate for the second half of 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The total results in the late surcharge to be determined for 1990 at the most"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If a later change in the tax assessment leads to a reduction in the tax rate, the maximum rate of 10 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "for the late surcharge to limit the reduced tax rate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "A late surcharge can also be set in the event of a negative tax rate, as in certain cases this is intended to induce the taxpayer to comply with his tax obligations to submit tax returns on time in the future"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The determination of a late surcharge must in any case be within the discretion of \u00a7 152 AO and should in principle be omitted up to December 31, 1991 in the case of the first delay"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "182 Estimation of the tax bases If tax bases are estimated for the first time and the IABV has not yet been introduced at this point in time, a separate posting line with posting type 27 must also be entered in the accounting section so that an automatic accounting message is created and the account is accounted for"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The booking line with the amount \"O\" is already preprinted; the lowest EAA in this case is only to be entered in the \"EAA\" field"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "183 Sending of tax assessments if the spouse cooperates The annual return also contains the calculation of the taxes that are attributable to the profit share of the cooperating spouse"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The taxes payable on the co-operating spouse are to be included in the summarized notification to the owner"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The notification is to be addressed to both spouses (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Mr. and Mrs. Hans and Maria Meier)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Should the co-operating spouse want a separate copy of the notification or one for other reasons (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "separated spouses or in cases of valuation) are necessary, a duplicate of the tax assessment notice must be prepared and sent to the co-operating spouse"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If the assessment point deviates from the tax return of the Stpfl, the special calculation sheet for the assisting spouse (form AV 9/23) must be used for calculation sheet AV 9/22"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This form contains the specific information for the co-operating spouse and is designed as an annex to form AV 9/22"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "184 Notification of ancillary provisions in the tax assessment notice The tax assessment notice becomes effective with the content with which it is announced (Section 124 AO 1977)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In the section ancillary provisions and explanations, in addition to the explanations about deviating calculations,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "to communicate the type of tax assessment (page 1 of the calculation sheet)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In the case of changes and corrections as well as preliminary notices according to \u00a7 165 AO, the relevant regulations of the AO must be communicated to the taxpayer"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In the case of a fully or partially provisional tax assessment or provisional loss assessment, the reason for the provisional nature must be stated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In the case of an only partial provisional tax assessment, the scope of the provisional tax must be precisely defined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "It must be clear to the taxpayer for which sub-area the provisional effect applies"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "19 Compensation payments for wage policy measures According to Section 9 Paragraph 2 of the DB to the St\u00c4G (a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": ") the taxpayer can apply for compensation payments at his responsible tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The prerequisite for the grant is that he has realized his income at prices set by the state, in which the wage and salary increases agreed between the collective bargaining partners for his employees are not yet included, and the income (profits) from the company 50,000 M / DM in Do not exceed the assessment period 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "These compensation payments are calculated separately after the first and second half of 1990 after the profit determination and requested with the annual declaration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If the conditions for granting compensatory payments for wage policy measures are not met in the entire assessment year 1990, the income limit of 50,000 M / DM must be reduced pro rata temporis"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The additional expenses are only offset until the relevant income limit is reached"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If, in the assessment year 1990, income was realized both on the basis of state-set prices and on the basis of free prices, compensation payments for wage policy measures can only be applied for in accordance with the ratio of the income realized from state-set prices to the total income To be billed for the first half of 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Since the currency changeover has to be taken into account, the ratio of the income realized from state-determined prices to the total income must be determined separately by half-year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "It can be assumed here that in the second half of 1990 the taxpayers essentially realized free prices"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "There were state-set prices in the 2nd half of 1990 u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "for coal traders and hauliers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Calculation examples for compensation payments for wage policy measures Compensation payments can be calculated and applied for using the following calculation examples: a) Profit in the 1st half of 199025,000 M Profit in the 2nd half of 199030,000 DM Profit in the assessment period 55,000 M / DMNo granting of compensation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The profit is greater than 50,000 M / DM; the income limit according to \u00a7 9 para 2 of the DB to the St\u00c4G has been exceeded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "b) Profit in the first half of 199025,000 M Profit in the second half of 199020000 DM Profit in the assessment period 45,000 M / DM Wage and salary increases agreed between the collective bargaining partners that have not yet been realized in the state-set prices 8,000 M / DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The profit is less than 50,000 M / DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The compensation payment can be granted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The compensation payment for wage policy measures in the amount of 8000 M / DM must be stated separately after the first and second half of 1990 so that the currency conversion can be taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "However, only 5000 M / DM can be granted, as only a profit of 50,000 M / DM is guaranteed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "c) The company was given up on October 31, 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Profit in the first half of 199024,000 M Profit in the second half of 1990 to 31 10 19 924,000 Profit in the assessment period up to 31 10 19 048 000 M / DM The profit is less than 50,000 M / DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The compensation payment could be granted after an initial examination"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "However, the prerequisite for the granting of compensation payments existed only from 1 1 1990 to 31 10 1990 so that the income limit must be reduced proportionately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Profit in the assessment period up to 31 10 199048000 M / DM Income limit for the period for which the prerequisites apply up to 31 10 1990 (50,000: 12 = 4166 x 10 months) 41,660 M / DMd) The business existed for the entire year 1990 State-set prices were only valid until 31 10 1990 realized"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Profit in the first half of 199024,000 M Profit in the second half of 199024,000 DM Profit in the assessment period 48,000 M / DM Profit for 1 half of 199024,000 M Partial profit for the second half of 199016000 DM Partial profit for the period 40000 M / DM Income limit 50,000 x 10/12 = 41,660 M / DM Since the income limit is not exceeded, a compensation payment can be granted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "e) The company existed for the entire year 1990 State-set prices were 80% in the first half of 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": ", in the second half of 1990 to 50%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "of total revenue realized"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Profit in the 1st half of 199016000 M Profit in the 2nd half of 1990 DM 24,000 Profit in the assessment period 40000 M / DM Compensatory wage and salary increase in the 1st half of 1990 = 5000 M, compensatory wage and salary increase in the 2nd half of 1990 = 6000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "For the first half of 1990 an amount of 80 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "of 5000 M = 4000 M can be requested"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "As a compensation payment for the 2nd half of 1990 50 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "of 6000 DM = 3000 DM can be requested"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "20 Social Security Issues With the annual income tax returns, the forms issued by the transfer agency were sent for the owners and the co-operating spouses to provide evidence of the 1990 social security contributions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The tax office only had the task of sending the information on the basis of the V lists"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The completed forms are returned directly to social security"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Erroneously, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Proof of payment of the social insurance contributions submitted with the annual declaration must be forwarded to them without notification of the tax and the tax must be noted in the tax file"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Appendix VAT for the 2nd half of 1990 1 Legal basis VAT Act (GDR) - UStG - v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "22 6 1990 GBl 1990 Reprint No. 1432 Sales Tax Implementation Regulation - UStDV - v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "22 6 1990 GBl 1990 Reprint No. 1432 Administrative regulations: Treatment of subsidies for certain sales to the population, BMF letter from"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "27 12 1990 - BStBl I 1991 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "80 Deliveries and other services to the Soviet troops (1 7 1990 to 2 10 1990), BMF letter of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "25 10 1990 - BStBl 1990 I, p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "760 VAT exemption according to Art"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "16 of the treaty between the FRG and the USSR on the conditions of temporary residence and the modalities of the scheduled withdrawal of Soviet troops from the territory of the FRG, BMF letter v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "15 2 1991 - BStBl 1991 I, p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "238 Treatment of the temporary support measures for selected goods to promote adaptation to market conditions and improve competitiveness (Section 10 (1) UStG-GDR), BMF letter v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "12 2 1991 - BStBl 1991 I, p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "321 Taxation of electricity, gas, heat and water supplies in the transition to the new sales tax, BMF letter v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "18 2 1991 - BStBl 1991 I, p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "323 Sales tax treatment of the domestic German trade in goods and services from 1 7 1990 BMF letter of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "10 8 1990 - BStBl 1990 I, p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "361 Law on the Structural Adaptation of Agriculture to the Social and Ecological Market Economy in the GDR v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "25 6 1990 - Agriculture Adaptation Act - of 29 6 1990 Journal of Laws I No. 42 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "642 (in particular \u00a7 67 LAPG) application of average taxation according to \u00a7 24 UStG-DDR to LPG, z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Order of the OFD Chemnitz v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "19 4 1991 - S-7410 - 2 - St 23 - Sales tax assessment of the involvement of companies in the fulfillment of sovereign tasks, BMF letter v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "27 12 1990 - BStBl 1991 I, p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "812 Sales tax forms Sales tax return - USt 2 A - for the period from 1 July to 31 December 1990 Annex UR Annex UN 3 Tax effect of the sales tax return Sales tax returns (VAT returns) are tax returns within the meaning of Section 150 (1) sentence 2 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "They may or may not require consent (\u00a7 168 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Tax notifications that do not require approval are equivalent to tax assessment on the day they are received by the tax office, subject to review"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Tax registrations that require approval are equivalent to tax assessment subject to review once the approval is granted by the tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "A tax assessment is only to be issued if the sales tax is determined differently from the VAT declaration (tax registration) (\u00a7 167 Paragraph 1 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "1 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The VAT declaration therefore contains the following information for the entrepreneur: \"A VAT assessment is only issued if there is a deviation from your calculation of VAT"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "\"Approval is required if the\" remaining sales tax \"(line 105 of the sales tax declaration) is reduced compared to the advance payment (example 1) and for applications for an assessment with a pre-tax surplus (Section 155 (1) and (6) AO) (example 2), It does not matter whether the pre-registration procedure results in a (further) reimbursement or a final payment (example 3) compared to the input tax surpluses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Example: 123DMDMDM Remaining VAT / remaining surplus800- 200- 600Prepayment target10000-400Reimbursement claim / Final payment- 200-200-200If the tax office does not deviate from the VAT declaration, the taxpayer receives a settlement notification"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If the billing is still carried out via project 713, the VAT declaration must be accounted for with 027 so that an account statement can be printed out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "4 Determination of sales tax by the sub-district The sales tax is to be processed together with the respective lead assessment (income tax or profit determination)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "This principle of the overall processing of the tax case is to be refrained from a) in cases of the shortened taxation period (\u00a7\u00a7 16 Paragraph 3 18 Paragraph 3 Sentence 2 UStG) and b) in the case of VAT declarations that require approval, if reimbursement claims are declared"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "A review of the VAT declaration is necessary if there are significant differences between the VAT"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "VAT declaration and sales tax according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Pre-registrations result"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "A rough comparison can be derived from the totals column of the attached VAT monitoring sheet USt 1 OE; possibly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "specifically ask the taxpayer (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "significant increase in taxable sales according to the VAT declaration; Increase in the proportion of reduced sales with roughly the same total sales; Increase in input tax amounts)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If the VAT return is roughly checked, the input tax deduction and sales should also be checked"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The highest possible input tax can be determined using the information in the loss and profit accounting or in the income statement (for the second half of 1990)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "a) Additions to assets and material expenses with input tax b) Private deposits and material expenses without input tax (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Personnel costs, depreciation, postage, telephone, company taxes, fees and insurance) When checking sales, the respective type of taxation must be used"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In the case of target taxation (taxation according to agreed remuneration), the following must be stated:"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "V + G (including auxiliary sales)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Sales deductions (discounts, bonuses)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "half-finished work + down payments within the framework of the minimum actual taxation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Income that is not subject to VAT (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Compensation for damages, foreign sales; cf. line 205 Annex UR) In the case of actual taxation (taxation according to received remuneration) (remuneration received after 30 6 1990 for sales made before 1 7 1990 are not to be taken into account): Income according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "V + G (including auxiliary sales)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Claims (net) up to December 31, 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Sales deductions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "income not subject to VAT"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In addition, the information provided by an entrepreneur on self-consumption should be checked and, if necessary,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "can be added"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "For the assessment basis, reference is made to Section 155 UStR and the information in the explanation of the VAT declaration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "For the second half of 1990, the self-consumption lump sums worked out by the reference rate group South can be valued at 70% or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "50% will be taken into account for the following business areas: bakery, catering and catering, confectionery, butcher's shop, retail - milk, dairy products, fat and eggs - food and luxury items of various kinds - fruit and vegetables, tropical fruits and potatoes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "In the case of personal consumption (Section 9 (2) UStR), the deduction for use for non-business purposes is not part of the assessment basis if the object was placed in the company by the entrepreneur himself from his non-entrepreneurial area or the object was brought into the company by a non-entrepreneur, from the non-entrepreneurial area The area of \u200b\u200banother entrepreneur, based on a tax-free delivery according to \u00a7 4 No. 7 to 28 UStG or from a small entrepreneur falling under the regulation of \u00a7 19 Paragraph 1 UStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The other costs i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "of Section 10 (4) No. 2 UStG are also part of the assessment basis if they are not entitled to input tax deduction (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "for motor vehicles, insurance premiums, motor vehicle tax and garage rental)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "If a telephone connection has been assigned to the company, private use is subject to sales tax including telephone charges (which are only taxable at Telekom from 1 1 1996)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "The provision of \u00a7 15a UStG only applies in the taxation period 1990 if an asset purchased or manufactured in the second half of 1990 was sold or taken for personal consumption during the same period and this turnover is to be treated differently for input tax deduction than when it was first used ( Section 215 (1) UStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0105285.xml"}, "text": "Other tax law Federal Republic kw 49-91"}]