[{"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion KoblenzS-2230 A - St 34 2S-2230EStG: 13EStG: 13aEStG: 7a / 8EStG: 34bEStG: 34eAO: 140AO: 141 / 1AO: 141 / 2Income taxation of farmers and foresters for the calendar year 19921 Bookkeeping farmers and foresters 12 .11 Lump-sum accounting for self-consumption and catering14 Evaluation of plant stocks in tree nurseries15 Value in use of the apartment2 Determination of profit by comparing the operating income with the operating expenses21 General22 Average livestock values23 Value in use of the apartment24 Maintenance of the special directory according to Section 7a (8) EStG3 Estimated farmers31 General32 Maintenance of the special directory according to Section 7a (8) EStG33 Estimation of profit according to reference rates331 initial estimate332 rental income333 surcharges for profits or profits not settled with the initial estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits334 Value in use of the apartment335 Wage expenses336 Lease expenses, debt interest, permanent charges337 Other surcharges and reductions34 Sales standard rates35 Tax reduction according to \u00a7 34e Income Tax Act36 Form4 Profit calculation according to average rates (\u00a7 13a Income Tax Act) 41 General42 Profit calculation421 Preceding land 422 Profits from forestry activities52, 423 Profits from forestry activities5 Sale of forest land53 Profit from wood use by valued farmers54 Tariff reduction according to \u00a7 34b EStG6 Non-objection limits for cashless retirement benefits7 Other71 Determination of capital gains - Land gain taxation72 Control reports73 Advance payments for winter rape74 Income tax treatment of the compensation according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "of the Non-Marketing Compensation Ordinance1 Book-keeping farmers and foresters 11 Obligation to keep records The obligation to keep records is made by farmers and foresters who manage an agricultural and forestry business as owners, tenants, usufructuary or other beneficial owners, as well as lessors who lease a business as a whole but have not given up if the requirements of Section 140 AO are met or one of the accounting limits set out in Section 141 Paragraph 1 AO is exceeded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "When making the assessment, care must be taken to ensure that businesses that are required to keep accounts in accordance with Section 141 (1) AO are informed in good time of the start of the accounting obligation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If the accounting obligation is no longer required, Section 141 (2) AO does not provide for a formal notification, but in these cases a corresponding note in the tax assessment or a special notification is considered appropriate for reasons of legal certainty"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "For the rest, reference is made to the following instructions regarding the accounting obligation in agricultural and forestry operations: Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "from 18 12 1980 - S-2230 / S-0311 A - St 34 2 / St 42 1 - Tz"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "1 -; FM decree of 27 3 1981 - S-2230 A - 442 - No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "5 (corresponds to BMF letter of 27 3 1981 BStBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "282; ESt-Kartei: Card 7 to \u00a7 13 EStG); FM-Decree of 15 12 1981 - S-2163 A - 442 - No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "1 and 2 (corresponds to BMF letter of 15 12 1981 BStBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "878; ESt-Kartei: Map 15 to \u00a7 13 EStG); Section 127 EStR 199012 Livestock assessment For the assessment of livestock - with the exception of horses - those with Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "vom 26 5 1967 - S-2132a A - St 32 2 - (BStBl II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "239) established average values"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "For horses acquired by the taxpayer or born in the taxpayer's business after the beginning of the 1980/81 financial year, the horses listed in the Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "vom 24 3 1981 - S-2132a A - St 34 2 - ESt-Kartei: Map 6 to \u00a7 13 EStG - contained values \u200b\u200bare decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Incidentally, also Section 125 EStR 199013 Flat-rate amounts for personal consumption and meals Generally applicable flat-rate amounts that can be used on a large scale in practice can no longer be determined with regard to the specialization of the companies in certain branches of production"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "14 Assessment of plant stocks in tree nurseries For the assessment of plant stocks in tree nurseries, the FM decree of 9 1 1991 - S-2163 A - 442 - (corresponds to BMF letter of 9 1 1991 BStBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "133; ESt-Kartei: card 2 to \u00a7 13 EStG) approved simplification regulations essential"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "15 Value in use of the apartment The income from agriculture and forestry includes until the last application of Section 13 (2) No. 2 EStG (reference to Section 52 (15) EStG and FM decree of 12 11 1986 - S-2236 A - 442 - corresponds BMF letter dated 12 11 1986 BStBl IS"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "528; Income tax card: card 3 to \u00a7 52 EStG) also the (gross) value in use of the taxpayer's apartment if the apartment does not exceed the size customary for businesses of the same type"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The profit of the financial year in which the value-in-use taxation ceases to apply, including the value in use still to be assessed for part of the financial year, is to be divided proportionally in accordance with Section 4a (2) No. 1 of the Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If the value-in-use taxation is retrospectively deselected, the application also regularly affects the amount of the previous year's income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If the assessment of the previous year has already been finalized, it must be changed in accordance with Section 175 (1) No. 2 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The rental value is to be regularly estimated in analogous application of Section 8 (2) EStG, whereby the local average rent for apartments of a comparable type, location and equipment (market rent) is decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If the rental value is determined according to the rent index drawn up by the tax office,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "still to take into account the rural conditions accordingly, as far as these have not yet been given special consideration in the rent index"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In addition, agricultural holdings in the narrower sense (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "regularly not for special uses) by the BFH jurisprudence (judgments of 30 1 1974 BStBl II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "608 of 30 1 1974 BStBl 1975 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "3 and from 28 3 1974 BStBl 1975 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "9) to undertake approved deductions from the rental value, provided these have not yet been reflected in the rent index"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Deductions are regularly considered because of the general value-reducing factors resulting from membership in agriculture (20 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": ") and because of the special circumstances impairing the value of the individual case (up to 30 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The general discount of 20%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "of the rental value customary in the location is not to be made in the case of businesses with special uses, viticulture or horticulture businesses in a normal location (cf. section II No. 17 of the minutes of the income tax group meeting 1987 of 8 9 1987 - S-2319 A - St 31 1 -)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In addition, reference is made to Section 130 a Paragraph 7 EStR 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "2 Determination of profits by comparing the operating income with the operating expenses21 General Because of the scope of the determination of profits according to \u00a7 4 Paragraph 3 EStG, I refer to Section 127 Paragraph 3 Income Tax Act 1990 (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Section 17 Income Tax Act 1990)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "22 Average livestock values \u200b\u200bThe average valuation permitted for book-keeping farmers and foresters (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "12) can, according to Section 125 a of the Income Tax Act 1990, under certain conditions, be used in the determination of profits in accordance with Section 4 Paragraph 3 of the Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "23 Value in use of the apartment In the cases of Section 4 (3) EStG, the value in use of the apartment is to be determined in accordance with the principles applicable to accounting operations (see"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "24 Maintaining the special register in accordance with Section 7a (8) of the EStGB When determining profits in accordance with Section 4 (3) of the EStG, special depreciation in accordance with Section 76 of the EStDV is permitted for the first time for the depreciable assets acquired or manufactured after June 26, 1982 up to the end of the 1991/92 financial year; their use requires records in accordance with Section 7a (8) of the Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "These records in the special directory named in Section 7a (8) of the Income Tax Act must be made at the latest by the submission of the tax return for the financial year in which the beneficial asset was acquired or manufactured"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "It is not sufficient if the directory is only available at the time of a later application after submitting the tax return, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "a later tax audit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "3 Appraisal farmers31 General For farmers and foresters who are obliged to keep accounts but do not keep proper books, the profit is to be estimated in individual cases according to \u00a7 162 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to those farmers and foresters who are not obliged to keep accounts nor meet the requirements of Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 2 and 3 EStG if they do not have any books in the sense of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 4 Abs 1 EStG and also the operating income and expenses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "of Section 4 Paragraph 3 EStG (Section 127 Paragraph 2 - 4 EStR 1990)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The estimate has - with the exception of the in Section 127 Paragraph 4 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "7 second half-sentence of the EStR 1990 - to be carried out in accordance with the principles of Section 4 (1) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "When making the estimate, all circumstances must be taken into account that are important for the estimate in individual cases (Section 162 (1) sentence 2 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The aim of the estimate must be to determine the profit actually achieved"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Of several possible estimation methods (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Asset growth calculation, total monetary transaction calculation or estimate based on the results of similar accounting operations) is therefore the one that comes closest to the result that would have been shown in proper accounting"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In doing so, preference should always be given to the method that best takes into account the particular operational conditions of the individual case"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The uncertainties inherent in an estimate are, however, at the expense of the taxpayer, who himself gave cause for the estimate by neglecting his tax cooperation obligations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "It is important to ensure that farmers who are required to keep accounts and whose profit is estimated are to be reported to the tax auditor if an audit appears suitable or promises success for other reasons"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "This applies in particular to all agricultural businesses that have fulfilled their accounting obligations for some time, then no longer keep books and allow themselves to be valued"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If a tax audit is planned in these cases, the assessment must be carried out subject to the review (Section 164 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "32 Maintaining the special register in accordance with Section 7a (8) of the Income Tax Act (EStG) Insofar as agricultural holdings that are required to keep accounts and do not keep books use special depreciation in accordance with Article 76 of the Income Tax Act (EStDV), the time at which the special register in accordance with Article 7a (8) of the Income Tax Act (EStG) no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "24 to be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "33 Estimation of the profit according to standard rates It is basically left to the discretion of the tax office which estimation method to use in the individual case"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "As a rule, however, the profit will have to be estimated based on the results of similar accounting operations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The basis for this is a modified guideline rate estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If, in individual cases, an estimate tailored to the particular operational conditions is not to be preferred or other empirical rates are not available, the profit can be estimated as follows: Initial estimate (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "331) + lease income (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "332) + surcharges for profits or profits not settled with the initial estimate amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "333) + value in use of the apartment (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "334) -wage expenses (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "335) -Lease expenses, debt interest, permanent burdens (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "336) +"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Other surcharges and reductions (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "337) = profit of the financial year The estimate of profit according to this procedure must not lead to an obviously incorrect taxation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Are there any doubts as to whether the type of operation, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In the case of processing operations or operations with sugar beet cultivation, an accurate profit estimate in this form is even possible, I ask you to call in the agricultural audit or the responsible official agricultural expert (ALS)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "331 Initial estimate When determining the initial estimate, a distinction is made - as before - according to the following areas: Area I: Rheinpfalz and Rheinhessen (both the Rhine level), Koblenz-Neuwied Basin, Maifeld and Grafschaft Area II: all other areas The initial estimate per hectare of agricultural land for the 1992/93 marketing year: estimated starting amounts per hectare / LN area forage cultivation area in percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "the LN to 30 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "30-60 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "about 60 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "DMDMDMIa) 15009001000b) 1800c) 900c) 1600d) 1300d) 1900II1200800900c) 900c) 1600d) 1300d) 1900 Surcharge for growing early potatoes 1500 DM / ha"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Turnover guide values \u200b\u200bper hectare / LN area forage cultivation area in f"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "the LN to 30 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "30-60 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "about 60 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "DMDMDMIa) 420042004000b) 6000c) 4300c) 4800d) 4800d) 5100II340034004700c) 3700c) 5200d) 4100d) 5500 Surcharge for growing new potatoes 1500 DM / ha"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Notes: a) with predominantly cereal cultivation) with predominantly root crop cultivation c) with dairy farming below 40%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "of the cattle herd d) in the case of dairy farming over 40%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "of the cattle herd based on the average herd of cattle in cattle units according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Lines 80 - 86 of Annex L to the income tax declaration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "For farms with poor soil conditions and / or in climatically unfavorable locations, a discount of up to 20% from the initial estimate can be made upon request"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "be made"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The relevant ALS must check the requirements for such a discount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The agricultural area relevant for the estimate only includes the pure agricultural production areas including leases and set-aside areas, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Areas of the social or rotation sector"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Areas for buildings, courtyards, house gardens, paths, ditches, field edges, forestry, tobacco-growing, horticultural, fruit-growing or viticultural areas, as well as areas used for mining, low-lying, unpaved land and similar areas are not taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "A quarter of hats and half of fruit-growing areas with regular agricultural underuse are to be considered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If vegetables are grown as catch crops or catch crops, the corresponding areas are not to be excluded from the calculation of the relevant agricultural area because there is double use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "For the extent of the forage cultivation area, I refer to No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "3334332 Lease income Lease income also for the provision of reference quantities, ground rent and hunting leases, reduced by proportionate operating expenses, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Property taxes must be added to the initial estimate if they are included in income from agriculture and forestry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "This is the case when the leased or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Hereditary assets belong to the lessor's agricultural and forestry business assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "333 Surcharges for profits or profits not settled with the initial estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "All profits from sustainable or one-off operating income that are not included in the initial estimate are to be added to the initial estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Such surcharges come z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Consideration for profits from the extraction and sale of land, profits from viticulture, profits from fruit and vegetable cultivation, profits from closure and severance distilleries, profits from tobacco production, profits from other special branches, profits from ancillary businesses, profits from abnormal animal husbandry, additional profits from sales of breeding cattle , Profits from the rental of buildings and parts of buildings that belong to the business assets, profits from the sale of milk quotas and sugar beet quotas and from a milk quota leasing"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "I would also like to point out the following: 3331 Removal and sale of land"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "on this point"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "713332 Viticulture, fruit and vegetable growing as well as distilleries For the determination of the corresponding profits, I refer to the information given in No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "423 circulars mentioned"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "3333 Tobacco growing According to the determinations made, the harvest yields in the Palatinate growing area have developed as follows (1 dt = 100 kg): Wj"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Cultivation area haErtrag German"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Monetary value DM net harvest dt / ha avg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "-Price DM / dt net income DM / ha net total cultivation1990 / 911 208 2406217 158 118 199 171 314 201 1991/1991 / 921 129 247 1819 206 165 219 77717010 repayment of premium withheld from harvest 1988 in fy"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "1991/924906951992 / 9310152612920488987257478420183Geudertheimer (cigar goods) 1990/917061388592985091967670131721991/926821499810479719219869915360"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "1991/92: 490695307741992 / 936301694611821358269169818773Burley (cut material) 1990/91439945572993792156772166451991/9238187937942815230790320836"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "1991/92: 00001992 / 9332680217575524245994423221Virgin1990 / 9164721560230113277687881991 / 9266927783631141284511937Repayment of premium withholding from harvest 1988"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "1991/92: 0001992/935911621092105196294018438 The tobacco vintage 1992 was of above-average quality and quantity"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Weather-related losses only occurred occasionally and slightly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Minor hail damage occurred at a late stage in the communities of Geinsheim, Hanhofen and Ha\u00dfloch"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In addition, minor drought damage was recorded in the community of Scheibenhardt"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The income from hail insurance compensation is not included in the table"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In the 1992/93 financial year - as in previous years - 9200 DM per hectare of cultivated area can be taken into account to compensate for the actual construction costs"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "3334 Abnormal animal husbandry Profits from animal breeding and animal husbandry are settled with the estimated starting amount, provided the average normal animal population is not exceeded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The normal number of livestock in livestock units (VE) for other farms for the first 20 ha LN22 VE / ha14 VE / ha for the next 10 ha LN16 VE / ha08 VE / ha for the next 20 ha LN15 VE / ha07 VE / hamit more than 50 ha LN A maximum of 90 VE50 VEF forage growing operations are businesses where the forage area is 60%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "and more of the LN"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The forage area includes: Meadows, arable meadows, tree meadows, litter meadows, pastures, cultivation areas for grass clover, alfalfa, seradella, saspars, green corn, vetches, sweet lupins, silage corn, fodder beet, clover in pure seed and mixed cultivation and all other forage crops"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "When calculating the number of animals and converting them into VE, the procedure is in accordance with Section 124 a EStR 1990"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "For the remaining after deduction of the normal inventory excess inventory is for the Wirtschaftsjahr1992 / be recognized as profit 93: BeiDM / VERindviehhaltung1250Stallmast of K\u00e4lbern690Stallmast of calves (payroll process) 195Mastschweineverkauf280L\u00e4uferverkauf500Ferkelverkauf650Legehennen eggs sale Gro\u00dfhandel0Legehennen eggs sale Einzelhandel1080Aufzucht of Junghennen830Junggefl\u00fcgelmast280Entenmast750Putenmast1950G\u00e4nsemast2550Darauf attributable wages are not taken into account and therefore can be up or set down"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "When determining the abnormal animal husbandry and calculating the corresponding surcharge to the initial estimate, please contact the responsible ALS"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "3335 Breeding cattle sales Regarding the determination of the additional profits from breeding cattle sales, No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "424 accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "3336 payments for the abandonment of milk production or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The income tax treatment of the milk delivery remuneration and the remuneration for the temporary use of delivery reference quantities was last amended by FM decree of 15 4 1991 - S-2132 A - 442 - (corresponds to BMF letter of 15 4 1991 BStBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "497; ESt-Kartei: card 18 e to \u00a7 13 EStG) and FM-decree of 21 8 1991 - S-2132 A - 442 - (Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "from 15 4 1992 - S-2230 A - St 34 2 - No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "45) regulated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Corresponding fees are to be determined in individual cases on the basis of the relevant documents and added to the initial estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "334 Value in use of the apartment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "15 to determine the principles contained"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Because the estimated starting amounts do not include the expenses for the owner-occupied apartment, 65 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "of the value in use as business expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The debt interest payable on the apartment (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "336) and the increased deductions (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "3372) can also be applied"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "335 Wage expenses In the case of the initial estimate (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "331) it is assumed that the company is managed exclusively with unpaid workers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Wage expenses are therefore to be deducted from the initial estimate insofar as they relate to the profit settled with the initial estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If profits are recorded as a surcharge through individual calculation, care must be taken to ensure that any proportionate wage expenditure is not recorded twice (cf. in particular no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "3332 and 3333)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "For the distribution of wage expenses required in individual cases, see Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "from 15 4 1992 - S-2230 A - St 34 2 - No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "46336 Lease expenses, debt interest, permanent charges These expenses can be deducted insofar as they represent operating expenses and have not already been taken into account in a surcharge calculation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Deductible expenses also include ongoing lease payments for the provision of reference quantities and payments for the temporary use of delivery reference quantities (quota leasing) in accordance with Section 7a of the Nineteenth Ordinance on the Amendment of the Milk Guarantee Quantity Offsetting of 28 3 1991 BGBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "799 (for income tax treatment, see no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "3336); however, not payments aimed at the purchase of reference quantities"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If the lessee does not (or no longer) tax a value in use for a jointly leased apartment, the part of the total rent that is attributable to the apartment cannot be deducted as business expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "337 Other surcharges and reductions 3371 Other surcharges The estimated starting amount for the profit from agricultural use does not include any income that is generated in the context of agriculture, but which is not regularly generated on farms (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Expert fees, breeding premiums, profits from the sale of fixed assets, profits from participation in cooperatives, stud fee income, feed money income, wages and remuneration for other services)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Insofar as such facts are determined in individual cases - especially in the context of company audits -"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "to make a profit surcharge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Any compensation or subsidies from public funding programs are not included in the initial estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "3372 Increased reductions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "increased deductions for residential buildings according to \u00a7 7b EStG and increased deductions according to \u00a7\u00a7 82a, 82g and 82i EStDV"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "As far as increased deductions are used, the profit must be increased again by the depreciation already taken into account in the initial estimate according to Section 7 (4) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "3373 Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Acquisition or production of the beneficiary assets by the end of the 1991/92 financial year) of the corresponding requirements"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "After the expiry of the tax credit period of three financial years, however (at the end of the tax assessment period 1994, the tax benefit expires - \u00a7 52 Paragraph 1 No. 2 Letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "k EStG) to increase the initial estimate by a surcharge, since according to Section 7a (9) EStG, the residual value is the assessment basis for further deductions for wear and tear and otherwise excessive depreciation amounts would otherwise be taken into account by applying the initial estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The surcharge for a financial year results from the total of the special depreciation granted divided by the remaining useful life of the respective asset"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The increase in the initial estimate is to be carried out for the remaining period of use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "When using the preferential treatment for immovable assets with a useful life of more than 30 years as well as for conversions and extensions to these assets, a correction is not necessary in view of Section 76 (4) sentence 3 EStDV for reasons of simplification"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In order to ensure that the surcharges are also taken into account in future assessments, the control sheet placed under form number \"ESt 7\" must be kept and attached to the income tax files"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "34 Standard sales rates The standard sales rates applicable for the 1992/93 financial year are set out in paragraph"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "331 printed overview of the estimated starting amounts for the respective types of business"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "35 Tax reduction according to \u00a7 34e EStG \u00a7 34e EStG, as amended by the Tax Amendment Act 1992, provides that the tax reduction does not apply for the first time for the assessment period 1992 even if the profit of the financial year beginning in the assessment period (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "due to failure to submit the tax return or balance sheet, only incomplete proof of operating income) was estimated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "There is no estimate of profit within the meaning of this provision if parts of the operating expenses are permissiblely taken into account on the basis of the guide amounts (see Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "from 10 9 1993 - S-2233 A - St 34 2 - No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "8th; ESt-Kartei: card 8 to \u00a7 13 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to the permissible application of the flat rate operating expenses according to \u00a7 51 EStDV for certain forestry operations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The estimate of the profit (according to no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "33) on the basis of initial estimates, includes all of the business's usual operating income and expenses; The benefit of Section 34e EStG is therefore ruled out in this determination of profits - as in the case of a full estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Contrary to Section 213 (5) EStR 1990, the lessor of an agricultural and forestry business is not entitled to the tax reduction under Section 34e EStG (BFH judgment of 15 4 1993 BFH / NV 1994 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "87), because he does not have the option of determining profits according to \u00a7 13a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The income guidelines will be adjusted accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "36 form"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "33 is available to the tax offices using the \"ESt 6\" form"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "4 Determination of profits according to average rates (\u00a7 13a EStG) 41 General To determine the profit from agriculture and forestry according to the average rates of \u00a7 13a paragraph 3 to 8 EStG, I refer to the following regulations: Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "from 18 12 1980 - S-2230 / S-0311 A - St 34 2 / St 42 1 Item"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "2; FM decree of 27 3 1981 - S-2230 A - 442 - No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "2 (corresponds to BMF letter of 27 3 1981 BStBl p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "282; ESt-Kartei: Card 7 to \u00a7 13 EStG, No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "2); Sections 127 and 130 a of the 1990 Income Tax Regulations When making the assessment, particular attention must be paid to the fact that the taxpayers in question are informed in good time if the prerequisites for determining profits according to average rates cease to exist (Section 13a, Paragraph 1, Sentence 2 of the Income Tax Act)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The use of z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "the estimated starting amounts according to no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "331 or the indicative amounts in viticulture (see no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "422 and Appendix 1 of the Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "from 10 9 1993 - S-2233 A - St 34 2 -; ESt-Kartei: card 8 to \u00a7 13 EStG) in the first financial year after the transition is contrary to an effective application according to \u00a7 13a paragraph 2 sentence 1 EStG (BFH judgment of 18 3 1993 BStBl II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "549)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "This right to choose presupposes that either proper bookkeeping or actual records of operating income and operating expenses are based on the profit determination presented for at least the 1 financial year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "This is not the case if z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Parts of the operating expenses are estimated or applied with reference rates"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "42 Determination of profit The scheme for determining profit according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 to 8 EStG results from the form \"Annex ESt 2L / 3L (91) - Profit determination according to \u00a7 13a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "\"The taxpayer can choose whether the profit to be assessed in accordance with Section 13a (8) of the Income Tax Act is determined according to the principles of Section 4 (1) or Section 4 (3) of the Income Tax Act (Section 130a (8) sentence 9 of the 1990 Income Tax Act)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Any loss resulting from Section 13a (8) of the Income Tax Act (EStG) must be offset against the average rate profit in accordance with Section 13a (3) to (7) of the Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The exemption of max"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "3000 DM is only to be taken into account if the sum of the profits according to \u00a7 13a Abs 8 EStG is positive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The granting of the exemption cannot lead to a loss or change a loss"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In the case of exclusive profits within the meaning of Section 13a Paragraph 8 EStG, even if the profit is actually determined in accordance with Section 4 Paragraph 3 or Section 4 Paragraph 1 EStG, the tax reduction in accordance with Section 34e EStG does not apply (BFH judgment of 28 November 1991 BStBl 1992 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "458)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "421 Areas to be taken into account The self-cultivated, own, leased and set-aside areas due to public funding programs must be taken into account (Section 124 a Paragraph 3 S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "3 EStR 1990)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "422 Value of the work performance a) For those according to the law for the promotion of the cessation of agricultural employment (FELEG) of 21 2 1989 (BGBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "233) set aside areas, the basic amount according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 4 EStG is to be set (see minutes of 17 7 1990 about ESt group meeting 1990 - S-2319 A - St 31 1 - Section II, No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Since, with the exception of a few maintenance measures, the cultivation of the set-aside areas is suspended, the value for the physical work performance of the business owner and his relatives in accordance with Section 13a (5) No. 1 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "On the other hand, the surcharge for the management of the company according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 5 No. 1 lit."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "b EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "b) Deviating from section 130 a paragraph 3 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "7 and 8 EStR, the value for the physical work of a business owner who is employed all day outside of his agricultural part-time business is to be set at 02 VAK for an initial value of up to 15,000 DM and 03 VAK for an initial value of up to 15,000 DM - 32,000 DM (FM - Decree of 8 7 1991 - S-2149 A - 442 - (corresponds to BMF letter of 8 7 1991 BStBl IS"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "736; ESt-Kartei: card 3 to \u00a7 13a EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "c) The paid workers are to be counted towards the reasonable time of the full-time workers (VAK) according to the duration of their employment (\u00a7 13a Abs 5 Nr 5 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "To determine the physical work of the business owner as well as the unpaid relatives on the one hand and the paid workers on the other hand, if the initial value does not include the value of the special uses within the meaning of Section 13a Paragraph 4 No. 1 Sentence 2 EStG, I refer to the Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "from 15 4 1992 - S-2230 A - St 34 2 - No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "46; ESt-Kartei: Card 10 c to \u00a7 13 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "423 Profits from special uses Pursuant to Section 13a (8) No. 1 EStG, profits from special uses must also be included in the average rate under the conditions specified there"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "For the determination of the profit from viticulture, I refer to the Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "vom 10 9 1993 - S-2233 A - St 34 2 - ESt-Kartei: Map 8 to \u00a7 13 EStG - and because of the determination of the profit from fruit and vegetable growing the Rdvfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "vom 15 12 1993 - S-2233 A - St 34 2 - ESt-Kartei: card 9 to \u00a7 13 EStG - to be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "As far as profits from closure and severance distilleries are to be determined, I ask that the responsible agricultural Bp office be involved"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "This will inform the taxable district of the necessary reference rates and key figures"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "424 Profits from other business operations Profits from sales of breeding cattle that exceed a normal profit are to be recorded within the framework of Section 13a (8) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "A surcharge from the sale of breeding cattle is 70%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "of the sales (auction) proceeds exceeding the initial value"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The additional profit has to be calculated individually for each animal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "A netting with sales proceeds that are below the initial values \u200b\u200bmay not be carried out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The decisive starting values \u200b\u200bfor the 1992/93 financial year are: for breeding horses 9000 DM for riding horses 7000 DM for breeding bulls 5300 DM for breeding cows 2300 DM for breeding cattle 2200 DM for breeding over 1,100 DM for breeding sows 1000 DM for breeding rams1300 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The following operating processes, which were not taken into account when determining the initial value, should be included in accordance with Section 13a (8) No. 3 EStG: Profits from the rental of rooms to holiday guests, insofar as income from agriculture and forestry is involved (reference to Sect 103 para 7 BewRL), interest income, insofar as the capital claim is attributable to the business assets, profits from participation that belong to the agricultural and forestry business assets, profits from the rental of buildings and parts of buildings belonging to the agricultural business assets, profits from the sale of sugar beet quotas, profits from the Sale of milk quotas, unless the FM decree of 15 4 1991 - S-2132 A - 442 - (corresponds to BMF letter of 15 4 1991 BStBl IS"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "497; ESt-Kartei: card 18 e to \u00a7 13 EStG) is to be used (see also no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "75), compensation for economic difficulties, see FM decrees of 5 3 1992 9 2 1993 and 1 7 1993 - S-2149 A - 442 - (corresponds to BMF letter of 5 3 1992 9 2 1993 and 1 7 1993 BStBl 1992 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "187 and BStBl 1993 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "241; ESt-Kartei: card 13 b to \u00a7 13 EStG), profits from an inter-company use of machines, which are achieved in the context of agriculture and forestry, are to be partially recorded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In this respect, reference is made to the ESt card index: Card 2 to Section 13a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "5 Forestry 51 Acquisition of forest land In Section 212 Paragraph 1 Sentences 7 u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "8 EStR 1990, for reasons of simplification, it is permitted that capitalized acquisition or production costs for standing wood are reduced annually by 3%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "can be reduced"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "When acquiring forest land and when acquiring businesses and sub-businesses, the purchase price must therefore be properly divided between the land and the stocking (standing wood)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Whether this has happened in individual cases is checked by the forestry expert from the regional tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "I therefore ask you to report to the regional finance directorate in the relevant cases before carrying out the assessment, enclosing the files"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In the case of the sale of forest land as well as the sale of businesses and sub-businesses, appropriate taxation is only guaranteed if the proceeds from the sale relate to the land (loss clause according to Section 55 (6) of the Income Tax Act) and to the forest as well as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "on other assets (buildings, inventory, paths, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": ") is divided"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The distribution of the sales proceeds and, if applicable,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In such cases, the corresponding book value is determined by the forestry expert from the regional finance directorate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "I therefore ask that in each individual case, immediately after a sale becomes known (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "by means of a notification of sale from the real estate acquisition tax office) and before carrying out the corresponding assessment, enclosing the tax files and the standard value files of the regional finance office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In the case of the sale of a business or a part of the business, this only applies if the proceeds from the sale exceed the applicable exemptions (\u00a7 14 in conjunction with"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "V with \u00a7 16 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If the taxpayer applies for such an exemption due to the sale of a business or part of a business, this must be pointed out in the submission report to the regional tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In principle, this also applies if the proceeds from the sale (incl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "of the standing wood) for the forest parcel does not exceed the book value of the land"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In the case of such a sale of well-stocked land for which the starting amount of DM 2 / sqm (\u00a7 55 Paragraph 1 in conjunction with"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Paragraph 2 no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "2 EStG) applies, nevertheless there is usually a loss - which is not deductible according to Section 55 (6) EStG - from the sale of the land (the value of the land with forestry use in Rhineland-Palatinate only exceptionally exceeds DM 050 / sqm) and with regard to the standing wood a - taxable - profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "53 Profit from the use of wood by valued farmers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If the actual operating expenses cannot be determined in such cases, there are no concerns about the operating expenses being reduced to 45 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "estimate the income from the use of wood"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "This flat rate covers all operating expenses for the financial year in which the wood was used (incl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "the reforestation costs)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Applications for the application of the reduced tax rates according to \u00a7 34b for extraordinary income from forestry due to a tariff reduction according to \u00a7 34b of the Income Tax Act for extraordinary wood use and wood use as a result of force majeure (calamity use) must be forwarded immediately to the regional tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The various uses achieved in a financial year must be verified in terms of quantity according to Section 34b (4) No. 2 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "After a review by the forestry expert, the tax offices receive a notification of the amount of tax-privileged wood use based on a preliminary calculation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "a) This preliminary calculation of the tax-privileged income according to \u00a7 34b EStG by the forestry expert is based on unaudited information from the taxpayer and the like"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "via the corresponding operating income (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Raw wood revenues) and expenditures (possibly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "reduced by grants)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If this differs from the above"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Notification of the information provided by the taxpayer from the amounts declared to the tax office in the context of the relevant income tax return, the discrepancy must be clarified by asking the taxpayer"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If it is found that the fundamentals (operating income and expenses) of the calculation periods of the preliminary calculation have changed, the forestry expert must be called in again, submitting the original and changed application documents"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "b) The calculation and reporting of the extraordinary wood uses in accordance with Section 34b (1) EStG by the forestry expert is subject to recognition by the tax office responsible for the determination"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Extraordinary uses of wood are uses that occur outside of the stipulated usage rate if they have taken place for economic reasons (Section 34b (1) No. 1 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "On the question of economic reasons, see"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Section 204 Income Tax"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If the uses shown in the preliminary calculation of tax-privileged income of the forestry expert as extraordinary wood uses are not as extraordinary wood uses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 34b EStG, they are to be assigned to normal use (overuse - overuse)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "An application of the reduced tax rates of \u00a7 34b EStG is not possible for these uses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "c) From the assessment period 1990 onwards, the reduced tax rates of \u00a7 34b EStG are no longer dependent on an application from the taxpayer"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "6 Non-objection limits for non-cash partial retirement benefits Non-cash partial retirement benefits are deductible at their actual value, which must be proven in detail"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "If an individual record is not provided, the value of non-cash partial retirement benefits is to be estimated in accordance with Section 1, Paragraph 1 of SachBez V in the version applicable for the respective assessment period (Section 87, Paragraph 4, p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "7 EStR)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "For the age-sharing spouse, only 80%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "to take this value into account (Section 1 (4) SachBezV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The following lists the non-objection limits, which are determined in accordance with Section 1 (1) SachBezV in the version applicable for the respective assessment period: 19921993 (BStBl 92 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "50) (BStBl 93 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "26) MealsHeating and lightingMealsHeating and lightingDMDMDMDMEIndividual36948213823850Old sharing couple6649147868821529The non-objection limits are not applicable if, on the basis of the company's profit determination documents, it is obvious that the costs attributable to the retirement sharing are lower"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "7 Miscellaneous71 Determination of capital gains - taxation of land gains I would like to draw your attention once again to the correct and timely recording of sales and land gains"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In particular, I ask that the control material available, such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Notices of sale of the real estate transfer tax offices to be evaluated promptly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "72 Control reports Except in the usual cases (control reports for the purposes of the Bp, inheritance tax, wage tax, unit valuation, etc.)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "), particularly in the case of lease / usage relationships, control notifications must be prepared using the \"ESt 34 d\" form"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The cases in which the individual lease / use ratio comprises agricultural areas of more than 2 ha or in which areas with special uses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "of Section 13a Paragraph 4 No. 4 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "I ask that incoming control reports as well as unit value reports always be evaluated promptly because of possible effects on the way in which the taxpayer's profit is determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "When evaluating them, it can be useful to consult the standard value files"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The same also applies to the assessment of farmers and foresters, particularly when determining profits in accordance with Section 13a of the Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "73 Advance payments for winter oilseed rape Reference to the BMF letter of 23 12 1993 - IV B 2 - S-2132 - 24/93 - BStBl 1994 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "1774 Income tax treatment of \"Compensation to certain producers because of their participation in the non-marketing and conversion program\" according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "the non-marketer compensation regulation - NEV - of 20 8 1993 (Federal Law Gazette 1993 I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "1510) It was asked how the o"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Compensation is to be treated in terms of income tax in particular with regard to the following points: a) Time of recognition (when determining profits according to Section 4 Paragraph 1 EStG), b) Application of Sections 24 No. 1 a, 34 Paragraph 1 and 2 EStG, c) Recording when determining profit \u00a7 13a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "In agreement with the Federal Ministry of Finance and the highest tax authorities of the other countries, I comment on this as follows: To a): The claim for compensation is at the time of the application, at the earliest on August 5, 1992 (taxpayers who have the claim for compensation before the announcement of the offer of the EC have asserted) to activate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Although the damaging event occurred in earlier financial years, the claim for compensation will only be concretized with the offer by the EC and acceptance by the taxpayer (application) (cf. a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "BFH judgment of April 26, 1989 BStBl 1991 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "213)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "re b): For the compensation, the tariff reduction according to \u00a7 24 No. 1 a i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Section 34 (1) and (2) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "It is a compensation for lost income, which is accumulated in an assessment period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "The tariff reduction does not include interest"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "to c): The compensation is settled with the basic amount according to \u00a7 13a Abs 4 EStG (see FM decree of 14 3 1985 - (S-2132 A - 442 -; ESt-Kartei: card 18 to \u00a7 13 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "This does not apply to financial years of the compensation period in which \u00a7 13a EStG does not apply"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "For the treatment of changes in area in the meantime, No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "1 letter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "c FM decree of 15 4 1991 - S-2132 A - 442 - (corresponds to BMF letter of 15 4 1991 BStBl I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "49); ESt-Kartei: card 18 e to \u00a7 13 EStG) accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "For the interest, Section 13a (8) No. 3 EStG applies"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107746.xml"}, "text": "Basis: FM decree of 27 January 1994 - S-2230 A - 442 -Income tax / wage tax / church taxAccountingProcedural law / tax codeCommercial law Company lawRhineland-PalatinateAgriculture"}]