[{"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion K\u00f6lnS-2532 - 231 - St 114 S-2532 -S-2532EStG: 2aEStG: 2a / 1EStG: 10 / 3EStG: 10dEStG: 10e / 5aEStG: 15aEStG: 22/4 / bEStG: 34cEStG: 34c / 1EStG: 34c / 2EStG : 34c / 3EStG: 52 / 12AO: 163AO: 180AO: 180/2 Forms for carrying out the personal income tax assessment for 19931 Form ESt 2 A 2 Form ESt 3 A 3 Form ESt 2 B / 3 B 31 Income from business operations 32 The findings in Section A33 Findings according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Section 180 (2) AO 34 In Section C4 Form ESt 2 BE / 3 BE / 4 BE 5 Form ESt 4 B 6 Form ESt 2 C / 3 C / 4 C 7 Form ESt 2 D / 3 D 8 Form ESt 2 E / 3 E The following forms have been reissued for the 1993 assessment period and will be sent to you shortly - if they have not already been issued: Ser"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "No Abbreviation Short description Form No. 724 /"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "1ESt 2 AE Income tax calculation sheet252ESt 3 AEeincome tax assessment263ESt \u200b\u200b2 BFestierungsbogen for separate and uniform assessment28ESt 3 BFestierungsbescheid4Annex ESt 2 BEfor the assessment sheet for building owner and buyer communities59Annex ESt 3 BE for the assessment notice for building owners and buyers 4 4 C Notification sheet for the separate determination 35ESt 3 C Notification of the separate profit determination 7 ESt 2 D Determination sheet \u00a7 10d EStG33ESt 3 D Notification of assessment \u00a7 10d EStG8ESt 2 EEstablishment sheet \u00a7 2a EStG36ESt 3 E Notification of assessment \u00a7 2a EStG (top left) the tax debtor must always be entered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "If the addressee is a third person (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Parent of a minor child), this person must be named in the address field and the taxpayer in the framed field under the year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Should the notification be sent to another person as the recipient (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Tax advisor), this is to be ordered in Section C (Order) No. 12 b; the notification must be addressed accordingly (cf. AO index \u00a7 122, card 2, examples for no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "152)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "12 For the respective types of income, the line \"Deductible foreign taxes according to \u00a7 34c para 2 u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "3 EStG \"does not apply, since in these cases the foreign taxes have to be deducted together with the other operating expenses or business expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "13 The pension allowance according to \u00a7 22 No. 4 letter b EStG (line 33) has been increased by the StMBG of 21 December 1993 from 4800 DM to 6000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "14 The maximum amount calculation (lines 111 - 115) according to \u00a7 10 Paragraph 3 EStG corresponds to the legal situation created by the StMBG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "This version applies to taxpayers with income from non-self-employed work with which the acquisition of entitlement rights or claims to old-age, sickness or unemployment benefits is connected solely on the basis of their own contribution (members of the board of an AG, GmbH-partner-managing directors), according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 52 (12) EStG to be applied for the first time for the VZ 1994"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Because of the minor importance in the personnel procedure, a separate calculation scheme has been dispensed with"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "15 In the new footnote 21 a (page 8) it is pointed out that a crediting of foreign taxes according to \u00a7 34c Abs 1 EStG is only possible for income from capital assets if this is positive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "16 In the scheme for calculating income tax including earnings (lines 236 - 240), the equity regulation according to \u00a7 163 AO (BMF letter of 26 10 1993 S-1900 - 593 - V B 5 - BStBl 1993 I S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "895) incorporated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "17 In particular for cases with a different financial year (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "1 5 1992 to 30 4 1993) and the setting of advance payments according to the SolZG 1995, the section \"Solidarity surcharge\" has been inserted on page 10"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "2 Form ESt 3 A The changes to this form result from the points already addressed in the ESt 2 A form"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "3 Form ESt 2 B / 3 B 31 Income from commercial operations Based on the case law of the BFH, according to which the special business assets of a limited partner when determining the capital account i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 15a EStG is not to be considered, the ESt 1 2 3 B and ESt 1 2 3 B (V) appendix have been changed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "This design was retained in 1993"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "This change has led to the fact that in the cases of \u00a7 15a EStG the total amount of the income to be ascertained for the partnership, which is to be entered in the forms ESt 2 B - assessment form - and ESt 3 B - assessment notice - is no longer by adding up the amounts in column 6 of the Annex ESt 1 2 3 B can be determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "In this respect, a separate calculation is required"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "The applicable profit / loss regularly corresponds to the result from column 2 of the ESt 1 2 3 B (V) annex and columns 3 4 and 5 of the ESt 1 2 3 B annex (pay attention to the signs)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "32 The findings in Section A have been supplemented by a selection field for Section 10e Paragraph 5 a EStG (income limit)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "33 findings according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Section 180 (2) AO Section A (last line) is for the above"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Findings have been expanded for reasons of legal clarity"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "With this, the connection to the forms with annex ESt 1 2 3 B and building owner and buyer groups with annex ESt 2 BE / 3 BE has been established for determinations in the case of laboratory communities (see detailed explanations below)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "34 In Section C, in the cases of an application pursuant to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Section 34c (2) EStG with regard to the taxpayer's right to choose the date of receipt of the declaration"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "4 Form ESt 2 BE / 3 BE / 4 BE 41 According to Section 1 Paragraph 1 No. 2 of the Regulation on Section 180 Paragraph 2 AO, tax bases, in particular income subject to income tax or corporation tax, can be determined separately, in whole or in part, if assets serving to generate income, assets or facilities are separately attributable to several people who have established or maintained similar legal relationships with third parties during the planning, production, maintenance or acquisition of these assets, facilities or facilities (overall property)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "According to No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "21 of the BMF letter of 5 December 1990 (BStBl 1990 I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "764), separate determinations can be made, in particular in the case of builder models that have the furnishing of single-family houses, condominiums or other buildings as their object, and of buyer models, including developer and renovation models"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "For this purpose, the year-neutral form \"Annex for building owners and buyer communities\" was published"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "42 Page 1 contains the sections \"General Findings\" and \"Special Findings\", information on income tax, sales tax and trade tax can be found on page 2 of the ESt 2 BE and ESt 4 BE forms"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "43 The form must be filled out for everyone involved in the property; it is permissible to carry out a separate assessment only for some of the taxpayers who are involved in the overall property (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "312 of the above"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "BMF letter)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "As a rule, this should be done after the completion of an external audit by the relevant tax office / the relevant BPST"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "The determination is only to be carried out for the period until it is ready for occupancy (in the case of builder models) or the first rental or owner-occupation by the taxpayer (in the case of buyer models) (see no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "312 of the above"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "BMF letter; Line 3 of the form)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "The form contains objective data (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Time of completion, types of service fees taken into account) and indirect tax bases (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Assessment basis for depreciation)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "44 In the case of properties that were built in the exercise of a heritable building right, column 7 (land) must be supplemented with information on the heritable building right"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "45 The ESt 2 BE part is intended as an annex to the ESt 2 B assessment form (link to page 1, last fill-in line and No. 4 b of the decision), the ESt 3 BE part is to be attached to the ESt 3 B assessment notice and the ESt 4 BE part is included to combine the income tax 4 B notification (see selection field above \"In order\")"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Information about the amount of the service fees listed in lines 15 to 19 is therefore not required, as these amounts are included in the total expenditure and the tax office of the residence may not take into account other expenditure of the types marked as part of the total expenditure in the income tax assessment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "46 If the determinations are made in one notification for several years, a form must be filled out to the required extent for each determination period"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "5 Form ESt 4 B In addition to the findings, the front page also contains information (see above for form ESt 2 B / 3 B)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "The reverse side was adapted to the ESt 1 2 3 B form"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "In the cases of \u00a7 15a EStG, the total amount according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Column 6 is the amount to be included in the assessment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "6 Form ESt 2 C / 3 C / 4 C The form has been changed with regard to the changes to \u00a7 34c EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "7 Form ESt 2 D / 3 D The separate determination of the remaining loss deduction is also to be carried out automatically in the case of a personal income tax assessment (subject 10, part 17 DA-ADV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise there are no changes compared to the previous year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "8 Form ESt 2 E / 3 E The negative income according to \u00a7 2a Abs 1 EStG, which can be compensated for a limited time, decreases from year to year (1986 - 1991)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "The negative income that can be compensated without restriction (from 1992) no longer needs to be separated on a yearly basis and is only to be found in one total amount in lines 10 and 21"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "Separate determinations must always be made for spouses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0107576.xml"}, "text": "--- Wage tax External tax law Income tax / wage tax / church tax procedural law / tax code of North Rhine-Westphalia"}]