[{"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion D\u00fcsseldorfS-2230 A - St 111S-2230EStK \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG Fach 1 Nr 1001EStG: 13EStG: 13aEStG: 4 / 1EStG: 4 / 3EStG: 4aEStG: 6cEStG: 7EStG: 7aEStG: 7bEStG: 7gEStG: 7bEStG: 7gEStG: 7dEStG: 7gEStG: 7iEStG: 7kEStG: 10/1 / 1aEStG: 34eEStG: 52 / 15EStR: 12EStR: 14EStR: 16EStR: 124aEStR: 125EStR: 125aEStR: 127EStR: 130aEStR: 135BewG: 22BewG: 36BewG: 44AO: 162A: 162 175/1 / 2EStDV: 52EStDV: 76EStDV: 82aEStDV: 82gIncome tax assessment of farmers and foresters for the assessment period 19931 General The assessment orders for farmers and foresters are issued in full"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Changes compared to the previous text - with the exception of purely editorial changes - are marked by vertical lines"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "2 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry according to average rates (\u00a7 13a EStG) 21 Scope In addition to R 127 EStR 1993 and No. 2 of the introductory letter of the BMF dated 27 3 1981 (BStBl I 1981 282), the following is pointed out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "211 Areas to be taken into account The self-cultivated, own, leased areas that have been set aside due to public funding programs must be taken into account (R 124a Paragraph 3 EStR 1993)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "212 Regarding Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 2 EStG (initial value limit) The initial value determined in accordance with Section 13a Paragraph 4 EStG is decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Cattle surcharges can therefore not be taken into account as long as they are not the subject of a value update according to \u00a7\u00a7 41 i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "V with 22 para 1 no 1 BewG have been made"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Something else only applies if the requirements of Section 13a Paragraph 4 No. 1 Sentence 4 EStG are met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "213 On \u00a7 13a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG (animal population limit) When examining the VE limits of \u00a7 13a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStG, R 124a EStR 1993 is to be applied accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The prerequisite for the elimination of the determination of the average rate of profit is that the number of VE sustainably exceeds the limits of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Regarding the concept of sustainability, reference is made to R 135 (2) EStR 1993"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the following applies: In the event of a gradual increase in animal populations, it depends on whether the animal populations converted into VE have been above the limits of \u00a7 13a Paragraph 1 No. 3 EStR over the three preceding financial years"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If this is the case, the requirements of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG are no longer met from the beginning of the fourth financial year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "On the other hand, if the livestock are z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "in connection with an expansion of the stable capacities significantly above the maximum permissible limits, so that the limits can also be expected in the following financial years, the requirements of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG do not apply from the time the maximum limits are exceeded for the first time on"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "When determining the animal population, foreign animals must also be taken into account (BFH, judgment of 23 9 1988 BStBl II 1989 111)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The maximum number of animals permitted in accordance with Section 13a Paragraph 1 No. 3 13 Paragraph 1 No. 1 EStG and converted into VE can be found in the overview attached as Annex 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "22 Determination of profits The scheme for determining the profit according to \u00a7 13a Paragraph 3 to 8 EStG results from the form \"Annex ESt 2 L / 3 L - Determination of profits according to \u00a7 13a EStG\""}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "In detail, I would like to point out the following: 221 Basic amount When determining the basic amount according to Section 13a Paragraph 4 EStG, R 124a Paragraph 3 and 130a Paragraph 1 EStR 1993 must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "222 Value of the work performance In the case of the basic amount according to Section 13a (4) EStG, it is assumed that the business is managed exclusively with paid workers (see Section 36 (2) BewG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The value of the work performed by the business owner and his relatives who are not employed in the company on the basis of an employment relationship to be determined in accordance with Section 13a (5) EStG must therefore be added to the basic amount (Section 13a (3) No. 2 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "R 130a Paragraph 3 to 5 EStR 1993 and H 130a EStH 1993 must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "In detail, the following is also pointed out: When determining the value of the work performance for the physical work of the business owner and the relatives who are not employed, only the work performance is to be taken into account in the result that is based on the initial value according to Section 13a (4) EStG in the individual case No space required"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The paid workers are to be counted towards the appropriate number of full-time workers (VAK) according to the duration of their employment (\u00a7 13a Abs 5 Nr 5 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to temporary workers employed on a short-term basis as well as to workers who have been made available by contractors for ordering, maintenance or harvesting work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "For the crediting of the paid VAK"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "a breakdown of the wages is necessary, insofar as what) is not applicable to the uses contained in the initial value (Section 13a (4) EStG) and b) to the uses not contained therein (BFH, judgment of 14 4 1988 BStBl II 1988 774)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Make taxpayers in the tax return (form \"Annex L\") to the extent / proportion of their employment or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "the activities of other people (relatives, third parties) in the company or no or obviously incorrect information on the part of the work attributable to special uses, the (physical) work or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "the proportion of the work performed by the business owner, the relatives employed in the business and / or the remunerated workers, if applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "with the assistance of the responsible official agricultural expert (ALS)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The tables in the Felsmann commentary, Income Taxation of Farmers and Foresters, under C 219 219a on the average labor requirement for special branches of business can serve as a guide to determine the proportion that is attributable to special uses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "For examples of calculating the value of the work, see Appendix 2223 Rent collected. Reference is made to Section 13a (6) sentence 2 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The rent received also includes income from ground rent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Income from hunting leases, on the other hand, is compensated by applying the basic amount insofar as it is attributable to areas included in the initial value"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "224 Profits according to Section 13a Paragraph 8 EStG Reference is made to Section 13a Paragraph 8 EStG and R 130a Paragraph 8 EStR 1993"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "In addition, please note the following: Profits from operations that were not taken into account when determining the initial value are, in particular,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "a) Additional profits from sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals (see Section 2241), b) Profits from renting rooms to holiday guests, insofar as it is income from agriculture and forestry (for delimitation see Section 103 (7) BewRL) , c) Interest income, insofar as the capital claim is attributable to the business assets, d) Profits from renting own horses, insofar as it is income from agriculture and forestry (for delimitation see H 135 (Reitpferde) EStH 1993), e) Profits from pensioner animal husbandry and wage rearing (cf. 2242), f) profits from participations belonging to the agricultural and forestry business assets, g) profits from the rental of buildings and parts of buildings belonging to the agricultural and forestry business assets, h) profits from the sale of milk quotas (cf. \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, subject 6 No. 13) and sugar beet quotas, i) compensation for economic difficulties (see \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, subject 6 No. 10)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Profits from the cross-company use of machines, which are achieved in the context of agriculture and forestry, are in part to be recorded in accordance with Section 13a (8) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "In this respect, reference is made to \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, Subject 7 No. 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The Stpfl can determine the profits (additional profits) according to \u00a7 13a Abs 8 EStG either by comparing assets according to \u00a7 4 Abs 1 EStG or by comparing the operating income and operating expenses (\u00a7 4 Abs 3 EStG) (H 130a (determination of profits) EStH 1993)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If no records are available, the profits (additional profits) are to be estimated (R 130a Paragraph 8 Sentence 6 EStR 1993)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "When estimating the profits (additional profits) from sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals, from retirement animal husbandry, from vegetable and fruit growing as well as from asparagus and strawberry cultivation and from trout pond farming, the following guidelines can serve as a guide"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "However, their application must not lead to an obviously incorrect taxation (BFH, judgment of 16 12 1965 BStBl III 1966 193)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "To determine the profit see also BFH, judgment of 14 4 1988 BStBl II 1988 774)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "With exclusive winnings i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 13a Abs 8 EStG - although the profits are determined according to \u00a7 4 Abs 3 EStG - the tax reduction according to \u00a7 34e EStG does not apply (BFH, judgment of 28 11 1991 BStBl II 1992 458)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "2241 Sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals From the sale of breeding cattle, according to Section 13a (8) No. 3 EStG, only extraordinary income is to be recorded as a surcharge that is achieved due to the special quality of the animals at prices significantly above average (BFH, judgment from 18 4 1991 BStBl II 1991 833)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Income by which the individual selling prices including sales tax exceed the following values \u200b\u200bare to be regarded as extraordinary: Breeding bulls 4200 DM breeding cows u"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "- Cattle 3200 DM Breeding boars 1100 DM Breeding sows 1000 DM For breeding and riding horses, the additional profit is 60 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "the amount by which the selling price exceeds the amount of 7500 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If a sales price of more than 16,250 DM is achieved, the full amount of 11,000 DM (7,500 DM + 40%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of 8,750 DM)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The aforementioned amounts include all expenses incurred in rearing and selling the animals (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Rearing costs, acquisition costs for purchased animals, wages, auction fees, insurance contributions, transport costs, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "), so cannot be deducted separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The additional profit has to be calculated individually for each animal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "A netting with sales proceeds that are below the values \u200b\u200blisted may therefore not be carried out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If in individual cases for others than the above"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Breeding animals (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Fallow deer, sheep, goats) extraordinary proceeds are achieved, the surcharge must be estimated based on the aforementioned simplification rule"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "2242 Profit from animal husbandry In the case of animal husbandry, income and profits are essentially dependent on the type of husbandry (stable or paddock husbandry), the type of animal kept (e"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Horses or cattle) and the services (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "for horses also use of riding arenas)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "In the case of pension horse keeping, the income includes payments for keeping and caring for the horses as well as remuneration for the use of riding arenas"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Depending on the location of the business and the type of services offered, the income fluctuates between 250 DM and around 600 DM for robust horses between 100 DM and 250 DM per retired horse"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "When determining the profit, the judgment of the BFH of 14 4 1988 (BStBl II 1988 774) must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The net profit for boarding horses is usually 60%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of receipts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "2243 Agricultural and horticultural vegetable growing For the delimitation of agricultural and horticultural vegetable growing, see Sect. 108 Paragraph 2 and 607 Paragraph 1 No. 1 BewRL"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If vegetable growing is then to be assigned to agricultural use, a surcharge according to Section 13a (8) EStG is not possible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Vegetable cultivation in the context of agricultural use only occurs if headed cabbage (white, red and savoy cabbage), picking peas and picking beans are grown exclusively according to agricultural cultivation methods as part of the agricultural crop rotation as the main crop"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "On the other hand, if the types of cabbage and / or peas or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Do not alternate beans with other agricultural crops such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Wheat, rye, barley, oats or beets, but one after the other or alternately with the same or different types of vegetables (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Endive, lettuce, lamb's lettuce, spinach, carrots, celery, beetroot, onions, radishes, leeks, tomatoes, kohlrabi, cucumbers, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": ") cultivated, the cultivation is no longer part of the agricultural crop rotation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Rather, it is a vegetable cultivation to be assessed according to horticultural principles (vegetable cultivation division of the horticultural use of vegetables, flowers and ornamental plants), which is to be recorded as a surcharge under the conditions of Section 13a (8) No. 1 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If, in individual cases, an estimation method tailored to the company's circumstances is not preferable, or if the accounting results of comparable companies or empirical data are not available, the profit can be estimated as follows: a) Vegetable growing in the open air (income mainly from growing open-air vegetables) Income between DM 40,000 and DM 80,000 per ha Net profit 40 to 65 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of receipts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "b) Vegetable growing with roofed cultivation areas (income mainly from vegetables grown under glass) Income between 80,000 DM and 135,000 DM per hectare of net profit 30 to 65 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of receipts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The profit is influenced by the type of marketing (auction in the wholesale market, sale from the farm or on the weekly market) and the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "An accurate estimate in individual cases is usually only possible in close cooperation with the ALS"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "2244 Fruit growing The income varies between 15,000 and 35,000 DM per hectare"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "They depend on the type of fruit, the types of fruit, the age structure of the orchard, the quality of the soil and the climate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Special natural events such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Late frosts can lead to lower income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The net profit can be 30 to 50 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of revenues are estimated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The profit is influenced by the type of marketing (auction in the wholesale market, sale from the farm, sale at the weekly market) and the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "An accurate estimate in individual cases is usually only possible in close cooperation with the ALS"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "2245 asparagus cultivation The income per hectare of asparagus cultivation area fluctuates between 24,000 and 34,000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The net profit can be 30 to 60 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of revenues are estimated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The profit is influenced by the type of marketing (auction in the wholesale market, sale from the farm, sale at the weekly market) and the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "An accurate estimate in individual cases is usually only possible in close cooperation with the ALS"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "2246 Strawberry cultivation The income per hectare of strawberry cultivation area fluctuates between 25,000 and 50,000 DM and the net profit between 50 and 70 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of receipts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The amount of income and profit are influenced by the type of marketing (sale on the farm, auction or by self-pickers) and the wages"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "2247 Trout pond farming The profits are i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "for full farms (mainly edible fish production) 35 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of the income and in the case of farms (mainly fish production) 40%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of receipts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If no information is given about the income, the following framework rates can be used for the profits: operating mode framework rates average rate labor requirements DM / qmDM / qmVAK / ha full farms10 - 402004 breeding farms4 - 401804 wages, rent, lease and debt interest are not yet taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "So you can still be deducted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The profit can be increased by up to 10% in individual cases"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "be increased or decreased"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "An increase in profit comes into consideration, in particular, if fish farming is carried out exclusively or predominantly or if table trout are largely refined into smoked trout"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "A reduction can be considered if it can be proven that losses had to be accepted due to low water inflow and poor water quality"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "225 Value in use of the apartment 2251 Approach of the value in use Reference is made to R 130a (7) EStR 1993"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "With regard to the value in use of the apartment for elderly people - insofar as Section 52 Paragraph 15 S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "4 EStG does not apply - the BFH judgment of July 28, 1983 (BStBl II 1984 97) must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the value in use is to be attributed to the owner even in the case of real security and to be taken into account in the corresponding amount as a permanent burden in accordance with Section 10 (1) No. 1 a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "2252 Loss of value in use taxation In cases of deselection of value in use taxation, form No. 724/74 \"Questionnaire on the withdrawal of an apartment from business assets\" must be sent to determine the facts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If the value-in-use taxation does not apply to the fiscal year deviating from the calendar year, particular attention must be paid to the fact that the value in use still to be assessed up to 31 December is included in the profit for the fiscal year and is to be allocated to the different calendar years on a pro-rata basis according to Section 4a (2) No. 1 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "As far as the value in use taxation according to \u00a7 52 Abs 15 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "4 EStG is retrospectively deselected, the application also regularly affects the amount of income from the previous year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If the assessment of the previous year has already been finalized, it must be changed in accordance with Section 175 (1) No. 2 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "226 Lease interest paid out, interest on debts Reference is made to Section 13a (3) sentence 2 EStG and R 130a (6) EStR 1993"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Interest subsidies from public funds reduce the deductible debt interest"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Regarding the income tax treatment of the interest subsidy subsidies according to the agricultural loan program, see \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, Fach 6 Nr.5 1993 (see \u00a7 4 (4) EStG Subject 3 No. 1) to be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "227 Other additions and reductions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The following can be considered: additions and deductions according to \u00a7 6c EStG, increased deductions for residential buildings according to \u00a7 7b EStG i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "V with \u00a7 52 EStDV, insofar as the value-in-use taxation is continued according to \u00a7 52 Paragraph 15 Clause 2 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "This reduction is therefore no longer applicable from the 1994/1995 financial year. The other increased deductions according to \u00a7\u00a7 7c, 7d, 7g, 7h, 7i and 7k EStG, 82a and 82g EStDV and according to the Protective Building Act cannot be used when determining profits according to \u00a7 13a Paragraphs 3 to 7 EStG must be taken into account because the average rates basically compensate for the depreciation and thus also the increased deductions that replace them (BFH, judgment of 7 6 1984 BStBl II 1984 663)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "However, if an asset is used in a part of the business whose full income is to be recorded in accordance with Section 13a (8) EStG, increased deductions can also be taken into account when determining the profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "23 Voluntary business assets When determining profits according to \u00a7 13a EStG, arbitrary business assets cannot be formed (BFH, judgment of 23 5 1991 BStBl II 1991 798)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "In the event of a change in use, however, arbitrary business assets can be retained (R 14 para 3 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "6 EStR 1993; \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, subject 4 no 8)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Regarding the treatment of land encumbered with heritable building rights as voluntary business assets see also BFH, judgment of 10 12 1992 (BStBl II 1993 342)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "3 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry by comparing the operating income with the operating expenses (Section 4 (3) EStG) 31 Determination of profits (R 16 EStR 1993) In addition, I would like to point out the following: 311 average values \u200b\u200bfor livestock R 125 EStR 1993) can acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "R 125a EStR 1993, under certain conditions, can also be used when determining profits in accordance with Section 4 (3) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "For the rest, I refer to Section 441312 Value in Use of the Apartment To determine the value in use of the apartment, reference is made to \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, Subject 8 No. 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the value in use is to be measured according to the circumstances of the individual case, also for farmers and foresters"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise, Sect. 225 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "4 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry through bookkeeping (\u00a7 4 Paragraph 1 EStG) 41 Scope of application Reference is made to the BMF letter of 15 December 1981 (\u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, subject 4 No. 1)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Surcharges for increased animal husbandry are also to be taken into account when determining the economic value limit according to \u00a7 141 Paragraph 1 No. 3 AO if they are not or not yet the subject of a value update according to \u00a7\u00a7 41 i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "V with 22 para 1 no 1 BewG have been made"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "42 Opening balance sheet To check the opening balance sheet when transitioning to the comparison of business assets, reference is made to \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, subject 4 no 5"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "43 Bookkeeping On R 12 para 1 EStR 1993 and the BMF letter of 15 12 1981 (a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": ") being point out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "44 Profit determination 441 Average livestock values \u200b\u200bReference is made to R 125 EStR 1993"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The applicable average livestock values \u200b\u200bresult from \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG, Fach 4 Nr 6. With regard to the judgment of the BFH of 1 October 1992 (BStBl II 1993 284) they are z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "revised"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The previous regulations can continue to be applied until the announcement"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "442 Value in use of the apartment Section 312 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "5 Estimate of the profit for farmers and foresters whose profit cannot be determined according to average rates51 General For farmers and foresters who are obliged to keep accounts but do not keep proper books, the profit is to be estimated in individual cases according to \u00a7 162 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to those farmers and foresters who are neither obliged to keep accounts nor meet the requirements of \u00a7 13a Paragraph 1 No. 2 and 3 EStG if they do not have any books in the sense of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 4 Abs 1 EStG and also the operating income and expenses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of Section 4 (3) EStG (R 127 (1) EStR 1993)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The estimate has - with the exception of that in R 12 para 2 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "6 EStR 1993 - to be carried out according to the principles of Section 4 (1) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "When making the estimate, all circumstances must be taken into account that are important for the estimate in individual cases (Section 162 (1) sentence 2 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The aim of the estimate must be to determine the profit actually achieved"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The uncertainties inherent in an estimate are, however, at the expense of the taxpayer, who himself gave cause for the estimate by neglecting his tax cooperation obligations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "It must also be ensured that farmers who are required to keep accounts and whose profits are estimated are reported to the tax auditors if an examination appears to be suitable to encourage the farmer to set up accounts or if the examination promises success for other reasons"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If a tax audit is planned in these cases, the assessment must be carried out subject to the review (Section 164 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "According to the principles of the FinMin NRW decree of 31 7 1989 S-0337 - 1 - V C 2, it is announced with the Vfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "dated 21 8 1989 S-0337 A - St 31 H, to decide"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The following explanatory text must be included in the notification or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "to be attached as an attachment: \"The profit from agriculture and forestry was for the financial year 19"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "/ 19th"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 162 AO estimated because you have not declared your profit or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "because you declared a profit that was not determined by bookkeeping, although you are obliged to keep the books"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If you actually achieved a higher profit than the estimated, the tax would have been set too low"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "In this case, there may be tax evasion or frivolous tax reduction"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "You can then, however, by declaring the profit actually achieved under the further requirements of \u00a7\u00a7 371 378 Paragraph 3 AO punitive or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Obtain no fines"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Furthermore, I would like to point out that failure to comply with the accounting obligation can already result in a tax risk"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "\"52 Estimation of the profit according to standard rates Which estimation method is to be used in the individual case is left to the discretion of the tax office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If, in individual cases, an estimation method tailored to the particular operational conditions is not to be preferred or if no circumstances particularly influencing the operating result, such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Seed propagation or field vegetable cultivation, exist or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "have been determined in the course of a previous tax audit and accounting results of comparable companies or empirical records are not available, the profit is to be estimated according to the principles of \u00a7 4 Paragraph 1 EStG as follows: starting amount (section 521) + rental income (section 522) + surcharges for Profits not paid for with the starting amount or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits (Sect. 523) + value in use of the apartment (Sect. 524)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Wage expenses (Section 525)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Rent expenses, debt interest (Sect. 526) +"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "other surcharges and reductions (section 527) = profit for the financial year The following guide rates are intended as a guide for an accurate estimate of the profit (R 127 paragraph 1 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "4 EStR 1993)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "At the same time, a reduction in the estimated profit due to objections to individual points in the valuation process is generally out of the question because special circumstances in an individual branch of the business do not allow any conclusions to be drawn about the profit of the entire business"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The application of the standard rates must not lead to an obviously incorrect taxation (BFH, judgment of 16 12 1965 BStBl III 1966 193)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "521 Starting amount The starting amount per hectare of usable agricultural area (UAA) for the 1993/1994 financial year is: 1for pasture farming (grassland share 71%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "and more of the LN) 1400 DM2 for mixed farms (grassland share 31 to 70 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "der LN) with a root crop content of a) less than 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "the LN1400 DMb) 15 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "and more of the LN1500 DMc) If the root crop content is more than 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "the LN and is in it a sugar beet content of more than 20%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of the LN, the starting amount increases to 2000 DMd) If the root crop portion exceeds 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "the LN, are each started 5 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Additional share of root crops to be added to the above starting amounts per DM 2003 for arable farms (share of grassland up to 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "der LN) with a root crop content of a) less than 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "the LN1400 DMb) 15 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "and more the LN1600 DMc) If the root crop content is more than 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "the LN and is in it a sugar beet content of more than 20%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of the LN, the starting amount increases to 2000 DMd) If the root crop portion exceeds 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "the LN, are each started 5 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "In the case of dairy cow husbandry, the starting amounts (No. 1 - 3) are to be increased as follows in accordance with the average dairy cow population of the farm: a) less than 05 cows / ha LN250 DMb) 05 to less than 1 cows / ha LN400 DMc) 1 to less than 15 cows / ha LN550 DMd) 15 and more cows / ha LN800 DM In cases of repeated profit estimates, the starting amounts may be"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "a safety margin of up to 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "to increase"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The surcharge is not to be shown separately, but to be incorporated into the starting amounts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Only the pure agricultural production areas belong to the agricultural use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Areas for buildings, courtyards, paths, ditches, field borders, water, land, quarries, sand pits, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Areas are therefore not considered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Areas for house gardens are also not included"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise R 124a Paragraph 3 EStR 1993 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "According to this, areas set aside due to public funding programs are still considered to be used for agriculture"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "For the calculation of the relevant root crop, grassland or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Sugar beet share depends on the size of these shares in the respective marketing year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The areas under cultivation of root crops do not include those areas on which root crops are only grown as catch crops or as catch crops"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Only the meadows and pastures listed in Sect. 5232 are to be regarded as grassland area, the other crops mentioned there (forage plants) belong to field forage cultivation, the areas of which belong to the field"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "522 Lease income Lease income including the income from the milk quota leasing, ground rent and hunting leases, reduced by proportionate operating expenses, such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Property taxes are to be added to the starting amount if they are included in income from agriculture and forestry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "This is the case when the leased or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Hereditary assets belong to the lessor's agricultural and forestry business assets"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "523 Surcharges for winnings or winnings not settled with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "All profits from sustainable or one-off operating income that are not included in the starting amount are to be added to the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Such surcharges come z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "into consideration for additional profits from sales of breeding cattle and other valuable animals or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "whole animal herds, profits from abnormal animal husbandry, additional profits from special crops, profits from other special business branches (see \"Special business income\" on p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "4 of Annex L), profits from the withdrawal and sale of land (see \"Sale / withdrawal of land\" on the S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "2 of Annex L); Profits from the rental of buildings and parts of buildings belonging to the agricultural and forestry business assets; Profits from the sale of milk quotas and sugar beet quotas, as well as from a quota leasing; Compensation for economic difficulties"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "5231 Sales of breeding cattle and other valuable animals As additional profit from the sale of breeding cattle and other valuable animals, the amounts by which the individual sales proceeds including sales tax exceed the following values: Breeding bulls DM 3,400 breeding cows and"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "-cattle 2600 DM breeding boars 900 DM breeding sows 800 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "For breeding and riding horses, the additional profit is 60 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "the amount by which the selling price exceeds the amount of 6000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If a sales price of more than DM 13,000 is achieved, the full amount of DM 8,800 (DM 6,000 + 40%) is to be recognized as additional profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "of 7000 DM)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Wages for paid workers as well as the selling costs (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Auction fees, insurance premiums, transport costs) are already taken into account when calculating the initial values, so they cannot be set separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The additional profit must also be calculated individually for each animal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Offsetting against sales proceeds that are below the above values \u200b\u200bmay not be carried out in this context"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The same procedure is to be followed if above-average prices are achieved for breeding animals other than those specified or for other valuable animals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The value to be taken as a basis in these cases results from the tax production costs of the animal species in question plus an assumed profit surcharge of 20% included in the initial value for the area with normal animal husbandry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "5232 Abnormal animal husbandry Profits from animal breeding and husbandry are settled with the starting amount, provided that the average normal animal population is not exceeded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "As animal husbandry paid for with the starting amount, other farms for the first 20 ha LN22 VE / ha14 VE / ha for the next 10 ha LN16 VE / ha08 VE / ha for the next 20 ha LN15 VE / ha07 VE / ha over 50 ha LN a total of at most 90 VE50 VE forage growers are Farms where the forage area is 60%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "and more of the usable agricultural area without courtyard and building space, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "matters"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "In this context, the forage area includes: Meadows (incl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Tree meadows, litter meadows), cattle pastures and fields, as well as the cultivation areas for clover in pure seed and mixed cultivation, clover grass, alfalfa, seradella, sainfoin, green corn, vetches, sweet lupins and all other forage plants"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Areas on which grain is grown for grain production are not included in the forage area even if the grain is fed to the livestock kept on the farm"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "When calculating the number of animals and converting them into VE, R 124a Paragraph 1 EStR 1993 must be used"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The average herds (lines 80-86 of Appendix L) and the animals produced (lines 87-93 of Appendix L) are to be summarized"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Care must be taken that no animals are recorded twice"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "For the excess inventory remaining after the normal inventory has been taken into account, a profit of DM 300 per VE is to be set"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Wages are not taken into account here and can therefore still be deducted separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "5233 Field vegetable cultivation (agricultural use) Field vegetable cultivation is understood to mean the cultivation of vegetables according to agricultural cultivation methods within the framework of agricultural crop rotation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "A distinction must be made between field vegetable cultivation in annual cultivation and field vegetable cultivation as a replica"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Additional profit not settled with the starting amount (Section 521) is to be set as follows: For field vegetable cultivation in annual cultivation: 7,000 DM per hectare minus the amount per hectare per hectare stated in the starting amount for this area, as a replica: 5,000 DM per hectare (without reduction)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "It is up to the Stpfl to provide evidence of the actual proceeds from vegetable growing in the fields"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "In these cases, a discount of 25 per cent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "be acknowledged"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The remaining amount is only to be reduced in the case of field vegetable cultivation in annual cultivation by the amount per hectare / UI set in the starting amount for this area"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The above standard rates do not take into account wages and can therefore still be deducted separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "5234 Vegetable growing (horticultural use), fruit growing (horticultural use), asparagus and strawberry cultivation as well as trout pond farming Sections 2243 to 2247 apply accordingly to the determination of profits"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "As a surcharge on the starting amount, however, only the additional profit, i.e."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "the profit reduced by the pro-rata starting amount applied in the individual case"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "524 Value in use of the apartment Section 312 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "When estimating the profit, the gross value in use must always be applied, because the expenses associated with the apartment - with the exception of interest on debt (Section 526) and the increased deductions (Section 527) - are taken into account when determining the starting amounts (Section 521) and are thus settled"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "525 Wage expenses The starting amount (Section 521) is based on the assumption that the company is managed exclusively with unpaid workers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Wage expenses are therefore to be deducted from the starting amount insofar as they relate to the profits settled with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The treatment of wage expenses incurred with profits or income not paid for in the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits (see Sect. 523) result from the respective surcharge regulations (Sections 5231 to 5234)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "For the distribution of wage expenses required in individual cases, Sect. 222 Nos. 2 and 3 apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The wage expenses to be deducted also include the expenses for temporary workers employed on a short-term basis as well as for the workers who have been made available by contractors for ordering, maintenance or harvesting work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If wage expenses in connection with machine expenses are invoiced in one sum by contractors, there are generally no concerns that the proportionate wage expenses to be taken into account at 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "estimate the gross expense"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If the contractor also supplies seeds, fertilizers and pesticides and bills them together with the machine performance, the invoice amount must be adjusted for the delivery fee included in order to calculate the wage expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "526 Lease expenses, debt interest Such expenses can be deducted if they are operating expenses and have not already been taken into account when determining the surcharges according to Section 523"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If, in addition to the rent for the lease of land and / or buildings (net lease), the lessee bears other expenses relating to the leased property (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Property tax, apportionment of the Chamber of Agriculture, building insurance), these expenses are not deductible as business expenses, as they have already been taken into account when determining the starting amounts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If the lessee does not (or no longer) tax a value in use for a jointly leased apartment, the part of the total rent that is attributable to the apartment cannot be deducted as business expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "527 Other surcharges and reductions 5271 Increase in the starting amounts due to the use of third-party buildings (AfA): When calculating the starting amount, the deduction for wear and tear from the value of the business premises is taken into account in accordance with Section 7 EStG, because it is assumed that the business is managed by the owner himself becomes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "In cases of leasing or free transfer of agricultural operations in whole or in part of a business with buildings, the depreciation for the business buildings is available to the lessor or the lessor"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "to the farmer leaving the property free of charge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "For this reason, the authorized user (manager of the business) has to increase the starting amount (Section 521) by 100 DM per hectare of leased LN"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "It is up to the lessee (beneficial owner) to prove the AfA in detail"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "5272 Reduction of the starting amounts due to increased deductions for residential buildings As such come - if the value in use taxation according to \u00a7 52 Abs 15 S."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "2 EStG will be continued - increased deductions for residential buildings according to \u00a7 7b EStG and in other cases increased deductions according to \u00a7\u00a7 7c, 7d, 7h, 7i, 7k EStG and 82a and 82g EStDV are possible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "These increased deductions are, however, by the depreciation already taken into account in the starting amount according to \u00a7 7 Abs 4 EStG in the amount of 2 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "to shorten"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The increased deductions according to \u00a7 7g EStG, on the other hand, must be taken into account in full"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "However, after the benefit period has expired, the starting amounts must be increased by surcharges"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Section 5273 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "5273 Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDVEs it should be noted that special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV only comes into consideration for those investments that have been acquired or made up to the end of the financial year 1991/92 (1992) (\u00a7 76 Abs 4 EStDV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV has been carried out in the past, the starting amount must be increased by a surcharge after the expiry of the benefit period of three financial years, since according to \u00a7 7a paragraph 9 EStG the residual value is the assessment basis for the further deductions for wear and tear of the starting amount otherwise excessive depreciation amounts would be taken into account"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The surcharge for a financial year results from the sum of the special depreciation granted divided by the remaining useful life of the respective asset"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The initial amount must be increased for the remaining period of use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "In order to ensure that the surcharges are also taken into account in future assessments, the control sheet for profit surcharges (Section 76 EStDV), form no. 724/49, must be kept and attached to the income tax file"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "6 Other 61 Partial retirement benefits 611 The value of the non-cash partial retirement benefits is to be estimated in accordance with Section 1 Paragraph 1 of the SachBezV in the version applicable for the respective assessment period (H 87 (partial retirement benefit) EStH 1993)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The values \u200b\u200bare published annually in BStBl Part I."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "For the assessment periods 1993 and 1994, the following values \u200b\u200bcan then be used as a basis without individual proof: 19931994 for meals- for an elderly couple 3823 DM3593 DM- for an elderly couple6882 DM7115 DMfor heating and lighting- for an elderly couple850 DM878 DM- for an elderly couple1529 DM1580 DM and with regard to the value for heating However, there are no concerns about lighting if the (proportionate) actual costs are included"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "612 If the value-in-use taxation ceases to apply on December 31, 1993, the pensioner may deduct the full value in use of the apartment to be assessed for the pensioner up to this point in the 1993 calendar year as special expenses, although he has a partial amount in accordance with Section 4a (2) No. 1 EStG of the value in use is not taxable until the calendar year 1994 (cf. 2252)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "62 Control notifications Except in the usual cases (control notifications for the purposes of the Bp, the recording of taxable transactions with other taxpayers, inheritance tax), control notifications are to be prepared in the following cases in particular: a) The competent assessment body is to be informed of the declarations of the taxpayer or taxpayer"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "to disclose circumstances arising from the files that may affect the level of the fixed unit values \u200b\u200b(e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Change of areas for special uses, changes in animal populations)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Information that may be of importance for an award according to \u00a7 41 BewG can be found on p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "4 of Appendix L summarized"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "I therefore ask, in all cases in which the animal population declared in Annex L obviously exceeds or exceeds the animal population customary in the opposite direction"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "in which, for other reasons, a surcharge according to \u00a7 41 BewG may be considered, the assessment body can be informed by sending a copy of page 4 of Annex L."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "b) Are access or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Leases known, so the lessor or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Inform the leaseholder of the competent assessment office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to the transfer of use free of charge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "In addition, I ask you to ensure that the Stpfl on S"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "2 of Annex L give the exact address of the lessee / lessor"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "c) In particular, cases without signal \"A\", in which wage expenses are claimed, and cases with significant wage expenses are to be reported to the responsible wage tax office for examination by the wage tax field audit (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Section 525)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "63 Unit value notifications Unit value notifications for agricultural and forestry assets must always be evaluated promptly, particularly because of the possible effects on the way in which the Stpfl's profit is determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "64 Consultation of the valuation files when carrying out the assessment In particular when determining profits in accordance with Section 13a of the Income Tax Act (EStG) and in valuation cases, I ask that you refer to the assessment files for the assessment and review of the values \u200b\u200bto be applied in the individual case when calculating profits"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "65 Review of the Annex L According to \u00a7 150 Para. 1 and 2 AO, book-keeping farmers are also obliged to fill out tax returns including the annexes and thus in particular also Annex L completely and truthfully"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "This applies in particular to the area data in lines 32 to 49 of Annex L, which are not only indispensable for the taxation of appraisal farmers, but also"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "also serve to check the applicable profit determination method, to test profits and to be able to monitor value updates"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The section \"Sale / Withdrawal of Land\" contains the essential basic information required to examine profits from sales and withdrawals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If the required information can be clearly found in the individual case from the balance sheet or similar documents, a reference in Annex L to the relevant documents is sufficient"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "The information on p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "4 of Annex L to the livestock are for the demarcation of agricultural from commercial animal breeding or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Animal husbandry, for sales taxation and for the applicable profit determination method"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "I would therefore ask you to work towards ensuring that farmers and foresters who keep books also fill out Appendix L in full in future"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "If this does not happen and if the missing information is essential for taxation and if this information does not result from the documents otherwise submitted, a copy of the incomplete Annex L must be returned for the purpose of completion"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "I point out the possibility of using coercive measures"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Appendix 1 Maximum permitted number of animals in livestock units (VE) according to Section 13a (1) No. 3 and Section 13 (1) No. 1 of the Income Tax Act (EStG) regularly used agricultural areas in ha Maximum permitted number of animals in VE Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG for businesses with Section 13 (1) No. 1 EStGbis to 76 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Pigs and poultry (3 VE / ha) over 76%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Pigs and poultry (4 VE / ha) in ganzen1101010220202033030304303040530305063030607303070830328093036901030401001133441101236481201339521301442561401545601501648631601751661701854691801957721902060752002163782072266812142369842212472872282575902352678932422781962492884992562987102263309010527031931082733296111276339911427934102117282351051202853610812328837111126291381141292943911713229740120135300f\u00fcr any other ha3315Von the consumption of the system 2 was apart"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Up to 15 ha 4 VE / ha, thereafter 3 VE / ha"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124395.xml"}, "text": "Income taxIncome tax / income tax / church taxAccountingValuationProcedural law / tax codeTax tax auditNorth Rhine-WestphaliaAgricultureSTED"}]