[{"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The Minister of Finance of the State of North Rhine-Westphalia S-2230EStK \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG Fach 1 Nr 3000EStG: 4 / 1EStG: 4 / 3EStG: 13EStG: 13aEStG: 13a / 1 / 2EStG: 13a / 1 / 3EStG: 13a / 4EStG: 13a / 6 / 2EStG: 13a / 8EStG: 13a / 5Income tax assessment of farmers and foresters for the assessment period 19931 General2 Determination of profit from agriculture and forestry according to average rates (Section 13a EStG) 21 Scope211 Areas to be taken into account212 On Section 13a (1) No. 2 EStG ( Baseline value limit) 213 On \u00a7 13a (1) No. 3 EStG (animal stock limit) 22 Determination of profit221 Basic amount222 Value of work performance223 Rent income received224 Profits according to \u00a7 13a (8) EStG2241 Sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals2242 Vegetable growing (agricultural and horticultural vegetable growing) 2243 Use) 2244 Asparagus cultivation2245 Strawberry cultivation225 Value in use of the apartment2251 Approval of the value in use2252 Elimination of the value in use taxation226 Lease interest paid, interest on debts, permanent charges2 27 Other additions and reductions23 Willing business assets3 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry by comparing the operating income with the operating expenses (Section 4 (3) EStG) 31 Determination of profit311 Average livestock values312 Value in use of the apartment4 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry through accounting (Section 4 ( 1) Income Tax Act) 41 Scope of application42 Opening balance sheets43 Bookkeeping44 Determination of profits441 Average livestock values442 Value in use of the apartment5 Estimation of profit for farmers and foresters whose profit cannot be determined according to average rates51 General52 Estimation of profit according to standard rates521 Starting amount522 Rental income523 Surcharges for profits not deducted from the starting amount523"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits5231 Sales of breeding cattle and other valuable animals5232 Above normal animal husbandry5234 Vegetable growing (horticultural use), fruit growing, asparagus and strawberry cultivation524 Value in use of the apartment525 Wage expenses526 Lease expenses, debt interest527 Other surcharges and reductions5271 Increase in the starting amounts due to the use of external buildings (AfA Deductions for residential buildings5273 Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV6 Other61 Retirement benefits62 Control notifications63 Unit value notifications64 Use of the assessment files when carrying out the assessment65 Review of Annex LText of Annex 1: Text of Annex 2: 1 General"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Changes compared to the previous text - with the exception of purely editorial changes - are marked by vertical lines"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Like the instructions cited in the ruling, they will become part of the new EStG file"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "2 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry according to average rates (\u00a7 13a EStG) 21 Scope of application In addition to R 127 EStR 1993 and No. 2 of the introductory letter of the BMF of 27 3 1981 (BStBl 1981 I p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "282) the following is pointed out: 211 Areas to be considered The self-cultivated, own, leased and set-aside areas due to public funding programs must be taken into account (R 124a (3) EStR 1993)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "212 Re Section 13a (1) No. 2 EStG (initial value limit) The initial value determined in accordance with Section 13a (4) EStG is decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Cattle surcharges can therefore not be taken into account as long as they are not the subject of a value update according to \u00a7 41 i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 22 (1) No. 1 BewG have been made"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Something else only applies if the requirements of Section 13a (4) No. 1 Clause 4 EStG are met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "213 On \u00a7 13a (1) No. 3 EStG (animal population limit) When examining the VE limits of \u00a7 13a (1) No. 3 EStG, R 124 a EStR 1993 is to be applied accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The prerequisite for the discontinuation of the determination of the average rate of profit is that the number of VE sustainably exceeds the limits of \u00a7 13a (1) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Regarding the concept of sustainability, reference is made to R 135 (2) EStR 1993"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In the case of a gradual increase in the number of animals, it is therefore important whether the number of animals converted into VE over the three previous Wj"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "in each case over the limits of \u00a7 13a (1) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If this is the case, from the beginning of the fourth Wj"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "the requirements of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG are no longer met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If, on the other hand, the animal population is increased significantly above the maximum permissible limits in one go - e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "in connection with an expansion of the stable capacities - so that in the following Wj"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If the limits are expected to be exceeded, the requirements of Section 13a (1) No. 3 EStG do not apply from the time the maximum limits are exceeded for the first time"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "When determining animal populations, foreign animals must also be taken into account (BFH judgment of 23 September 1988 BStBl 1989 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "111)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The maximum number of animals permitted in accordance with \u00a7\u00a7 13a (1) No. 3 13 (1) No. 1 EStG and converted into VE can be found in the overview attached as Annex 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "22 Determination of profit The scheme for determining profit according to \u00a7 13a (3) to (8) EStG results from the form \"Annex ESt 2 L / 3 L - Profit determination according to \u00a7 13a EStG -\""}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In detail, I point out the following: 221 Basic amount When determining the basic amount according to \u00a7 13a (4) EStG, R 130 a (1) EStR 1993 must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "222 Value of the work performance The basic amount according to \u00a7 13a (4) EStG is assumed that the business is managed exclusively with paid workers (see \u00a7 36 (2) BewG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The value of the work performed by the company owner and his relatives who are not employed in the company on the basis of an employment relationship, to be determined in accordance with Section 13a (5) EStG, must therefore be added to the basic amount (Section 13a (3) No. 2 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "R 130 a (3) to (5) EStR 1993 and H 130 a EStH 1993 must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In detail, the following is also pointed out: When determining the value of the work performance for the physical work of the owner and the relatives who are not employed, only the work performance that is based on the initial value according to \u00a7 13a (4) EStG in the individual case is to be taken into account covered areas are omitted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The paid workers are to be counted towards the appropriate number of full-time workers (VAK) according to the length of their employment (\u00a7 13a (5) No. 5 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to temporary workers employed on a short-term basis as well as to workers who have been made available by contractors for ordering, maintenance or harvesting work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "For the crediting of the paid VAK"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "A breakdown of the wages is necessary, as far as it relates to the uses contained in the initial value (\u00a7 13a (4) EStG) and to the uses not contained therein (BFH judgment of 14 4 1988 BStBl 1988 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "774)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Make Stpfl in the tax return (form \"Annex L\") to the extent / proportion of their employment or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "the activities of other people (relatives, third parties) in the company or no or obviously incorrect information on the part of the work attributable to special uses, the (physical) work or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "the proportion of the work performed by the business owner, the relatives employed in the business and / or the remunerated workers, if applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "with the assistance of the responsible official agricultural expert (ALS)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The tables printed in Felsmann's comment in Section C 219 219 a about the average labor requirement for special branches of business can also serve as a guide to determine the proportion that is attributable to special uses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "For examples of calculating the value of the work, see Appendix 2223 Rent collected. Reference is made to Section 13a (6) sentence 2 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The rent received also includes income from ground rent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "This was confirmed by the FG M\u00fcnster with a legally binding judgment of 22 September 1992 6 K 4420/90 E (not published)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Income from hunting leases, on the other hand, is compensated by applying the basic amount insofar as it is attributable to areas included in the initial value"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "224 Profits according to Section 13a (8) EStG Reference is made to Section 13a (8) EStG and R 130 a (8) EStR 1993"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In addition, please note the following: Profits from operations that were not taken into account when determining the initial value are, in particular,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": ": Additional profits from the sale of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals (cf. No. 2241), profits from renting rooms to holiday guests, insofar as it is income from LuF (for delimitation reference to Section 103 (7) BewRL), interest income, insofar as the capital claim is attributable to the BV, profits from the rental of own horses, insofar as it is income from LuF (for delimitation see H 135 (Reitpferde) EStH 1993), profits from pensioner animal husbandry and wage rearing, profits from investments that belong to the luf BV , Profits from the rental of buildings and parts of buildings belonging to the agricultural BV, profits from the sale of milk quotas (cf. \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG subject 6 No. 13) and sugar beet quotas, compensation for economic difficulties (see \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG subject 6 No. 10)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Profits from the inter-company use of machines, which are achieved within the framework of the LuF, are in part to be recorded according to Section 13a (8) No. 3 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In this respect, reference is made to \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG Subject 7 No. 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The Stpfl can determine the profits (additional profits) according to \u00a7 13a (8) EStG either by comparing assets according to \u00a7 4 (1) EStG or by comparing operating income and operating expenses (\u00a7 4 (3) EStG) (H 130 a (determination of profits) EStH 1993 )"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If no records are available, the profits (additional profits) are to be estimated (R 130 a (8) sentence 6 EStR 1993)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "When estimating the profits (additional profits) from sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals, from growing vegetables and fruit, from growing asparagus and strawberries, the following guidelines can serve as a guide"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Their application must not lead to an obviously incorrect taxation (see BFH judgment of 16 12 1965 BStBl 1966 III p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "193)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "For the determination of the profit, see BFH judgment of 14 4 1988 BStBl 1988 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "774 In the case of exclusive profits i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 13a (8) EStG - although the profits are determined according to \u00a7 4 (3) EStG - the tax reduction of \u00a7 34e EStG does not come into consideration (BFH judgment of 28 11 1991 BStBl 1992 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "458)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "2241 Sales of breeding cattle and other particularly valuable animals From the sale of breeding cattle, according to \u00a7 13a (8) No. 3 EStG, only extraordinary income is to be recorded as a surcharge that is achieved due to the special quality of the animals at prices that are significantly above average"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Extraordinary income is to be regarded as exceeding the individual selling prices including sales tax: Breeding bulls 4900 DM Breeding cows and cattle 3300 DM Suckler calves 1050 DM Breeding boars 1200 DM Breeding sows 1050 DM Breeding horses and racing horses 9000 DM The above amounts include all expenses incurred in raising and selling the animals compensated (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Rearing costs, AK for purchased animals, wages, sales costs)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The additional profit has to be calculated individually for each animal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Offsetting with sales proceeds that are below these values \u200b\u200bis not permitted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If in individual cases for others than the above"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Breeding animals (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Fallow deer, sheep, goats) extraordinary proceeds are achieved, the surcharge should be estimated based on the aforementioned simplification rule"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "2242 Vegetable growing (agricultural and horticultural vegetable growing) For the delimitation of agricultural and horticultural vegetable growing, see Sections 108 (2) and 607 (1) No. 1 BewRL"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If vegetable growing is then to be assigned to agricultural use, a surcharge according to \u00a7 13a (8) EStG is not possible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Vegetable cultivation in the context of agricultural use only occurs if headed cabbage (white, red and savoy cabbage), picking peas and picking beans are grown exclusively according to agricultural cultivation methods as part of the agricultural crop rotation as the main crop"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "On the other hand, if the types of cabbage and / or peas or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Do not alternate beans with other agricultural crops such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Wheat, rye, barley, oats or beets, but one after the other or alternately with the same or different types of vegetables (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Endive, lettuce, lamb's lettuce, spinach, carrots, celery, beetroot, onions, radishes, leeks, tomatoes, kohlrabi, cucumbers, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": ") cultivated, the cultivation is no longer part of the agricultural crop rotation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Rather, it is a vegetable production to be assessed according to horticultural principles (vegetable production division of the horticultural use of vegetable, flower and ornamental plant production), which is to be recorded as a surcharge under the conditions of \u00a7 13a (8) No. 1 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If, in individual cases, an estimation method tailored to the company's circumstances is not preferable or if accounting results from comparable farms or empirical values \u200b\u200bare not available, the profit can be estimated as follows: Outdoor vegetable growing (income mainly from outdoor vegetable growing) Operating income between 38,000 and 47,000 DM / ha, Operating income between 16,000 and 20,000 DM / ha"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Vegetable growing with a roofed area (income mainly from vegetables grown under glass) Operating income between DM 110,000 and 165,000 / ha, operating income between DM 43,000 and 70,000 / ha"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The profit is influenced by the type of marketing (auction in the wholesale market, sale on the farm, sale on the weekly market) and the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The wages, interest and lease expenses associated with vegetable growing can also be deducted from the operating income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "An accurate estimate in individual cases is usually only possible in close cooperation with the ALS"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "2243 Fruit growing (horticultural use) The income from fruit growing amounts to - with the exception of strawberry growing (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "2245) - to 21,000 to 25,000 DM / ha"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "They depend on the type of fruit, the types of fruit, the age structure of the orchard, the quality of the soil and the climate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The operating income fluctuates between 10,000 and 12,000 DM / ha, from which proportionate wage, interest and lease expenses can also be deducted in accordance with No. 2242"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "2244 Asparagus cultivation The income generally fluctuates between 16,000 and 32,000 DM / ha"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The farm income can be estimated at 9,000 to 24,000 DM / ha"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Productive (prickable) asparagus plants bring an average of DM 18,000 operating income per hectare"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "It is influenced by the type of marketing (sale through auctions and wholesale markets, sale on the farm, sale at the weekly market, sale to resellers) and by the wage expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "No. 2243 last sentence applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "2245 Strawberry cultivation When determining the average rate profit, a distinction must be made as to whether the land used for strawberry cultivation is harvested by the farmer and his workers or so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Leave to be picked by self-pickers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In the case of harvest by the farm's workers, farm income between 35,000 and 40,000 DM / ha and profits of 13,000 to 19,000 DM / ha can be assumed, while the farm income for self-picking is 20,000 to 24,000 DM / ha and the profit between 9,000 and 11,000 DM / ha lies"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The last sentence of No. 2243 applies accordingly with regard to wage, interest and lease expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "225 Value in use of the apartment 2251 Approach of the value in use Reference is made to R 130 a (7) EStR 1993"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "As far as \u00a7 52 (15) sentence 4 EStG does not apply, the BFH judgment of July 28, 1983 (BStBl 1984 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "97) must be observed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the value in use is to be assigned to the owner even in the case of real security and to be taken into account in the corresponding amount as a permanent burden according to \u00a7 10 (1) No. 1 a EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "2252 Loss of value-in-use taxation In cases of deselection of value-in-use taxation, form No. 724/74 (questionnaire on withdrawing an apartment from the BV) must be sent to determine the facts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Falls from Kj"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "different Wj"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "the value-in-use taxation away, it is particularly important to note that the value in use still to be assessed up to 31 December is included in the profit of the FY"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "is included and according to \u00a7 4a (2) No. 1 EStG the different Kj"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "is to be assigned"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Insofar as the value-in-use taxation according to Section 52 (15) sentence 4 EStG is retrospectively deselected, the application also regularly affects the amount of the previous year's income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If the assessment of the previous year has already been finalized, it must be changed in accordance with Section 175 (1) No. 2 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "226 Lease interest paid, interest on debts, permanent encumbrances Reference is made to Section 13a (3) sentence 2 EStG and R 130 a (6) EStR 1993"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Interest subsidies from public funds reduce the deductible debt interest"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Regarding the income tax treatment of the interest reduction subsidies according to the agricultural loan program see \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG Fach 6 Nr 7 On the tax treatment of the overdraft interest the principles of the BFH decision of 4 July 1990 (BStBl 1990 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "817) and the BMF letter of 10 11 1993 (cf. \u00a7 4 (4) EStG subject 3 no 1)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "227 Other additions and reductions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The following can be considered: additions and deductions according to \u00a7 6c EStG, increased deductions for residential buildings according to \u00a7 7b EStG i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "V with \u00a7 52 EStDV, insofar as the value in use taxation according to \u00a7 52 (15) sentence 2 EStG is continued"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "This reduction does not apply from WY"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "1994/1995 The other increased deductions according to \u00a7\u00a7 7c, d, g, h, i and k EStG, 82a and g EStDV and according to the Protection Building Act cannot be taken into account when determining profits according to \u00a7 13a (3) to (7) EStG because with the average rates, the AfA and thus also the increased deductions that replace them are basically compensated (see BFH judgment of 7 6 1984 BStBl 1984 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "663)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "However, if a WG is used in a part of the business whose full income is to be recorded in accordance with Section 13a (8) EStG, increased deductions can also be taken into account when determining the profit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "23 Voluntary business assets When determining profits in accordance with Section 13a EStG, a voluntary BV cannot be formed (BFH judgment of 23 5 1991 BStBl 1991 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "798)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In the case of a change of use, however, the voluntary BV can be retained (R 14 (3) sentence 6 EStR 1993 \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG subject 4 no 8)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Because of the treatment of land encumbered with heritable building rights as a voluntary BV reference to BFH judgment of 10 December 1992 (BStBl 1993 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "342)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "3 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry by comparing the operating income with the operating expenses (\u00a7 4 (3) EStG) 31 Determination of profit Reference R 16 EStR 1993 and the following is pointed out: 311 Average cattle values \u200b\u200bThe average valuation permitted for bookkeeping farmers and foresters (R 125 EStR 1993) can, under certain conditions, also be used for the determination of profits according to Section 4 (3) EStG in accordance with R 125 a EStR 1993"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise reference is made to No. 441"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "312 Value in use of the apartment To determine the value in use of the apartment, reference is made to \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG Subject 8 No. 1"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the value in use is to be measured according to the circumstances of the individual case, even for farmers and foresters"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise, No. 225 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "4 Determination of the profit from agriculture and forestry through bookkeeping (\u00a7 4 (1) EStG) 41 Scope of application Reference is made to the BMF letter of 15 December 1981 (see \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG subject 4 no 1)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Cattle surcharges are also to be taken into account when determining the economic value limit according to \u00a7 141 (1) No. 3 AO if they are not or not yet the subject of a value update according to \u00a7\u00a7 41 i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "V with 22 (1) No. 1 BewG have been made"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "42 Opening balance sheets To check the opening balance sheets when transitioning to the BV comparison, reference is made to \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG Subject 4 No. 5"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "43 Accounting on R 12 (1) EStR 1993 and the BMF letter of 15 12 1981 (a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": ") being point out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "44 Profit determination 441 Average livestock values \u200b\u200bReference is made to R 125 EStR 1993"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The applicable average livestock values \u200b\u200bresult from \u00a7\u00a7 13 13a EStG subject 4 No. 6 The principles of livestock evaluation are based on the BFH judgment of 1 October 1992 (BStBl 1993 II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "284) currently revised"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The previous regulations can continue to be applied until the announcement"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "442 Value in use of apartment number 312 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "5 Estimate of the profit for farmers and foresters whose profit cannot be determined according to average rates51 General For farmers and foresters who are obliged to keep accounts but do not keep proper books, the profit is to be estimated in individual cases according to \u00a7 162 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to those farmers and foresters who are neither obliged to keep accounts nor meet the requirements of Section 13a (1) No. 2 and 3 EStG, if they do not have any books in accordance with"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 4 (1) EStG and also not the operating income and expenses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 4 (3) EStG (R 127 (1) EStR 1993)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "With the exception of the cases mentioned in R 12 (2) sentence 6 EStR 1993 - the estimate must be made according to the principles of Section 41 (1) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "When making the estimate, all circumstances that are important for the estimate must be taken into account (Section 162 (1) sentence 2 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The aim of the estimate must be to determine the profit actually achieved"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The uncertainties inherent in an estimate are, however, at the expense of the taxpayer, who himself gave cause for the estimate by neglecting his tax cooperation obligations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "It must also be ensured that farmers who are required to keep accounts and whose profits are estimated are reported to the tax auditors if an examination appears to be suitable to encourage the farmer to set up accounts or if the examination promises success for other reasons"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If a tax audit is planned in this sense, the assessment is to be carried out subject to a follow-up audit (Section 164 AO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "According to the principles of the FinMin NRW decree of 31 7 1989 S-0337 - 1 - VC 2, it is communicated by order of 14 8 1989 S-0335 - 17 - St 31 whether an estimate is to be carried out in other cases subject to review - 34 to decide"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The following explanatory text must be included in the notification or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "to be attached as an attachment: \"The profit from agriculture and forestry for the financial year 19"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "/ 19th"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "was estimated according to \u00a7 162 AO because you did not declare your profit or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "because you declared a profit that was not determined by bookkeeping, although you are obliged to keep the books"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If you actually achieved a higher profit than the estimated, the tax would have been set too low"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In this case, there may be tax evasion or a frivolous tax reduction"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "However, you can then by declaring the actual profit under the further requirements of \u00a7\u00a7 371 378 (3) AO criminal or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Obtain no fines"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Furthermore, I would like to point out that failure to comply with the accounting obligation can already result in a tax risk"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "\"52 Estimation of the profit according to standard rates Which estimation method is to be used in the individual case is left to the discretion of the FA"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If, in individual cases, an estimation method tailored to the particular operational conditions is not to be preferred or if no circumstances particularly influencing the operating result, such as"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Seed propagation or field vegetable cultivation, exist or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "have been determined in the course of a previous tax audit and accounting results of comparable companies or empirical records are not available, the profit is to be estimated according to the principles of \u00a7 4 (1) EStG as follows: starting amount (No. 521) + lease income (522) + surcharges for Profits not paid for with the starting amount or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits (no.523) + value in use of the apartment (no.524)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Wage expenses (No. 525)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Lease expenses, debt interest (No. 526) +"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Other surcharges and reductions (No. 527) = profit of the FY"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The guideline rates listed below are intended as a guide for an accurate estimate of the profit (R 127 (1) sentence 4 EStR 1993)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "At the same time, a reduction in the estimated profit due to objections to individual points in the valuation process is generally out of the question because special circumstances in an individual branch of the business do not allow any conclusions to be drawn about the profit of the entire business"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The application of the standard rates must not lead to an obviously incorrect taxation (see BFH judgment of 16 12 1965 BStBl 1966 III p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "193)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "521 Starting amount The starting amount per hectare of usable agricultural area (LN) is for Wj"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "1993/1994: In pasture farming (share of grassland 71%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "and more LN) 1400 DM For mixed farming (grassland share 31 to 70%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "der LN) with a root crop portion of a) 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "and more LN 1300 DMb) less than 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "the LN 1200 DM For arable farms (grassland share up to 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "der LN) with a root crop portion of a) 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "and more of the LN 1250 DMb) less than 15%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "the LN 1100 DM For sugar beet farms (root crop content more than 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "of the LN, including: sugar beet content more than 20%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "der LN) 1900 DM In the case of dairy cow husbandry, the above starting amounts (No. 1 to 4) are to be increased according to the average dairy cow herd of the farm as follows: a) less than 05 cows / ha LN by 0 DM b) 05 to less than 1 cows / ha LN by 400 DMc) 1 to less than 15 cows / ha LN around 550 DMd) 15 and more cows / ha LN around 750 DM In the case of bull fattening, the above starting amounts can be reduced by 200 DM / ha if bull fattening is the main branch of the farm"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In cases of repeated profit estimates, the starting amounts may be"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "a safety margin of up to 30%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "to increase"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The surcharge is not to be shown separately, but to be incorporated into the starting amounts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The starting amounts are to be increased if the estimate for the corresponding FY"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "at least five profit estimates have preceded it"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In the other cases (2 or more estimates at the time of the reminder, but not yet five previous estimates), safety surcharges are considered if, in individual cases, special circumstances suggest that the use of the starting amounts leads to a profit estimate that is too low"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The FA decides on the amount and staggering of the safety surcharges at its due discretion, taking into account all circumstances of the individual case"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "I would also ask farmers and foresters whose profits have been estimated for the second time in a row as part of the income tax assessment to fulfill their statutory accounting obligations or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "to remember the determination of the actual profit according to \u00a7 4 (1) EStG or \u00a7 4 (3) EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The legality of the safety surcharges has meanwhile been confirmed by the legally binding judgment of the FG M\u00fcnster of 4 6 1992 15 K 1697/90 E (not published)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Only the pure agricultural production areas belong to the agricultural use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Areas for buildings, courtyards, paths, ditches, field borders, water, land, quarries, sand pits, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Areas are therefore not considered"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Areas for house gardens are also not included"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Otherwise R 124 a (3) EStR 1993 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "According to this, areas set aside due to public funding programs are still considered to be used for agriculture"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "For the calculation of the relevant root crop, grassland or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Sugar beet proportion depends on the extent of these proportions in the respective FY"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The areas under cultivation of root crops do not include those areas on which root crops are only grown as catch crops or as catch crops"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Only the meadows and pastures listed in No. 5232 are to be regarded as grassland; the other crops mentioned there (fodder plants) belong to field forage cultivation, the areas of which belong to the field"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "522 Lease income Lease income, ground rent and hunting leases, reduced by proportionate operating expenses, e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Property taxes are to be added to the starting amount if they are part of the income from LuF"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "This is the case when the leased or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Luf BV of the lessor belong to the landlord's share of the land under construction"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "523 Surcharges for winnings or winnings not settled with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "All profits from sustainable or one-off operating income that are not included in the starting amount are to be added to the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Such surcharges come z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Consideration for additional profits from sales of breeding cattle and other valuable animals as well as whole animal herds Profits from abnormal animal husbandry Extra profits from special crops Profits from other special business branches (see \"Special operating income\" on page 4 of Annex L) Profits from the removal and sale of land (see \"Sale / withdrawal of Land \"on page 2 of Annex L) Profits from the rental of buildings and parts of buildings belonging to the BV Profits from the sale of milk quotas and sugar beet quotas Compensation for economic difficulties5231 Sales of breeding cattle and other valuable animals The amounts are to be recognized as additional profit from the sale of breeding cattle and other valuable animals , by which the retail price including sales tax exceeds the following values: Breeding bulls 3750 DM Breeding cows and cattle 2500 DM Mother calves 770 DM Breeding boars 900 DM Breeding sows 820 DM For breeding and riding horses the Meh profit with 60 BC"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "the amount by which the selling price exceeds the value of 6000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If sales proceeds of more than DM 13,000 are achieved, the full amount must be recognized as additional profit, which is DM 8,800 (DM 6,000 + 40%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "of 7000 DM)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Wages for paid workers as well as selling costs (auction fees, insurance contributions, transport costs, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": ") are taken into account in the amount of the above values, so they cannot be deducted separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The additional profit has to be calculated individually for each animal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "A netting with sales proceeds that are below the above values \u200b\u200bmay not be carried out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The same procedure is to be followed if above-average prices are achieved for breeding animals other than those specified or for other valuable animals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The underlying value in these cases results from the taxable HK of the animal species in question plus an assumed profit surcharge of 20% included in the initial value for the area with normal animal husbandry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "5232 Abnormal animal husbandry Profits from animal breeding and husbandry are settled with the starting amount, provided that the average normal animal population is not exceeded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "As animal husbandry paid for with the starting amount, other farms for the first 20 ha LN VE / ha16 VE / ha14 VE / haf for the next 10 ha LN VE / ha10 VE / ha08 VE / haf for the next 20 ha LN VE / ha09 VE / ha07 VE / ha for every additional ha LN08 VE / ha06 VE / haFodder-growing farms are holdings where the forage area is 60 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "and more of the usable agricultural area without courtyard and building space, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "matters"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In this context, the forage area includes: Meadows (including tree meadows, litter meadows), cattle pastures and arable pastures, as well as the areas under cultivation for clover in pure seed and mixed cultivation, clover grass, alfalfa, seradella, sasparsette, green maize, vetches, sweet lupins and all other forage plants"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Areas on which grain is grown for grain production are not included in the forage area even if the grain is fed to the livestock kept on the farm"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "When calculating the number of animals and converting them into VE, R 124 a (1) EStR 1993 must be used"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The average herds (lines 80 to 86 of Appendix L) and the animals produced (lines 87 to 93 of Appendix L) are to be summarized"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Care must be taken that no animals are recorded twice"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "For the excess inventory remaining after the normal inventory has been taken into account,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "1993/1994 set as profit: As a rule 265 DM / VE, if only broiler poultry are raised 190 DM / VE, if only laying hens are kept 490 DM / VE"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Wages are not taken into account here, so they can still be deducted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "5234 Vegetable growing (horticultural use), fruit growing, asparagus and strawberry growingNo"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "2242 to 2245 apply to the determination of profit accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "As a surcharge on the starting amount, however, only the additional profit, i.e."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "the profit reduced by the proportionate starting amount applied in the individual case"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "524 Value in use of apartment number 312 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "When estimating the profit, the gross value in use must always be applied, because the expenses associated with the apartment - with the exception of interest on debt (No. 526) and the increased deductions (No. 527) - are taken into account when determining the starting amounts (No. 521) and are thus compensated are"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "525 Wage expenses The starting amount (No. 521) is based on the assumption that the business is managed exclusively with unpaid workers"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Wage expenses are therefore to be deducted from the starting amount insofar as they relate to the profits settled with the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The treatment of wage expenses incurred with profits or income not paid for in the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Additional profits (see no.523) result from the respective surcharge regulations (see no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "5231 to 5234)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "For the distribution of wage expenses required in individual cases, No. 222 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "2 and 3 apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The wage expenses to be deducted also include the expenses for temporary workers employed on a short-term basis as well as for the workers who have been made available by contractors for ordering, maintenance or harvesting work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If wage expenses in connection with machine expenses are invoiced in one sum by contractors, there are generally no concerns that the proportionate wage expenses to be taken into account at 25%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "to estimate the gross expenditure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If the contractor also supplies seeds, fertilizers and pesticides and bills them together with the machine services, the invoice amount must be adjusted for the delivery fee included to calculate the wage expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "526 Lease expenses, debt interest Such expenses can be deducted if they are operating expenses and have not already been taken into account when determining the surcharges according to No. 523"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If, in addition to the rent for the lease of land and / or buildings (net lease), the lessee bears other expenses relating to the leased property (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Property tax, apportionment of the Chamber of Agriculture, building insurance), these expenses are not deductible as business expenses, as they have already been taken into account when determining the starting amounts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "527 Other surcharges and reductions 5271 Increase in the starting amounts due to the use of third-party buildings (AfA) When calculating the starting amount, the depreciation of the value of the company building is taken into account in accordance with Section 7 EStG, because it is assumed that the owner manages the business himself"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In cases of leasing or free leasing of agricultural operations as a whole (including farmyard), the depreciation for the business buildings is available to the lessor or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "to the farmer leaving the property free of charge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In the case of the authorized user, the starting amount must therefore be increased by 100 DM / ha of leased LN"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "5272 Reduction of the starting amounts due to increased deductions for residential buildings"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "increased deductions for residential buildings according to \u00a7 7b EStG and in other cases increased deductions according to \u00a7\u00a7 7c d, h, i, k EStG, 82a and g EStDV"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "These increased deductions are, however, by the depreciation already taken into account in the starting amount according to \u00a7 7 (4) EStG in the amount of 2 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "to shorten"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "5273 Special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDVEs it should be noted that special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV is only considered for investments that are made until the end of the fiscal year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "1991/1992 (Wj"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "1992) are acquired or manufactured (Section 76 (4) EStDV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If special depreciation according to \u00a7 76 EStDV has been carried out in the past, then after the expiry of the preferential period of three FY"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "to increase the starting amount by a surcharge, since according to \u00a7 7a (9) EStG the residual value is the assessment basis for the further depreciation and otherwise too high depreciation amounts would be taken into account by applying the starting amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The addition of a Wj"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "results from the total of the special depreciation granted divided by the remaining useful life of the respective flat share"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The initial amount must be increased for the remaining period of use"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In order to ensure that it is also taken into account in future assessments, the control sheet for profit surcharges (Section 76 EStDV), form no. 724/49 must be kept and attached to the income tax file"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "6 Other 61 Partial old-age benefits The values \u200b\u200bof the non-cash partial old-age benefits are to be estimated in accordance with Section 1 (1) SachBezV in the version applicable to the respective VZ (H 87 (partial old-age benefits) EStH 1993)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The values \u200b\u200bare published annually in BStBl I."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "611 For the VZ 1993 and 1994, the following values \u200b\u200bcan then be used as a basis without individual proof: 19931994 for meals with an old-age divider 3824 DM 3953 DM for a married couple 6882 DM7115 DM for heating and lighting with an old-age divider820 DM878 DM for a married couple 1530 DM1580 DMHowever, there are no concerns about the value of heating and lighting on the basis of the pro rata, based on the energy bills, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "the actual costs determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "612 If the value-in-use taxation ceases to apply on December 31, 1993, the pensionable person obliged to apply the value in use of the apartment for the pensioner up to this point in time in full in calendar year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "1993 deducted as special expenses, although according to \u00a7 4a (2) No. 1 EStG a partial amount of the value in use only in the calendar year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Has to pay tax in 1994 (see No. 225)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "62 Control notifications Except in the usual cases (control notifications for the purposes of the Bp, the recording of mandatory"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Processes at other Stpfl of ErbSt) are to be prepared in particular in the following cases:"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "to disclose circumstances arising from the files that may affect the level of the fixed unit values \u200b\u200b(e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Change in areas for special uses, changes in animal populations - see also order of 10 6 1976 S-2230 - 45 - St 11 - 31)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Information that may be of importance for an award according to \u00a7 41 BewG is summarized on page 4 of Annex L."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "I therefore ask in all cases in which the animal population declared in Appendix L obviously exceeds or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "in which, for other reasons, a surcharge according to \u00a7 41 BewG may be considered, the assessment body can be informed by sending a copy of page 4 of Annex L."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Are access or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Leases known, so the lessor or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Inform the leaseholder of the competent assessment office"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to the transfer of use free of charge"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In addition, I ask you to ensure that the Stpfl on page 2 of Annex L the address of the lessee / lessor, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "specify exactly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "In particular, cases without signal \"A\", in which wage expenses are claimed, and cases with significant wage expenses are to be reported to the responsible LSt office for examination by the LSt external audit (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "No. 525)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "63 Unit value notifications Unit value notifications about assets must always be evaluated promptly, in particular because of possible effects on the way in which the Stpfl's profit is determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "64 Consultation of the valuation files when carrying out the assessment In particular when determining profits in accordance with Section 13a of the Income Tax Act (EStG) and in valuation cases, I ask that you refer to the assessment files for the assessment and review of the values \u200b\u200bto be applied in the individual case when calculating profits"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "65 Review of the Annex L According to \u00a7 150 (1) and (2) AO, book-keeping farmers are also obliged to fill out tax returns including the annexes and thus in particular also the annex L completely and truthfully"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "This applies in particular to the area data in lines 32 to 49 of Annex L, which are not only indispensable for the taxation of appraisal farmers, but also"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "also serve to check the applicable profit determination method, to test profits and to be able to monitor value updates"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The section \"Sale / Withdrawal of Land\" contains the essential basic information required to examine profits from sales and withdrawals"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If the required information can be clearly found in the individual case from the balance sheet or similar documents, a reference in Annex L to the relevant documents is sufficient"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The information on page 4 of Annex L on the livestock population is used to distinguish between agricultural and commercial animal breeding or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Animal husbandry is important for sales taxation and for the applicable profit method"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "I would therefore ask you to ensure that farmers and foresters who keep books also fill out Appendix L in full"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "If this does not happen and the missing information is essential for taxation and this information does not result from the documents otherwise submitted, a photocopy of Annex L must be returned for the purpose of completion"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "I point out the possibility of using coercive measures"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "--- Text of Annex 1: Maximum permitted number of animals in livestock units (VE) according to \u00a7 13a (1) No. 3 and \u00a7 13 (1) No. 1 of the Income Tax Act (EStG) regularly used agricultural areas in ha Maximum permitted number of animals in VE \u00a7 13a (1) No. 3 of the Income Tax Act \u00a7 13 Paragraph 1 No. 1 EStG up to 75 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Pigs and poultry (3 VE / ha) over 75%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Pigs and poultry (4 VE / ha) (up to 15 ha 4 VE / ha, then 3 VE / ha) in ganzen1101010220202033030304303040530305063030607303070830328093036901030401001133441101236481201339521301442561401545601501648631601751661701854691801957721902060752002163782072266812142369842212472872282575902352678932422781962492884992562987102263309010527031931082733296111276339911427934102117282351051202853610812328837111126291381141292943911713229740120135300f\u00fcr any other ha3315Text Annex 2: Example of calculating the value of the output (\u00a7 13a para 5 ITA) Example 1An farmer has the following self-cultivated areas: agricultural use 15 ha, comparative value 25,500 DM special uses 1 ha, comparative value 5000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The initial value (Section 13a (4) EStG) is thus 25,500 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The comparative value for the special uses is not part of the initial value because it exceeds DM 2000 (Section 13a (4) No. 1 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Worked in the company: the owner (full-time employee) his wife (without an employment contract)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "She was also responsible for housekeeping for five fully boarded and accommodated people"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "the son (without an employment contract, 17 years old) a permanent part-time external worker a temporary worker for three months in the financial year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "20% of the work done by all employees in the company"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "on the special uses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Example 2 (changes to Example 1 in italics) A farmer has the following self-cultivated areas: agricultural use 15 ha, comparative value 25500 DM special uses 1 ha, comparative value 1900 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The initial value (Section 13a (4) EStG) is thus DM 27,400"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "The comparative value for the special uses is part of the initial value because it does not exceed DM 2000 (Section 13a (4) No. 1 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "Worked in the company: the owner (full-time employee) his wife (without an employment contract)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "She was also responsible for housekeeping for five fully boarded and accommodated people"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "the son (without an employment contract, 17 years old) a permanent part-time external worker a temporary worker for three months in the financial year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "20% of the work done by all employees in the company"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "on the special uses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124606.xml"}, "text": "--- Income tax / wage tax / church tax Accounting North Rhine-Westphalia Agriculture Agriculture ESt assessment"}]