[{"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion Erfurt S-2000 A - 08 - St 32S-2000 Information about current changes to the Income Tax Act General The Income Tax Act (EStG) was changed in 1994 by several laws, which are listed below: Article 4 of the Sixth Act to amend the Political Parties Act and other laws of 28 January 1994 ( BStBl 1994 part 1 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "207), see OFD order of 15 4 1994 S-2000 A - 08 - St 32 Article 26 of the Long-Term Care Insurance Act of 26 5 1994 (BStBl 1994 Part 1 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "531) Article 7 of the Housing Promotion Act of 6 6 1994 (Federal Law Gazette 1994 Part 1 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "1184) Article 3 of the Tenth Act to Change the Prisoner Assistance Act and other laws of June 8, 1994 (Federal Law Gazette 1994 Part 1 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "1214) Article 7 of the Second SED Injustice Correction Act of 23 June 1994 (BStBl 1994 Part 1 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "508) Article 1 of the Cross-Border Commuters Act of June 24, 1994 (BStBl 1994 Part 1 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "440) Article 14 of the Third Implementation Act / EEC to the VAG of 21 July 1994 (Federal Law Gazette 1994 Part 1 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "1630) Article 14 of the Second Financial Market Promotion Act of July 26, 1994 (Federal Law Gazette 1994 Part 1 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "1749) Article 27 of the Agricultural Social Reform Act 1995 of 29 7 1994 (Federal Law Gazette 1994 Part 1 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "1890) The following is a brief overview of the practice-relevant changes to the EStG by the Care Insurance Act (Pflege VG), the Housing Promotion Act, the SED Unlawful Adjustment Act and the Cross-Border Commuter Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "1 Long-term Care Insurance Act 11 \u00a7 3 No. 1 a and 14 EStG The tax exemption also applies to benefits from long-term care insurance and grants for long-term care insurance"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Long-term care insurance benefits are: Long-term care benefits in kind Care allowance for self-procured nursing aidsCombination of cash benefits and benefits in kind Home care when the carer is unable to attendNursing aids and technical aidsDay and night careShort-term careComplete care services for social security for the caregiver- Nursing courses for relatives and voluntary caregivers are only granted on application"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "In the case of care benefits in kind, the entitlement to home care assistance per calendar month includes an equivalent value of up to: - for care level I of 75,000 DM - for care level II of 180,000 DM - for care level III of 280000 DM DM possible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "The care allowance for self-procured nursing aids amounts to per full calendar month in the- care level I40000 DM- care level II80000 DM- care level III130000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Vacation) for a maximum of 4 weeks the costs for a substitute carer"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "The expenses of the long-term care insurance funds may not exceed DM 280,000 in individual cases"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "For aids intended for consumption, benefits of up to DM 6,000 per month can be granted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Subsidies for measures to improve the individual living environment of the person in need of care are limited to DM 500,000 per individual measure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "As part of the day and night care, the care fund pays the expenses of day-care care in the- care level Ibis to 75,000 DM- care level II up to 150,000 DM- care level III up to 210,000 DM per calendar month"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "This also includes the necessary transport costs for the person in need of care from the apartment to the day or night care facility and back"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "For short-term care, limited to 4 weeks per calendar year, the long-term care insurance fund can grant a maximum of DM 280,000 per calendar year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "It should be noted that entitlement to benefits only exists for an insurance period of at least 19961 year19972 years19983 years19994 years from 1 1 2000 at least 5 years in the last 10 years12 Section 10 (1) No. 2 a, 2 c EStG The catalog of eligible special expenses has been expanded to include \"contributions to long-term care insurance \"and\" Contributions to additional voluntary long-term care insurance \""}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "13 Section 10 (3) of the Income Tax Act (EStG) The maximum amounts for pension expenses are increased by an additional maximum amount of DM 36,000 for contributions to additional voluntary long-term care insurance (Section 10 (1) No. 2 c EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "However, this only applies to taxpayers who were born after December 31, 1957"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "14 Section 33b EStG141 Section 33b (2) No. 2b EStG The external recognizability feature has been omitted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "142 Section 33b (3) sentence 3 EStGFor the criterion \"helpless\", the definition in Section 33b (6) sentences 2 and 3 EStG applies"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "The PflegeVG comes into force on 1 1 1995 (Article 68, Paragraph 1)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "2 Housing Promotion Act 21 Section 3 No. 59 EStG Section 3 No. 59 EStG was added"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "This regulation applies from 1994. This ensures that the additional funding acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 88e WoBauF\u00f6rdG 1994 belongs to the tax-free income"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Section 88e WoBauF\u00f6rdG 1994 regulates the income-oriented promotion of social housing"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "This can take the form of basic or additional funding"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "The additional subsidy is granted for the purpose of an income-oriented housing cost burden for the respective tenant"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "The recipient of the additional funding is the landlord; the payment can be made through the tenant"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "If the payment is made via the tenant, the landlord will only be informed of the fact of the subsidy if the additional subsidy is determined"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "3 Second SED Injustice Act31 \u00a7 3 No. 23 EStG The new version of \u00a7 3 No. 23 EStG now makes it clear that the benefits under the Administrative Rehabilitation Act and the Occupational Rehabilitation Act are also tax-free"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "This regulation applies from the assessment period 19944 Grenzpendlergesetz41 \u00a7 1 Abs 3 EStG The group of persons affected was changed - instead of previously - \"German citizens\" - now \"natural persons\""}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "In addition, the income limit has been increased from 500,000 DM to 600,000 DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Sentence 3 of the previous section 1 (3) EStG has been dropped"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "The extended unlimited tax liability according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Section 1 (3) EStG for members of the public service resident abroad if their income subject to income tax abroad does not exceed the limit of DM 600,000"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "This applies e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "for the diplomatic service, teachers at foreign German schools, members of the Bundeswehr stationed in another NATO country, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": ", for all natural persons no longer only for German citizens"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "42 Paragraph 7 (5) of the Income Tax Act (EStG) For buildings belonging to private assets that are not used for residential purposes, the degressive building depreciation i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Section 7 (5) p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "1 No. 2 EStG extended by 1 year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "The reference date 1 1 1994 (decisive sales contract or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Building application) was postponed to 1 1 1995"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "The equity regulation in the BMF letter of 8 3 1994 BStBl 1994 part 1 p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "206 is therefore obsolete"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "I expressly point out that for the degressive building depreciation according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Section 7 (5) No. 1 EStG (building in business assets and not used for residential purposes) continues to be the reference date 1 1 1994"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "43 Section 33a (1) of the EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Section 33a (1) no.2 EStG is now DM 720,000 instead of DM 630,000"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "The credit limit of Section 33a (1) sentence 3 EStG has increased from the previous DM 450,000 to DM 600,000"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "44 Section 39d (2) EStG, Section 39d EStG regulates the implementation of wage tax deduction for employees with limited tax liability"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Section 39d, Paragraph 2 of the Income Tax Act regulates the scope of the exemption that the tax office on the employee's request on the certificate according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Section 39d (1) of the Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "4 4 1 Section 50 (4) of the Income Tax Act (EStG) group of persons: Limited taxpayers whose total income is at least 90% subject to German income tax or whose income not subject to German income tax does not exceed DM 1,200,000"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Exempt amount: the following can be entered as an exemption: a) the income-related expenses exceeding the employee lump sum b) maintenance services exceeding the special expenses lump sum, \u00a7 10 Paragraph 1 No. 1 EStG ongoing charges, \u00a7 10 Paragraph 1 No. 1 a EStG church tax, \u00a7 10 Paragraph 1 No. 4 EStG \u00a7 10 Paragraph 1 No. 5 EStG tax advice, \u00a7 10 Paragraph 1 No. 6 EStGB professional training, \u00a7 10 Paragraph 1 No. 7 EStG housekeeping, \u00a7 10 Paragraph 1 No. 8 EStG school fees, \u00a7 10 Paragraph 1 No. 9 EStG donations, \u00a7 10b EStG deduction amounts according to"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 10e EStG after completion (no upfront costs acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 10e Abs 6 EStG during the construction phase) c) Child allowance acc"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Section 32 (6) sentence 4 EStG Note: As of Vz 1994, a new sentence has been inserted after sentence 3) Extraordinary burdens, Sections 33, 33a, 33b, 33c EStGe) Tax class III if the requirements of Section 38b sentence 2 No. 3 b EStG exist (widow splitting) 442 Section 50 (1) EStG Group of persons: Persons not falling under Section 50 (4) EStG Exemption: a) the income-related expenses exceeding the employee lump sum b) expenses exceeding the special expenses lump sum for: - AO interest, Section 10 para 1 no 5 EStG donations, \u00a7 10b EStG No other expenses are to be entered for this group of people"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "45 Section 39d (3) of the EStG At the request of the employee, the employer must issue an official wage tax certificate upon termination of the employment relationship or at the end of a calendar year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "46 Section 50 (3) sentence 3 EStG With the newly added sentence 3 of Section 50 (3) EStG, when Section 50 (1) sentence 6 EStG and Section 50 (4) EStG are applied, the special tax-free amount i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "86400 DM not to be granted"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "In these cases, the minimum tax rate of 25% is not applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "47 Section 50 of the Income Tax Act (EStG) The new version of paragraphs 1 and 4 is in no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "44 discussed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Paragraph 5 in the new version is a consequential change"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "48 Section 52 (30a) of the Income Tax Act (EStG) The cross-border commuter law applies to income tax regulations from VZ 1994"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Section 52 (30a) of the Income Tax Act, sections 39d and 50 of the Income Tax Act (EStG) are to be applied in principle from 1 1 1995 onwards, however, upon request, Section 50 (4) of the Income Tax Act (EStG), the new version, must also be applied for assessment periods prior to 1994 if tax assessments are not yet final or if a Definitive decision on an application for equity measures submitted before October 13, 1993 is not yet available (see Section 52 (30a) sentence 2 EStG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "49 Employees from the Netherlands For employees from the Netherlands, the Implementing Act for Frontier Workers Netherlands, amended by Art"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "2 of the Cross-Border Commuters Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Attachments: - Summary of the changes to the EStG by the Pflege-VG and the Grenzpendlergesetz (sheets 1 and 2) This decree was based on decrees of the OFDs Rostock and Cottbus"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Annex (sheets 1 and 2) Changes to the income tax law by the care insurance law (Pflege-VG) and the cross-border commuter law Regulation changed by the application of the provisions of \u00a7 1 paragraph 3 EStG border commuter law Nationals \"; Raising the so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "Hardness limit to 6000 DM from the assessment period 1994 \u00a7 7 Abs 5 Nr 2 EStG border commuters law Extension of the degressive building depreciation on cases in which the building application was made or"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "the notarial purchase contract was concluded before 1 1 1995 from assessment period 1994 \u00a7 10 Paragraph 1 No. 2 a EStG \u00a7 10 Paragraph 1 No. 2 c EStGPflege-VGB WK are from assessment period 1995 \u00a7 10 Abs 3 EStGPflege-VG Additional maximum amount of 360 DM for Stpfl who have made contributions for an additional voluntary long-term care insurance and were born after December 31, 1957 from assessment period 1995 \u00a7 33a Abs 1 EStGGrenzpendlergesetz Increase of the maximum maintenance amount according to \u00a7 33a Abs 1 No. 2 EStG to DM 7,200 (previously DM 6,300) and the credit-free amount to DM 6,000 (previously DM 4,500) from the assessment period 1994, Section 50 (4) EStG Border Commuter Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": "is subject to German income tax or where the income is not subject to German income tax more than (i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0124055.xml"}, "text": ") Amount to DM 12,000; The assessment is then carried out using the provisions cited in Section 50, Paragraph 1, Clause 5 of the Income Tax Act from the 1994 assessment period, which are generally excluded from the assessment; On request also - for earlier, not yet final assessment periods income tax / wage tax / church tax Thuringia"}]