[{"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion Frankfurt am MainFG-2018 A - 9 - St II 40FG-2018G-2018FG-2018 - 21 - StO 321 / FG-2018 - 209 - StH 551FG-2018 - 21 - StO 321 / FG-2018 - 209 - StH 551FG- 2018 -FG-2018 - 21 - StO 321 / FG-2018 - 209 - StH 551FG-2018 -FG-2018 - 21 - StO 321 / FG-2018 - 209 - StH 551FG-2018 | GFG-2018-AO-K Before \u00a7\u00a7 135 - 149 FGO card 1 overhauled by OFD Frankfurt am Main FG-2018 A - 9 - St II 40 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "212002 AO card index before Sections 135-149 FGO card 1 Bibliography of the corresponding administrative instructions: NDAO-K Before Sections 135-149 FGO card 1 OFD Hannover FG-2018 - 21 - StO 321 / FG-2018 - 209 - StH 551 from 03/02 / 98AO: 135AO: 149BRAGO: AllgemeinStBGebV: AllgemeinAO: 139Costs of the tax court proceedings1 Cost decision 2 Costs i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 139 FGO3 Court costs 4 Costs of the parties 5 Fees and expenses (of the RA / StB) in the lawsuit 51 Fees52 Litigation fee (\u00a7 31 Abs 1 Nr 1 BRAGO) 53 Negotiation fee (\u00a7 31 Abs 1 Nr 2 BRAGO) 54 Evidence fee (\u00a7 31 Abs 1 No. 3 BRAGO) 55 Discussion fee (Section 31 Paragraph 1 No. 4 BRAGO) 56 Handling fee (Section 24 BRAGO) 57 Fees in the appeal procedure 58 Fees in the complaint procedure 59 Expenses 510 Fees for postal and telecommunications services511 Writing expenses 512 business trips 513 Sales tax (Section 25 Paragraph 2 BRAGO ) 6 Fees and expenses of the preliminary proceedings 61 Fees and expenses of a tax advisor (in the preliminary proceedings) 62 Fees and expenses of an RA (in the preliminary proceedings) 7 Interest on the reimbursement claim 8 Example of the reimbursable costs 9 Cost determination procedure91 Responsible for the determination92 Payment by the FA Kassel-Goethestrasse 93 Reminder 94 Objections to the amount in dispute 95 Application for temporary suspension of enforcement 96 En decision on the reminder 97 Costs of the reminder procedure Annex 1: Excerpt from the Federal Fee Regulations for Lawyers (BRAGO) Annex 2: Excerpt from the Tax Advisor Fee Ordinance (StBGebV) 1 Cost decision on the question of who has to bear the costs of a tax court procedure (\u00a7 135 - \u00a7 138 FGO), the court decides in the judgment or, if the proceedings have ended in a different way, by order (\u00a7 143 FGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The contestation of this decision on costs is inadmissible according to \u00a7 145 FGO unless an appeal is filed against the decision in the main matter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "2 costs i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 139 FGO costs are the court costs and the expenses of the parties involved for appropriate legal prosecution or legal defense including the costs of the preliminary proceedings"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "3 Court costs The court costs are made up of fees and expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "On the basis of the cost decision (see no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "1) levied in accordance with the provisions of the Court Fees Act (GKG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The fees are listed in the list of costs under nos"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "3110 - 3402 (Annex 1 to the GKG) and are based on the amount in dispute (Section 11 Paragraph 2 and Section 13 GKG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The expenses are levied in accordance with nos"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "9000 ff"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "of Annex 1 to the GKG (part 9 of the list of costs)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The court costs are determined (set) according to \u00a7 4 Abs 1 GKG by the cost officer of the finance court (I instance) or the BFH (II instance)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Since the tax authorities are exempt from court costs in the event of failure before the FG or the BFH (Section 2 GKG), the (further) details of the cost approach are not dealt with here"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "4 Costs of the parties involved The parties involved in the tax court proceedings (Section 57 FGO) are to be reimbursed according to Section 139 (1) FGO for the expenses that have accrued (necessary) for appropriate legal prosecution"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "However, the expenses of the tax authorities are not to be reimbursed (Section 139 Paragraph 2 FGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "To the expenses i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 139 Paragraph 1 FGO also include the fees and expenses of an authorized representative"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "These expenses are always reimbursable in accordance with Section 139 (3) FGO, provided they are provided for by law"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If the plaintiff is represented by a lawyer in the tax court proceedings, his remuneration is based on the Federal Fee Regulations for Lawyers (BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The BRAGO regulations are also to be applied if the plaintiff is represented by a tax advisor (StB), a tax agent or a tax consulting company (\u00a7 45 of the Tax Advisor Fee Ordinance - StBGebV)."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "According to this, the following fees and expenses can essentially come into consideration (\u00a7 114 BRAGO): FeesProcess fee (\u00a7 31 Paragraph 1 No. 1 BRAGO) Negotiation fee (\u00a7 31 Paragraph 1 No. 2 BRAGO) Evidence fee (\u00a7 31 Paragraph 1 No. 3 BRAGO) Discussion fee (\u00a7 31 Paragraph 1 No. 31 Paragraph 1 No. 4 BRAGO) Processing fee (\u00a7 24 BRAGO) Expenses fees for postal and telecommunications services (\u00a7 26 BRAGO) Writing expenses (\u00a7 27 BRAGO) Business travel (\u00a7 28 BRAGO) Sales tax (\u00a7 25 Paragraph 2 BRAGO) The fees of the StB / RA are measured according to the amount of the object value (\u00a7 7 and \u00a7 11 BRAGO), and this in turn is determined in court proceedings according to the value regulations applicable to court fees (\u00a7 8 paragraph 1 BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The basis for calculating the applicable fees in court proceedings is therefore always the value in dispute i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 13 GKG (see also No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The same applies to the reimbursable fees in the out-of-court preliminary proceedings (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "5 Fees and expenses (of the RA / StB) in legal proceedings 51 Fees The amount of the fees is based on \u00a7 11 BRAGO (see also the table of fees printed as an annex to BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "52 Litigation fee (Section 31 (1) No. 1 BRAGO) The litigation fee is the basic fee for judicial proceedings"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "With it the whole \"running the business\" (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Expenses for written submissions, documents and photocopies that are to be added to the statement of claim) including the information for a legal action (\u00a7 13 BRAGO) are compensated by the procurator"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The fee is generally 10/10 of a full fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "In the case of an activity in the same matter for several clients, the fee for each additional client increases by 3/10 (so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Multiple representation surcharge according to \u00a7 6 Abs 1 BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Multiple increases cannot exceed two full fees"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If the judgment under appeal is overturned by the BFH and the matter is referred back for another hearing and decision (Section 126 Paragraph 3 No. 2 FGO), the further proceedings are indeed a new legal act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "However, a (renewed) trial fee only arises if the matter is referred back to a court that has not yet dealt with the matter (Section 15 (1) BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "53 Negotiation fee (\u00a7 31 Paragraph 1 No. 2 BRAGO) The negotiation fee arises for the activity (submission of applications, discussion of the dispute, comments on the statements of the FA) of the authorized representative in the oral hearing"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If the proxy does not attend the oral hearing, the negotiation fee does not apply"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The same applies if the proceedings do not include an oral hearing (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "in the case of an application for suspension of execution according to Section 69 (3) FGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The negotiation fee does not apply, however, if an oral hearing is not carried out with the consent of the parties (\u00a7 35 BRAGO), by judgment without an oral hearing (procedure according to equitable discretion in accordance with"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 94a FGO) or by court order (\u00a7\u00a7 90a and 79a FGO) (\u00a7 117 BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The fee is generally 10/10 of a full fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Because the discussion fee is offset against the negotiation fee and vice versa, reference is made to Section 31 (2) BRAGO and No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "55 referenced"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "54 Evidence fee (Section 31 Paragraph 1 No. 3 BRAGO) The evidence fee arises for representation in evidence proceedings or when hearing or interrogating a party in accordance with Section 613 ZPO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "However, the authorized representative does not receive the evidence fee if the taking of evidence consists only in the presentation of the files in the hands of the evidencing party or the opponent (Section 34 (1) BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If files or documents are used, the authorized representative will only receive the evidence fee if the files or documents are used as evidence or used as evidence by resolution of evidence or otherwise (Section 34 (2) BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The fee is generally 10/10 of a full fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The amount in dispute for the evidence fee depends on what evidence is being collected"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "This value can be lower than the amount in dispute for the procedure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "55 Discussion fee (Section 31 (1) No. 4 BRAGO) The discussion fee arises for the discussion of the matter, also in the context of an attempt to find an amicable settlement"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The fee is generally 10/10 of a full fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Discussion fees and negotiation fees that relate to the same subject and arise in the same court are offset against each other"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The authorized representative can thus only claim a fee in cases in which he has attended an appointment to discuss the factual and legal situation and in which an oral hearing was later held"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "56 Handling fee (\u00a7 24 BRAGO) The handling fee arises if the legal dispute is completely or partially settled after the contested administrative act has been withdrawn or changed and the authorized representative has participated in the settlement"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The activity of the legal agent aimed at settling the matter without judgment must therefore go beyond his activities covered by the process and negotiation fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "This means that the activity of the tax advisor / RA is only rewarded with the handling fee (separately) if it is a separate, qualified contribution"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Such cooperation does not already exist if the statement of claim is so successful that the IA takes remedial action on its own or if reference is only made to the case law in parallel proceedings"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If a judge's notice is the cause of the settlement, the criteria of \u00a7 24 BRAGO are in any case not met"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The amount of the (success) fee is 10/10 of a full fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "57 Fees in the revision procedure In the revision procedure the fees according to \u00a7 31 BRAGO and the handling fee (\u00a7 24 BRAGO) increase by 3/10 to 13/10 of a full fee (\u00a7 11 Paragraph 1 Clause 4 BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "58 Fees in the complaint procedure In the complaint procedure the fees according to \u00a7 31 BRAGO are 5/10 (= half) of a full fee (\u00a7 61 para 1 no 1 BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If a complaint is made against the non-admission of the revision, the attorney receives 65/10 (= half the fee for the revision procedure) a full fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "59 Expenses According to Section 25 (1) BRAGO, the fees also include general business expenses (rent for office space, salaries, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": ") paid"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "For certain expenses (fees for postal and telecommunications services, office expenses and business trips), however, \u00a7 25 Paragraph 3 BRAGO i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "V proposes a reimbursement of the costs incurred with the following provisions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "510 Fees for postal and telecommunications services According to \u00a7 26 BRAGO, the procurator is entitled to compensation for the fees to be paid for the execution of the order for postal and telecommunications services"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Instead of the costs actually incurred, he can demand a flat rate that amounts to fifteen percent of the statutory fees, in the same matter and in court proceedings in the same court, however, a maximum of DM 40 (postage flat rate)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "511 Writing expenses Pursuant to Section 27 (1) BRAGO, the procurator is entitled to reimbursement of writing expenses for the additional copies and photocopies made in agreement with the client"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "A reimbursement (by the FA) is only possible if it is necessary i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 139 Paragraph 1 FGO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "For copies and photocopies from official and court files, writing expenses can only be claimed if their production was necessary for the proper processing of the legal case"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "This is usually not the case with photocopies of tax assessments and correspondence with the FA, which are in the tax files and which are submitted to the FG in accordance with Section 71 (2) FGO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Insofar as photocopies for the other parties involved are attached to the pleadings to the FG (Section 77 Paragraph 1 Sentence 3 FGO), the costs for this are covered by the process fee (Section 25 Paragraph 1 BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The amount of the writing expenses is based on the amounts determined for the judicial writing expenses in the GKG (\u00a7 27 Abs 2 BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Thereafter, the writing expenses for each page (photocopy) a) for the first 50 pages 1-- DM b) for each additional page 030 DM (cf. No. 9000 of the list of costs for the GKG, printed in the FGO manual edition)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "512 Business trips For business trips, the legal representative is to be reimbursed for travel expenses and accommodation expenses; he also receives a daily allowance and an absence allowance"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "A business trip exists if the travel destination is outside the municipality in which the office or the home of the authorized representative is located (Section 28 (1) BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "5121 Travel expenses (Section 28 (2) BRAGO) The travel expenses to be reimbursed when using your own vehicle are DM 052 for every kilometer or part thereof plus the expenses that are regularly incurred due to the use of the vehicle on the occasion of the business trip, in particular the parking fees, when using other means of transport, the actual costs Expenses insofar as they are reasonable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "5122 Daily and absence allowance (Section 28 (3) sentence 1 BRAGO) The daily and absence allowance for a business trip of no more than 4 hours is DM 30, from more than 4 to 8 hours DM 60, and from more than 8 hours 110-- DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "5123 Accommodation costs (Section 28 Paragraph 3 Clause 2 BRAGO) The accommodation costs are to be reimbursed in the amount of the actual expenses, provided they are reasonable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "5124 Travel expenses for the execution of several transactions (\u00a7 29 BRAGO) If a trip serves several transactions, the travel expenses and absence allowances are to be distributed according to the ratio of the costs that would have been incurred if the individual transactions had been carried out separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Example The lawyer attends four oral hearings on one day"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The total amount of travel expenses is DM 200"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The authorized representative can claim 50-- DM for travel expenses reimbursement from the client (200-- DM: 4 - number of transactions performed)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "However, whether the costs are to be reimbursed by the FA depends on the outcome of the respective proceedings"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "513 Sales tax (Section 25 (2) BRAGO) For taking into account the sales tax paid to the authorized representative in the cost fixing procedure (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "9) a declaration by the plaintiff (applicant) is sufficient, according to which he is not allowed to deduct the amounts as input tax (Section 104 (2) ZPO in the version of the KostR\u00c4ndG 1994 of 24 6 1994 BStBl 1994 I page 383)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "6 Fees and expenses of the preliminary proceedings If fees and expenses are to be reimbursed for the involvement of an authorized representative for the preliminary proceedings (Section 139 Paragraph 3 Clause 3 FGO), it should be noted that the StB and RA for these proceedings have different fee schedules (StB according to the StBGebV and RA according to BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The fees and expenses that come into consideration in accordance with these fee regulations can be found in the following overviews: FeesTax AdvisorRechtsanwaltStBGebVBRAGO Business Fee\u00a7 41\u00a7 118 Paragraph 1 No. 1 Meeting Fee\u00a7 42\u00a7 118 Paragraph 1 No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Telecommunications Services Article 16 Article 26 Writing expenses Article 17 Article 27 Business trips Article 18 Article 28 Sales tax Article 15 Article 25 Paragraph 2 The fees are (also) calculated in out-of-court redress proceedings according to the amount in dispute (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If a tax advisor or attorney has acted on his own behalf in out-of-court preliminary proceedings, he will not receive any reimbursement of costs for this in contrast to judicial proceedings (due to lack of necessity)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "This also applies if the authorized representative is employed by the parties involved (Section 139 (3) sentence 4 FGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "61 Fees and expenses of a StB (in the preliminary proceedings) The amount of the fees is based on Table E (legal remedies table) for the StBGebV (see Section 10 (1) StBGebV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "611 Business fee (\u00a7 41 StBGebV) The business fee is the basic fee for the out-of-court appeal procedure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "With it the operation of the business including the information, the submission and justification of the legal remedy by the tax advisor is compensated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The amount of the business fee is 5/10 to 10/10 of a full fee (framework fee)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The fee framework is reduced to 3/10 to 8/10 of a full fee if the tax advisor receives fees according to \u00a7 28 StBGebV for the examination of the tax assessment in the administrative procedure that precedes the appeal procedure (\u00a7 41 para 3 StBGebV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "As an appeal is usually preceded by a review of the administrative act, the fee framework must generally be reduced"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "This applies even if the consultant has not received any fee according to \u00a7 28, because it depends only on the emergence of the claim"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Unless anything special is presented (see \u00a7 11 StBGebV), an average fee (3/10 + 8/10: 2 = 55/10 of a full fee) can be assumed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Higher framework rates (than the medium fee) can e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "come into consideration when special knowledge in peripheral areas of tax law is required, with difficult legal questions and with considerable workload"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The lowest frame rate, however, may be appropriate if, for example,"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "the grounds for opposition are limited to one or a few sentences"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If the tax advisor objects to an assessment notice and prepares the tax return during the objection procedure (to justify the appeal), for which he is rewarded according to \u00a7 24 StBGebV, the business fee is reduced to 1/10 to 3/10 of a full fee (\u00a7 41 Paragraph 4 StBGebV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 41 (5) StBGebV contains a further reduction if the legal remedy procedure is a separately calculable application i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "of \u00a7 23 StBGebV precedes (if e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "an application for deferral or an application for AdV was previously submitted)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The sum of these fees and the fee according to \u00a7 41 Paragraph 1 StBGebV must not exceed 10/10 of a full fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "In the case of an activity in the same matter for several clients, on the other hand, the business fee increases for each additional client by 3/10 (at most 20/10), in cases of \u00a7 41 Paragraph 3 StBGebV by 2/10 (at most 16/10) and in cases of \u00a7 41 para 4 StBGebV by 1/10 (maximum 6/10) of a full fee (\u00a7 41 para 6 StBGebV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "612 Meeting fee (\u00a7 42 StBGebV) The meeting fee arises if the tax advisor participates in a meeting on factual or legal questions (after filing the appeal and before the appeal decision is made), which is ordered by the authority or in agreement with the client with the authority or a third party"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The tax advisor does not receive the fee for an oral or telephone inquiry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Even if there are several meetings in the out-of-court appeal procedure, the fee can only be set once"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The amount of the fee is 5/10 to 10/10 of a full fee (framework fee)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If the StB has already negotiated with the authority in the administrative proceedings preceding the out-of-court appeal proceedings and received a fee for this (a fee not to be reimbursed by the FA) according to \u00a7 31 StBGebV, the sum of this fee and the (meeting) fee according to \u00a7 42 para 1 StBGebV 10/10 of a full fee (offset against the fee according to \u00a7 42 StBGebV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "613 Evidence fee (\u00a7 43 StBGebV) The amount of the evidence fee is 5/10 to 10/10 of a full fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Since evidence is rarely taken in out-of-court appeal proceedings, there is usually no evidence fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The prerequisites for the incurrence of this fee result largely from \u00a7 43 StBGebV614 Expenses The reimbursement of expenses of the StB for the preliminary proceedings is based on Section 3 of the StBGebV (\u00a7\u00a7 15 to 19 StBGebV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Since the regulations essentially correspond to the relevant provisions of the BRAGO for judicial proceedings (exception: see \u00a7 18 StBGebV), reference is made to Tzn"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "59 to 513 referenced"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "62 Fees and expenses of an RA (in preliminary proceedings) The amount of the fees is based on \u00a7 11 BRAGO (see also the table of fees printed as an annex to BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "621 Business Fee (Section 118 Paragraph 1 No. 1 BRAGO) According to Section 119 Paragraph 1 BRAGO, the administrative procedure that precedes the legal dispute and serves to review the administrative act (preliminary procedure, objection procedure, remedy procedure) is one matter together with the preceding administrative procedure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "It follows that the RA is only entitled to a single business fee for his work in the assessment procedure and the (later) opposition procedure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Depending on the circumstances of the individual case (Section 12 (1) BRAGO), it amounts to 5/10 to 10/10 of a full fee (framework fee) for the operation of the business including the information, submission, preparation or signing of briefs or letters and drafting of documents; the RA does not receive this fee for advice or information (\u00a7 20 BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "With regard to the regulation in \u00a7 139 Paragraph 1 i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "V with paragraph 3 sentence 3 FGO, according to which only the costs of the preliminary proceedings, but not the costs of the previous administrative proceedings, are reimbursable, the business fee is only to be taken into account insofar as it has increased due to the action in the appeal proceedings"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The (uniform) fee must therefore be divided, taking into account the effort involved in the assessment procedure (tax return with or without balance sheet, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": ") was operated"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "In the case of an activity in the same matter for several clients, the business fee increases by 3/10 for each additional client (\u00a7 6 Paragraph 1 BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Multiple increases cannot exceed two full fees"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "In the case of fees that are only determined according to the minimum and maximum amount, the minimum and maximum amount increase by 3/10 with each additional client; multiple increases may not exceed twice the minimum and maximum amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "622 Meeting fee (\u00a7 118 Abs 1 Nr 2 BRAGO) The remarks on the meeting fee according to \u00a7 42 StBGebV (meeting fee of the tax advisor in out-of-court appeals proceedings; cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "612) apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The fee is (also) 5/10 to 10/10 of a full fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "For his work in the administrative procedure and in the subsequent out-of-court appeal proceedings, the RA may not charge more than 10/10 of a full fee as a meeting fee (Section 118 Paragraph 1 No. 2 in conjunction with"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "V with Section 119 (1) BRAGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If meetings have taken place both in the assessment procedure and in the objection procedure, the (uniform) fee must be divided"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Only that part of the fee that is attributable to the out-of-court appeal procedure is to be taken into account according to \u00a7 139 FGO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "623 Fee for taking evidence (Section 118 (1) No. 3 BRAGO) The statements on the fee for taking evidence according to Section 43 of the StBGebV (fee for taking evidence of the StB in out-of-court appeal proceedings, cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "613) apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 34 BRAGO applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "624 Expenses The same rules apply as for expenses in court proceedings (cf. Tzn"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "59 to 513)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "7 Interest on the reimbursement claim The fixed costs (see no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "9) are subject to interest at 4 percent (\u00a7 155 FGO i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "V with Section 104 (1) sentence 2 ZPO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The interest run begins with the receipt of the application to determine the costs at the FG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If the application was submitted before the cost decision (see no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "1), the interest rate begins at the point in time at which the cost decision becomes final, or if the costs are declared provisionally enforceable in the judgment, from the point in time when the judgment is pronounced"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "8 Example of the reimbursable costs After the tax advisor X had checked the tax assessment, he filed an objection (unsuccessful) against the 1993 income tax assessment on August 1, 1994 on behalf of the ABs"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "In the lawsuit filed on behalf of the couple on 10 2 1995, he applied for a reduction in income tax by DM 10,200"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "After an oral hearing the judgment was given on October 15, 1996"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "According to the cost decision, the costs of the proceedings are to be borne by the spouses (plaintiff) at 30 percent and the FA (defendant) at 70 percent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "It was declared necessary to consult the plaintiff's agent for the preliminary proceedings"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If the amount in dispute is between DM 10,200 and DM, the plaintiffs can apply for reimbursement of the following expenses: Costs of the legal action The decisive factor is the BRAGO fee table dated July 1, 1994 Process fee 10/10 + 3/10 (multiple agency surcharge) = DM 13/1086450 Negotiation fee (10/10 ) 66,500 DM postage fee, 4,000 DM travel costs to the court (120 km x 052 DM) 6,240 DM daily and absence allowances (more than 4 to 8 hours) 6,000 DM sales tax (15%)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "von 169190) 25379 DM total: 194569 DM Costs of the preliminary proceedings The table of fees (Table E) of the StBGebV business fee is decisive Since the StB receives a fee for checking the notification, the fee range is reduced to 3/10 to 8/10 with regard to the fact that it is is a so-called normal case, an average fee of 54/10 (31,350 DM) is to be granted, which is increased by 2/10 (313 50 DM x 2/10 = 6270 DM) (multiple agency surcharge, because married people) 37,620 DM postage fee, 4,000 DM sales tax (15 of the hundred of 41,620 DM) 6,243 DM total 47,863 DM total costs (19 469 DM + 47,863 DM) 242 432 DM costs to be reimbursed (70%"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "of 242,432 DM) 169,702 DM The amount to be reimbursed is subject to interest at 4 percent on request"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The clerk of the court of first instance, usually the FG, is responsible for determining the costs to be reimbursed to the parties involved (successful plaintiffs) on application (Section 149 (1) FGO, Section 155 FGO i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "V with \u00a7\u00a7 103 - 105 ZPO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If an application is made to determine costs, the FG forwards it to the FA for comment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The FA then has to check whether the costs claimed according to \u00a7 139 FGO are to be taken into account and whether the amount in dispute (see no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "94) is applicable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "After the opinion of the FA, the clerk of the FG sets on the basis of the cost decision (no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "1) the costs to be reimbursed with a (cost-fixing) resolution"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "92 Payment by the FA Kassel-Goethestrasse One copy of this decision is served to the debtor (defendant FA) and the creditor (successful plaintiff)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Furthermore, the Kassel-Goethestrasse tax office (FA KsG) receives, according to \u00a7 24 of the ordinance on the responsibilities of the Hessian tax offices (AO-Kartei, \u00a7 17 FVG, Karte 1) for the payment of the reimbursable expenses determined according to \u00a7 149 FGO for all Hessian F\u00c4 is responsible for a copy of the decision"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "After receipt of the copy, the FA KsG asks the FA concerned (cost debtor) whether the set reimbursement amount can be paid out"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "To avoid complaints and enforcement measures (\u00a7 151 FGO), the FA (cost debtor) has to process the request immediately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If the cost reimbursement claim can be offset against, this must be reported to the FA KsG using the form attached to the request"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The FA KsG will then explain the set-off and arrange for the rest (transfer of the amount to the FA)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If there are no concerns about the payment, the FA KsG (also with the above"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Form) and indicate to whom the reimbursement is to be made (reimbursement address: name, address, bank code and account number)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The following applies to a reimbursement to the legal representative: According to \u00a7 155 FGO i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "V with \u00a7 81 ZPO authorizes the power of attorney to receive the costs to be reimbursed by the opponent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "This means that there is no need to assign the claim for reimbursement by the creditor (plaintiff) to his legal representative"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "In the other cases, a payment with debt-discharging effect to a third party is only possible if the tax office (cost debtor) has an assignment of the reimbursement claim"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The strict formal requirements of \u00a7 46 AO do not have to be met for such an assignment because the claim for reimbursement of costs is not a claim within the meaning of \u00a7 46 Paragraph 1 AO"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The provisions of the BGB are authoritative"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "93 Reminder The IA can (also) appeal against the determination of the costs"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Notwithstanding the other deadlines for legal remedies, the deadline for collecting the reminder is only two weeks (Section 149 (2) FGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "With the reminder, objections can only be made to the calculation of the costs, but not to the cost decision on which the cost-fixing decision is based (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "1) are collected"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "94 Objections to the amount in dispute If the amount in dispute used to determine the costs was incorrectly determined and the costs to be reimbursed were consequently set too high, this must also be reprimanded with the reminder (for the amount in dispute, see Tipke / Kruse, Vor \u00a7 135 FGO , No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "103 ABC of the amounts in dispute)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Only in those cases in which the court has determined the amount in dispute (separately) by resolution, objections to its determination with the reminder against the decision to determine costs are inadmissible"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "There is no legal remedy against such a (value in dispute) resolution as there is no appeal to a supreme federal court (Section 25 (3) GKG i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "V with section 5 (2) sentence 3 GKG)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "For the possibility of changing the resolutions on the determination of the amount in dispute, see Section 25 (2) sentences 2 and 3 GKG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Due to the amendment to Section 25, Paragraph 1, Clause 1 of the GKG, which came into force on 1 1 1997, by the 6 VwGO\u00c4ndG (Federal Law Gazette 1996, page 1626), the court will only set the amount in dispute separately from the decision on cost fixing if requested by a party or the court deems it appropriate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Since the amount in dispute is not determined in accordance with Section 24 GKG in tax proceedings, the (separate) determination of the amount in dispute will again be the exception in the future, as was already the case in the period before July 1, 1994"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "In the period from July 1, 1994 to December 31, 1996, the FG had to set the value in dispute ex officio (separately) for each final decision on the main issue or when the proceedings were settled"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "95 Application for temporary suspension of enforcement According to Section 149 (3) FGO, the chairman of the court or the court can order that enforcement be temporarily suspended"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If a reminder has been filed and an application for temporary suspension of enforcement has been made, the FA KsG must be informed accordingly (see also No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "96 Decision on the reminder If the clerk does not remedy the reminder, the court decides by (incontestable) order (Section 149 (4) and Section 128 (4) FGO)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "97 Costs of the reminder procedure A decision on costs is (again) issued on the question of who has to bear the costs of the reminder procedure (No."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "1), which is the basis for a subsequent cost-fixing procedure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The amount of the fees (\u00a7 31 BRAGO) for the activity of the procurator is according to \u00a7 61 Abs 1 Nr 2 BRAGO 5/10 of a full fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The (reference files) rulings of 16 8 1988 - O-2206 A - 3 / FG 2018 A - 6 - St I 61c - and of 8 9 1994 - FG 2018 A - 7 - St II 40 - as well as the AO index, \u00a7 145 FGO, general, map 1 are to be excluded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Annex 1: Excerpt from the Federal Fee Regulations for Lawyers (BRAGO) First Section: General Provisions Section 1 Scope (1) The lawyer's remuneration (fees and expenses) for his professional activity is determined according to this law"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 3 Agreement on remuneration (1) The lawyer can only demand a higher remuneration than the statutory remuneration from an agreement if the client's declaration is made in writing and is not contained in the power of attorney or in a form that also includes other declarations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 4 Remuneration for activities of representatives of the lawyer The remuneration for an activity that the lawyer does not perform personally is calculated according to this Act if the lawyer is represented by a lawyer, the general representative or a trainee assigned for training"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 5 Several lawyers If the assignment is assigned to several lawyers for joint execution, each lawyer receives full remuneration for his work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 6 Several clients (1) If the lawyer works for several clients in the same matter, he will only receive the fees once"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If the subject of the legal activity is the same, the business fee (Section 118 Paragraph 1 No. 1) and the litigation fee (Section 31 Paragraph 1 No. 1) increase by three tenths for each additional client; the increase is calculated according to the amount in which the clients are jointly involved; multiple increases cannot exceed the amount of two full fees"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "In the case of fees that are only determined according to the minimum and maximum amount, the minimum and maximum amount increase by three tenths with each additional client; multiple increases may not exceed twice the minimum and maximum amount"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) The attorney also receives writing expenses for copies and photocopies that are made in the same matter for the necessary information of more than ten clients"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(3) Each of the clients owes the lawyer the fees and expenses that he would owe if the lawyer had only acted on his behalf; However, everyone owes writing expenses only for transcripts and photocopies made for their instruction"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The lawyer cannot, however, demand more than the fees calculated in accordance with paragraph 1 and the writing expenses calculated in accordance with paragraph 2; he can only claim the remaining expenses once"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 7 Object value (1) Unless otherwise stipulated in this Act, the fees are calculated according to the value of the object of the legal activity (object value)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) In the same matter, the values \u200b\u200bof several items are added together"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 8 Value regulations (1) Insofar as the court fees are based on the value, the value of the item in court proceedings is determined by the value regulations applicable to court fees"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "These value regulations also apply mutatis mutandis to activities outside of judicial proceedings, if the object of the activity could also be the subject of legal proceedings"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 9 Determination of the value of the court fees (1) If the value that is decisive for the court fees is determined by a court, the determination is also decisive for the lawyer's fees"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 11 Full fee, minimum fee (1) The full fee for an object value of up to DM 60,000 is DM 5,000"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The fee increases for an item value of up to ... DM for each commenced amount of another ... DM"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "DM3000006000040001000000100000550020000002000007000500000050000080001000000010000001400040000000300000016000100000000600000025000 over 1000000001000000030000 A table of fees for object values \u200b\u200bup to one million Deutsche Mark is attached to this law"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "In the appeal and revision procedure, the amounts of the fees resulting from sentences 1 and 2 increase by three tenths"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "In the appeal proceedings, however, the process fee increases by ten tenths, provided that the parties can only be represented by a lawyer approved by the Federal Court of Justice"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Sentences 4 and 5 apply accordingly in proceedings before the appellate court regarding the admission of the appeal"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 12 Framework fees (1) In the case of framework fees, the lawyer determines the fee in individual cases, taking into account all circumstances, in particular the importance of the matter, the scope and the difficulty of the legal work as well as the financial and income situation of the client, at its own discretion"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If the fee is to be reimbursed by a third party, the stipulation made by the lawyer is not binding if it is unreasonable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 13 Compensation area for fees (1) Unless otherwise stipulated in this Act, the fees cover the entire work of the lawyer from the assignment to the settlement of the matter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) The lawyer can only claim the fees once in the same matter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "In judicial proceedings, he can demand the fees in each instance"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(3) If different fee rates are to be applied for parts of the object, the lawyer shall receive separately calculated fees for the parts, but not more than the fee calculated from the total amount of the valuable parts according to the highest fee rate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(4) Unless otherwise specified in this Act, fees already incurred have no influence if the matter is dealt with prematurely or the order ends before the matter is dealt with"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(5) If the lawyer, after having acted in a matter, is instructed to continue to act in the same matter, he will not receive more fees than he would have received if he had been instructed to do so from the outset"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If the previous job has been completed for more than two calendar years, the further activity is considered a new matter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(6) If the lawyer is only commissioned with individual acts, he will not receive more fees than the lawyer commissioned with the entire matter would receive for the same activity"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "second part"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Common rules on fees and expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 24 Processing fee If a legal matter is dealt with in whole or in part after the administrative act contested with a legal remedy has been withdrawn or changed, the lawyer who participated in the processing receives a full fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 25 Reimbursement of expenses (1) The fees also cover general business costs"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) The lawyer is entitled to reimbursement of the sales tax due on his remuneration, unless this is not levied under Section 19 (1) of the Sales Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(3) The right to reimbursement of the fees to be paid for postal and telecommunications services, the writing expenses and travel expenses is determined by the following provisions"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 26 Fees for postal and telecommunications services The lawyer is entitled to compensation for the fees to be paid for the execution of the order for postal and telecommunications services"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "He can choose to demand a flat rate instead of the actual costs incurred, which amounts to fifteen percent of the statutory fees, in the same matter and in court proceedings in the same court, however, a maximum of 4,000 German marks, in criminal cases and fine proceedings a maximum of 3,000 German marks"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 11 (2) sentence 2 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 27 Copy expenses (1) The lawyer is entitled to reimbursement of the copy expenses for copies and photocopies from official and court files, insofar as their preparation was necessary for the proper processing of the legal case, for the information of more than three opponents or participants on the basis of a legal regulation or after Request by the court and otherwise only if they have been made with the consent of the client, also to inform third parties"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) The amount of writing expenses in the same matter and in judicial proceedings in the same court is based on the amounts specified for judicial writing expenses in the Court Fees Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 28 Business trips (1) For business trips, the lawyer shall be reimbursed travel expenses and accommodation expenses; he also receives a daily allowance and an absence allowance"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "A business trip exists if the travel destination is outside the municipality in which the law firm or the lawyer's apartment is located"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) The travel expenses to be reimbursed when using your own motor vehicle to cover the acquisition, maintenance and operating costs as well as the wear and tear of the motor vehicle are 052 Deutsche Mark for each kilometer driven plus the cash expenses regularly incurred through the use of the motor vehicle on the occasion of the business trip, in particular the parking fees and, if other means of transport are used, the actual expenses, insofar as they are reasonable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(3) The attorney receives 3,000 Deutsche Marks for business trips of no more than 4 hours, 6,000 Deutsche Marks for more than 4 to 8 hours and 11,000 Deutsche Marks for more than 8 hours as daily allowance and absence allowance; for trips abroad, a surcharge of 50 percent can be added to these amounts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The accommodation costs are to be reimbursed in the amount of the actual expenses, insofar as they are reasonable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 29 Travel for the execution of several transactions If a trip involves several transactions, the travel costs and absence allowances incurred are to be distributed according to the ratio of the costs that would have arisen if the individual transactions had been carried out separately"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Third section"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Fees in civil disputes and in similar proceedings \u00a7 31 litigation fee, negotiation fee, evidence fee, discussion fee (1) the lawyer appointed as a procurator receives a full fee for the operation of the business including the information (litigation fee), for the oral hearing (negotiation fee), for the Representation in the taking of evidence or at the hearing or interrogation of a party according to Section 613 of the Code of Civil Procedure (evidence fee), for the discussion of the matter, also in the context of an attempt to amicably settle (discussion fee)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) Discussion fees and negotiation fees that relate to the same subject and arise in the same instance are offset against each other"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 34 Submission of documents, reference of files or documents (1) The lawyer does not receive the evidence fee if the evidence only consists in the submission of the documents in the hands of the evidencing person or the opponent"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) If files or documents are used, the lawyer will only receive the evidence fee if the files or documents are used as evidence by a resolution or otherwise recognizable"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 35 Decision without an oral hearing If a decision is made without an oral hearing in a procedure for which an oral hearing is prescribed, with the consent of the parties or in accordance with Section 128 (3), Section 307 (2), Section 331 (3) or Section 495a (1) of the Code of Civil Procedure the lawyer charges the same fees as in a hearing procedure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 61 Complaint, Reminder (1) The lawyer receives five tenths of the fees specified in Section 31 in the complaint procedure; in the procedure for a reminder against the fixing of costs and against the cost estimate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) In the same matter, the lawyer receives the fees referred to in paragraph 1 no.2 only once"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(3) The provisions of Section 32 and Section 33 Paragraphs 1 and 2 do not apply"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 114 proceedings before courts of administrative and financial jurisdiction"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Fees in proceedings"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "before courts of"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Financial jurisdiction (1) In proceedings before the courts of administrative jurisdiction and financial jurisdiction, the provisions of the third section apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) In the first instance proceedings before the Federal Administrative Court and before a Higher Administrative Court (Verwaltungsgerichtshof), the lawyer receives fees in accordance with Section 11 Paragraph 1 Clause 4 in proceedings before the Finance Court fees in accordance with Section 11 Paragraph 1 Clause 1 and 2 (3) In the proceedings under Section 84 Paragraph 1 Clause 2 of the Administrative Court Regulations and in the procedure under Section 130a Clause 2 in conjunction with Section 125 Paragraph 2 Clause 3 of the Administrative Court Regulations, the lawyer receives half a negotiation fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(4) If the lawsuit is to be treated as an extrajudicial remedy in accordance with Section 45 of the Finance Court Regulations, the litigation fee will be offset against the new business fee or one that has already arisen in the same administrative procedure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(5) In proceedings to suspend or repeal the execution of the administrative act, to order or restore the suspensive effect and in proceedings to issue an interim order, Section 40 shall apply mutatis mutandis"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "If an interim order is executed, Section 59 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(6) In judicial proceedings on an act of enforcement (administrative compulsion), the lawyer receives three tenths of the fees specified in Section 31"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The provisions of Section 32 and Section 33 Paragraphs 1 and 2 do not apply"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 117 Special features for proceedings before courts of financial jurisdiction If a judgment is made without an oral hearing or a court decision effective as a judgment, the lawyer receives the same fees as in proceedings with an oral hearing"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Twelfth Section: Fees in Other Matters Section 118 Business Fee, Meeting Fee, Evidence Fee (1) In matters other than those regulated in the third to eleventh section, the lawyer receives five tenths to ten tenths of the full fee for the operation of the business, including the information, the filing, Preparation or signing of pleadings or letters and drafting of documents (business fee); the lawyer does not receive this fee for advice or information (Section 20); for participating in oral negotiations or discussions on factual or legal issues that are ordered by a court or an authority or in agreement with the client before a court or a Authority with which the opponent or a third party are conducted; for participating in the drafting of a partnership agreement and in disputes between societies and communities (meeting fee); the lawyer does not receive this fee for an oral or telephone inquiry; for participating in the taking of evidence that has been ordered by a court or an authority (evidence fee); Section 34 applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) Insofar as the business fee specified in paragraph 1 no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Half of the business fee referred to in sentence 1 is to be offset against the corresponding fees for proceedings on applications for a declaration of enforceability of a settlement according to Section 1044b of the Code of Civil Procedure"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 119 Preliminary proceedings, compulsory administrative proceedings, suspension of enforcement (1) The administrative proceedings that precede the legal dispute and serve to review the administrative act (preliminary proceedings, objection proceedings, complaint proceedings, remedial proceedings) are a matter together with the preceding administrative proceedings"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) In compulsory administrative proceedings (administrative enforcement proceedings), the lawyer receives three tenths of the full fee as a business fee, a meeting fee and a fee for taking evidence"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(3) The administrative procedure for the suspension of execution or for the elimination of the suspensive or inhibiting effect is a matter together with the procedures mentioned in paragraphs 1 and 2"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Table of fees for \u00a7 11 BRAGO object value up to\u2026 DM fee\u2026 DM object value up to\u2026 DM fee"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "DM600507000017051200908000018451800130900001985240017010000021253000210130000228540002651600002445500032019000026056000375220000276570004302500002925800048528000030859000540310000324510000595340000340512000665370000356514000735400000372516000805460000397518000875520000422520000945580000447525000102564000047253000011057000004975350001185760000522540000126582000054754500013458800005725500001425940000597560000156510000006225Anlage 2: Extract from the tax consultant fees (StBGebV) First Section: General Vorschriften\u00a7 1 Scope (1) The remuneration (fees and reimbursement of expenses) of the tax consultant for his own occupation pursued (\u00a7 33 of the Act) shall be based on this Regulation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) For the remuneration of the tax agents and the tax consultancy companies, the provisions on the remuneration of tax consultants apply accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 3 Minimum Fee, Expenses (1) The minimum fee is 15 Deutsche Mark"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Penny amounts are rounded up to 10 German pfennigs"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) The fees also cover general business costs"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(3) The right to payment of the sales tax attributable to the remuneration and to reimbursement of the postage and telecommunications fees, the writing expenses and the travel expenses is determined according to \u00a7\u00a7 15 to 20\u00a7 4 Agreement on the remuneration (1) The tax advisor can use an agreement Only demand higher remuneration than results from this ordinance and the statutory provisions on reimbursement of expenses if the client's declaration is made in writing and is not contained in the power of attorney or in a form that also includes other declarations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 5 Several tax consultants If the matter is transferred to several tax consultants for joint settlement, each tax consultant receives full remuneration for his work"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 6 Several clients (1) If the tax advisor works for several clients in the same matter, he will only receive the fees once"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) Each client owes the tax advisor the fees and expenses that he would owe if the tax advisor had only acted on his behalf"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The tax advisor cannot, however, demand more than the fee according to paragraph 1, which is to be calculated in the cases of \u00a7 41 paragraph 6 in accordance with this provision; he can only claim the expenses once"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Second Section: Calculation of Fees Section 10 Value Fees (1) The value fees are determined in accordance with Tables A to E attached to the regulation"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "They are calculated according to the value that the object of the professional activity has"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Unless otherwise specified in this Ordinance, the value of the interest is decisive"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) In the same matter, the values \u200b\u200bof several objects are added together; this does not apply to the activities specified in sections 24 to 27, 30 35 and 37"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 11 framework fees If a framework is provided for the fees, the tax advisor determines the fee in individual cases, taking into account all circumstances, in particular the importance of the matter, the scope and the difficulty of the professional activity at its reasonable discretion"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 12 Compensation area of \u200b\u200bthe fees (1) Unless otherwise specified in this ordinance, the fees cover the entire activity of the tax advisor from the order to the settlement of the matter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) The tax advisor can only claim the fees once in the same matter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(3) If different fee rates are to be applied for parts of the item, the tax advisor shall receive separately calculated fees for the parts, but not more than the fee calculated from the total amount of the valuable parts according to the highest fee rate"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(4) Unless otherwise stipulated in this ordinance, goods that have already arisen have no influence if the matter is dealt with prematurely or the order ends before the matter is dealt with"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(5) If the tax advisor, after having acted in a matter, is commissioned to continue to act in the same matter, he will not receive more fees than he would have received if he had been commissioned with this from the outset"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(6) If the tax advisor is only commissioned with individual acts, he will not receive more fees than the tax advisor commissioned with the entire matter would receive for the same activity"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 13 Time Fee The time fee is to be calculated in the cases in which this regulation provides, if there are no sufficient indications for an estimate of the value of the object; this does not apply to activities according to \u00a7 23 as well as to representation in out-of-court appeals procedure (\u00a7\u00a7 40 to 43), in administrative enforcement proceedings (\u00a7 44) and in judicial and other proceedings (\u00a7\u00a7 45 46)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "It amounts to 30 to 7750 German marks for every half hour or part thereof"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 14 Flat-rate remuneration (1) The tax advisor can agree on a flat-rate remuneration for one or more activities to be carried out on an ongoing basis for the same client"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The agreement must be made in writing and for a period of at least one year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "In the agreement, the activities to be taken over by the tax advisor and the periods for which they are performed must be detailed"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) The agreement of a flat-rate remuneration is excluded for the preparation of tax returns that do not recur at least annually; the preparation of written reports (\u00a7 22); the activities mentioned in \u00a7 23; participation in examinations (\u00a7 29); advice and representation in out-of-court redress proceedings (Sections 40 to 43), in administrative enforcement proceedings (Section 44) and in judicial and other proceedings (Section 45)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Third section: sales tax, reimbursement of expenses \u00a7 15 sales tax The sales tax is to be added to the remuneration, which is applicable to the activity according to \u00a7 12 of the sales tax law"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "This does not apply if the sales tax is not levied in accordance with Section 19 (1) of the Sales Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 16 Post and telecommunications fees The tax advisor is entitled to reimbursement of the post and telecommunications fees incurred during the execution of the order"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "He may, at his discretion, instead of the costs actually incurred, demand a flat rate amounting to 15 per cent of the fees resulting from this ordinance, but in the same matter a maximum of 40 German marks, in criminal matters and fine proceedings a maximum of 30 German marks"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 17 Writing expenses (1) Writing expenses are only available to the tax advisor for the additional copies and photocopies made in agreement with the client"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The tax advisor is entitled to write expenses for copies and photocopies from official and court files, provided that the copy or photocopy was necessary for the proper processing of the matter"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) The amount of writing expenses in the same matter and in judicial proceedings in the same court is based on the amounts specified for judicial writing expenses in the Court Fees Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 18 Business trips (1) For business trips, the tax consultant receives 045 Deutsche Mark for every commenced kilometer of the outward and return journey, if he uses his own vehicle, the actual expenses when using other means of transport"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) The tax consultant receives 25 Deutsche Marks for business trips of no more than 4 hours, 50 Deutsche Marks for more than 4 to 8 hours and 95 Deutsche Marks for more than 8 hours as daily and absence allowances; for trips abroad, a surcharge of 50 percent can be added to these amounts"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "He is also entitled to reimbursement of accommodation costs"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Fourth section: Fees for advice and assistance in fulfilling general tax obligations"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 23 Other individual activities The fee is for 1 the correction of a declaration (\u00a7 153 of the Tax Code) 2/10 to 10/102 an application for deferral2 / 10 to 8/103 an application for adjustment of the advance payments2 / 10 to 8/104 an application for different Tax assessment for reasons of equity2 / 10 to 8/105 an application for waiver of claims from the tax obligation2 / 10 to 8/106 an application for reimbursement (\u00a7 37 Abs 2 of the tax code) 2/10 to 8/107 an application for repeal or amendment of a Tax assessment or revocation of a tax registration2 / 10 to 10/108 an application for full or partial withdrawal or for full or partial revocation of an administrative act4 / 10 to 10/109 an application for restitution to the previous status outside of the appeal proceedings4 / 10 to 10/1010 other applications, insofar as they are not made in tax returns, a full fee according to Table A (Appendix 1)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Insofar as activities according to numbers 1 to 10 concern the same object, only one activity is decisive, namely the one with the highest upper fee limit"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "2/10 to 10 / 10\u00a7 24 tax returns (1) The tax advisor receives a full fee in accordance with Table A (Appendix 1) for preparing1 the income tax return without determining the individual income; The object value is the sum of the positive income, but at least 12,000 German marks; 1/10 to 6/10"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 28 Examination of tax assessments The tax advisor receives the time fee for the examination of a tax assessment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 31 Meetings For meetings with authorities or third parties in matters of tax law, the tax advisor receives 5 tenths to 10 tenths of a full fee according to Table A (Appendix 1)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 42 (2) applies accordingly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Sixth section: Fees for representation in out-of-court appeal proceedings and in administrative enforcement proceedings Section 40 Proceedings before administrative authorities For representation in appeal proceedings before administrative authorities, the tax advisor receives the business fee (Section 41), the discussion fee (Section 42), the fee for taking evidence (Section 43)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 41 Business Fee (1) The business fee is 5 tenths to 10 tenths of a full fee according to Table E (Appendix 5)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) The business fee covers the operation of the business including the information, the submission and the justification of the legal remedy"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(3) The business fee is reduced to 3 to 8 tenths of a full fee according to Table E (Appendix 5) if the tax advisor receives fees according to Section 28 in the administrative procedure that precedes the procedure according to Section 40"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(4) The business fee is reduced to 1 to 3 tenths of a full fee according to Table E (Appendix 5) if the tax advisor receives fees according to Section 24 in connection with the procedure according to Section 40"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(5) If a tax advisor receives fees in accordance with Section 23 in the administrative procedure that precedes the procedure in accordance with Section 40, the sum of these fees and the fee in accordance with paragraph 1 may not exceed 10 tenths of a full fee in accordance with Table E (Annex 5)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(6) If the tax advisor works for several clients in the same matter and the subject of the professional activity is the same, the business fee increases by 3 tenths for each additional client, in the cases of paragraph 3 by 2 tenths and in the cases of paragraph 3 4 by 1 tenth"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The increase is calculated according to the amount in which the clients are jointly involved"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Several increases may not exceed the amount of 20 tenths, in the cases of paragraph 3 the amount of 16 tenths and in the cases of paragraph 4 the amount of 6 tenths of a full fee according to Table E (Appendix 5)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 42 Meeting Fee (1) The meeting fee is 5 tenths to 10 tenths of a full fee according to Table E (Annex 5)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) The meeting fee arises if the tax advisor participates in a meeting on factual or legal questions that is arranged by the authority or is conducted with the authority or a third party in agreement with the client"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "The tax advisor does not receive this fee for an oral or telephone inquiry"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(3) If the tax advisor receives a fee in accordance with Section 31 in the administrative procedure that precedes the procedure in accordance with Section 40, the sum of this fee and the fee in accordance with paragraph 1 may not exceed 10 tenths of a full fee in accordance with Table E (Appendix 5)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 43 Fee for taking evidence (1) The fee for taking evidence is 5 tenths to 10 tenths of a full fee according to Table E (Appendix 5)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) The taking of evidence fee arises if the tax advisor is involved in taking evidence that has been ordered by an authority"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(3) The tax advisor does not receive the fee for taking evidence if the taking of evidence consists only in the presentation of the documents in the hands of the client or the authority"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(4) If files or documents are used, the tax advisor will only receive the fee for taking evidence if the files or documents are clearly used as evidence or used as evidence"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Section 44 administrative enforcement proceedings, suspension of enforcement (1) In administrative enforcement proceedings, the tax advisor receives 3 tenths of the full fee according to Table E (Appendix 5) as a business fee, a meeting fee and a fee for taking evidence"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "(2) The administrative procedure for the suspension of execution or for the elimination of the suspensive or inhibiting effect is a matter together with the procedures mentioned in Paragraph 1 and Section 40"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Seventh section: Judicial and other proceedings \u00a7 45 remuneration in judicial and other proceedings on the remuneration of the tax advisor in proceedings before the courts of financial jurisdiction and administrative jurisdiction, in criminal proceedings, professional judicial proceedings, fine proceedings and in mercy cases, the provisions of the federal fee regulations for lawyers shall apply mutatis mutandis"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138573.xml"}, "text": "Table E (Appeal table) for StBGebV Item value Deutsche Mark Full fee (10/10) Deutsche Mark Item value Deutsche Mark Full fee (10/10) Deutsche Mark up to 30040 to 950001824 up to 60055 up to 1000001889 up to 90070 up to 1150001964 up to 120085 up to 1300002039 up to 1500100 up to 1450002114 up to 180011522 up to 16000024227000 up to 3000 001 up to 3000 001 001 up to 1450002114 up to 180011522 up to 16000024227 2500002639bis 4500253bis 2650002714bis 5000279bis 2800002789bis 5500305bis 2950002864bis 6000331bis 3100002939bis 6500357bis 3250003014bis 7000383bis 3400003089bis 7500409bis 3550003164bis 8000435bis 3700003239bis 8500461bis 3850003314bis 9000487bis 4000003389bis 9500513bis 4300003509bis 10000539bis 4600003629bis 11000570bis 4900003749bis 12000601bis 5200003869bis 13000632bis 5500003989bis 14000663bis 5800004109bis 15000694bis 6100004229bis 16000725bis 6400004349bis 17000756bis 6700004469bis 18000787bis 7000004589bis 19000818bis 7300004709bis 20000849bis 7600004829bis 25000914bis 7900004949bis 30000979bis 8200005069bis 350001044bis 8500005189bis 400001109bis 8800005309bis 450001174bis 9100005429bis 500001239bis 9400005549bis 550001304bis 9700005669bis 600001369bis 10000005789bis 650001434von the surplus 150 to 700001499\u00fcber one million by 750001564Deutsche Markbis 800001629f\u00fcr each angefangenenbis 850001694Betrag of weiterenbis 90000175950000 German Mark Berufsrecht tax advisors professional law lawyers Procedural Law / Tax Code Hesse Lower lawyers tax consultants"}]