[{"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "Oberfinanzdirektion Saarbr\u00fccken S-2253 - 41 - St 222 S-2253 -S-2253EStG: 9aEStG: 9/1 / 1EStG: 9/1/3 / 1EStG: 9a / 1 / 2EStG: 21 / 1EStG: 21 / 2EStR: 42a / 4 / 2EStDV: 82b2-BVO: 422-BVO: 44OFD Saarbr\u00fccken S-2253 - 41 - St 222 v"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "20 5 1997 (Supplement) Application of the flat-rate income for income-related expenses in accordance with Section 9a Sentence 1 No. 2 EStG for income from renting and leasing From the 1996 assessment period onwards, a flat-rate amount of 42-- DM / sqm living space can be applied to buildings that are used for residential purposes can be deducted from rental and leasing income if the income-related expenses are determined as a lump sum"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "1 Scope of application The flat rate only applies to the rental of buildings for residential purposes within the framework of Section 21 of the Income Tax Act"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "In the case of buildings with several apartments, the right to choose can only be exercised uniformly, unless the apartments are owner-occupied"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "Since every condominium is an independent economic asset, the right to choose can be exercised for each individual apartment"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "The use is therefore excluded in particular in the case of a) rental for commercial or freelance purposes"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "in the case of only partial use for other residential purposes and partial use for commercial or professional purposes, a subdivision must be made (calculated according to usable area in analogous application of II BV, cf. R 13 Paragraph 6 EStR); In this context, a study is considered to be used for residential purposes (cf. R 42 a, Paragraph 4, Clause 2 EStR): b) Renting out movable accommodation such as caravans; c) Self-use, even if the large transitional regulation is applied, as it is part of the taxation of the value in use there is no income (excess of rental value over income-related costs) and the value in use according to Section 21 (2) EStG is included in the income, the rental value is isolated but does not belong to the rental and leasing income; If the building is only partially used by the owner, a corresponding division must be made (see above under a) and no"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "52 of the decree of 31 12 1994 - B / III - 216/94 - S-2225 a -)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "2 Calculation of the flat rate The flat rate is 42 DM per square meter of living space per year"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "The living space is to be determined according to Sections 42 and 44 of the Second Calculation Ordinance (II BV, Appendix 4 III EStH 1995)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "As a rule, the calculation of living space that has been checked and approved by the building supervisory authorities can be used as a basis"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "If such a current calculation - also in the assessment body - is not or no longer available, the following must be observed when determining the living space: According to \u00a7 42 II BV, the living space does not include e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "the footprint of accessory rooms (e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "Garages, basements, attics, sheds, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "), the floor space of rooms or parts of rooms with a clear height of less than 1 meter (\u00a7 44 II BV)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "Only half may be credited according to \u00a7 44 II BV z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "the floor area of \u200b\u200brooms and room parts with a clear height of less than 2 meters and at least 1 meter, winter gardens, swimming pools, balconies, loggias and roof gardens"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "If the prerequisites for the application of the flat rate are not present for the whole year, the flat rate is only to be granted pro rata temporis"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "3 Commercial expenses covered by the lump sum By applying the lump sum, all other expenses incurred on the rental property, in particular all repair and maintenance expenses (this also includes expenses according to \u00a7 82b EStDV, cf.Vfg"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "from 18 10 1996 - S-2253 - 39 - St 222), all operating costs (property tax, insurance premiums, water fees, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": ") and pensions and permanent burdens associated with rental and leasing income i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "Section 9 (1) no.1 EStG"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "This also applies to applications that can be assigned to ancillary rooms which, according to II BV, cannot be taken into account, or only half of them, when determining the living space"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "4 In addition to the lump sum, deductible expenses In addition to the lump sum, a) Debt interest i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "Section 9 (1) No. 1 EStG, including the ancillary costs of raising money, the damnum, the ground rent (cf."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "93 of the decree of 31 December 1994 a"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": ") as well as the suspension interest on the GrESt (BFH of 25 7 1995 BStBl II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "835); b) increased deductions and special depreciation, this includes not only the depreciation amounts for the building, but also the depreciation amounts for outdoor facilities and leased furnishings"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "5 Apportionable ancillary rental costs The main advertising costs covered by the flat-rate amount also include the ancillary rental costs paid by the landlord - regularly allocated to the tenants - e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "for heat and water supply, sewage, garbage disposal, property tax, certain home insurance, etc."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "If the taxpayer chooses the lump sum, he no longer has the right to choose between applying the \"warm or gross rent\" with the option of deducting the apportionable additional costs as business expenses, or the approach of the \"cold or net rent\" without deducting the apportionable additional costs"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "When applying the lump sum, the taxpayer must compulsorily include the actually received \"warm rent\" (incl"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "all contributions, if necessary"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "offset with reimbursements)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "For this reason, Annex V to the 1996 income tax return always provides for the entry of all levies received"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "If the landlord agrees with the tenant that he - as far as possible - settles the ancillary costs with the service provider himself, no corresponding income is to be recorded"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "The prerequisite for this, however, is that the tenant himself becomes the debtor of these passed on costs"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "This is z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "with a decentralized heating and hot water supply through a so-called"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "Gas boiler or gas floor heating may be possible for the energy costs, since the tenant regularly concludes the contract with the gas supply company himself and may have to bear the maintenance costs of the device himself, while the costs for cold water and sewage are regularly still owed by the landlord"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "If the tenant pays the ancillary costs directly to the respective creditor without being a debtor himself - e.g."}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "the property tax, whose debtor is the owner according to \u00a7 10 GrStG - or he pays amounts that the landlord is not allowed to pass on because they are not operating costs i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "\u00a7 27 i"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "V deals with Appendix 3 \"List of operating costs\" II BV - z"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "Condominiums add to the maintenance reserve - these amounts must always be recorded as income for the landlord"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "6 Miscellaneous a) The flat rate may result in a loss"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "b) In principle, the taxpayer has the choice between the flat rate calculation and the assertion of the actual income-related expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "The right to choose can be exercised until the income tax assessment is final, i.e. also within the framework of the fiscal court proceedings (see BFH of 27 9 1988 BStBl II p"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "225 for applying for separate assessment)"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "Co-owners who participate in the income must exercise the right to vote uniformly"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "A binding effect exists (only) in the event of a transition from a flat rate calculation to the actual deduction of income-related expenses"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "Werbungskosten &gt; Pauschale = Keine Bindungswirkung    Pauschale &gt; Werbungskosten = 4j\u00e4hrige Bindungsfrist"}, {"meta": {"name": "0138434.xml"}, "text": "--- Income tax / wage tax / church tax Saarland"}]